- So I was trying to figure out
- 所以我想弄清楚
how to do photorealistic AI photos and it was...
如何制作逼真的 AI 照片，它是......
Stable Diffusion by itself is not doing that well.
稳定扩散本身效果 并不好。
The faces look all mangled- - Yeah.
这些脸看上去都被毁坏了—— 是的。
- And it doesn't have enough resolution
- 而且分辨率不够
or something to do that well.
或者做一些能做好的事情。
But I started seeing these base models,
但我开始看到这些基本模型，
these fine tune models,
这些微调模型，
and people would train them on porn,
人们会训练他们色情内容，
and I would try them,
我会尝试一下，
and they would be very photorealistic.
而且它们会非常逼真。
They would have bodies that actually made sense,
他们会有真正有 意义的身体，
like body anatomy.
就像身体解剖学一样。
But if you look at the photo realistic models
但如果你看看照片 逼真的模型
that people use now, still,
人们现在仍然使用
there's still core of porn there,
那里仍然有色情的核心，
of naked people- - Yeah.
裸体的人- - 是 的。
- So I need to prompt out the naked,
- 所以我需要提示裸体，
and everyone needs to do this with AI startups with imaging.
每个人都需要通过成像人工智能 初创公司来做到这一点。
You need to prompt out the naked stuff.
你需要提示出赤裸裸的东西。
- You have to keep reminding the model
- 你要不断提醒模特
you need to put clothes on the thing.
你需要给这个东西穿上衣服。
- Yeah, don't put naked 'cause it's very risky.
- 是的，不要裸露， 因为这非常危险。
I have Google Vision- - Yeah.
我有 Google Vision- - 是 的。
- That checks every photo before it's shown to the user
- 在向用户显示之前 检查每张照片
to like check for NSWF. - Like nipples detector?
喜欢检查 NSWF。 - 像 乳头探测器一样？
Oh, NSFW detector. (chuckles)
哦，NSFW 探测器。 （笑声）
- Because the journalist gets very angry.
- 因为记者非常生气。
- The following is a conversation
- 以下是一段对话
with Pieter Levels, also known on X as levelsio.
使用 Pieter Levels，在 X 上也称为levelsio。
He is a self-taught developer and entrepreneur
他是一位自学成才 的开发者和企业家
who designed programs shipped and ran over 40 startups,
他设计的程序交付并运行 了 40 多家初创公司，
many of which are hugely successful.
其中许多都取得了巨大成功。
In most cases, he did it all by himself
大多数情况下都是他自己做的
while living the digital nomad life
过着数字游牧生活
in over 40 countries, in over 150 cities,
在40多个国家、150多个城市，
Programming on a laptop while chilling on a couch,
一边在沙发上休息一边 用笔记本电脑编程，
using Vanilla HTML, jQuery, PHP, and SQLite
使用 Vanilla HTML、jQuery、PHP 和 SQLite
He builds and ships quickly and improves on the fly,
他快速构建和交付 并即时改进，
all in the open, documenting his work,
一切都是公开的，记录他的工作，
both his successes and failures
他的成功和失败
with a raw honesty of a true indie hacker.
具有真正独立黑客的原始诚实。
Pieter is an inspiration
彼得是一个灵感
to a huge number of developers and entrepreneurs
为广大的开发 者和创业者
who love creating cool things in the world
热爱在世界上创造酷炫事物的人
that are hopefully useful for people.
希望对人们有用。
This was an honor and a pleasure for me.
这对我来说是一种荣幸和快乐。
This is the "Lex Fridman Podcast."
这是“莱克斯·弗里德曼播客”。
To support it, please check out our sponsors
为了支持它，请查看 我们的赞助商
in the description.
在描述中。
And now, dear friends, here's Pieter Levels.
现在，亲爱的朋友们，这是彼 得·莱弗斯（Pieter Levels）。
You've launched a lot of companies
你创办了很多公司
and built a lot of products.
并打造了很多产品。
As you say, most failed, but some succeeded.
正如你所说，大多数人都失败了 ，但也有一些人成功了。
What's your philosophy
你的哲学是什么
behind building the startups that you did?
你创办初创公司的幕后黑手？
- I think my philosophy
- 我认为我的哲学
is very different than most people in startups.
与初创公司中的大多数 人有很大不同。
'Cause most people in startups,
因为大多数初创公司的人
they build a company and they raise money, right?
他们建立了一家公司 并筹集资金，对吧？
And they hire people,
他们雇佣人，
and then they build a product,
然后他们开发了一个产品，
and they find something that makes money.
他们找到了赚钱的东西。
I don't really raise money.
我真的不筹集资金。
I don't use VC funding.
我不使用风险投资资金。
I do everything myself.
我自己做一切。
I'm a designer.
我是一名设计师。
I'm the developer.
我是开发商。
I make everything, I make the logo.
我制作一切，我制作标志。
So for me, I'm much more scrappy.
所以对我来说，我更加斗志旺盛。
And because I don't have funding,
而且因为我没有资金，
I need to go fast.
我需要走快点。
I need to make things fast to see if an idea works, right?
我需要加快速度来看看一个 想法是否有效，对吗？
I have an idea in my mind and I build it,
我脑子里有一个想法，我就会去实现它，
build like a micro, mini startup.
像微型初创公司一样构建。
And I launch it very quickly,
我很快就启动了它，
like within two weeks or something of building it,
比如在两周之内或者建造 它之后的某个时间，
and I check if there's demand.
我会检查是否有需求。
And if people actually sign up,
如果人们真的注册了
and not just sign up,
而不仅仅是注册，
but if people actually pay money, right?
但如果人们真的付钱，对吗？
They need to take out their credit cards, pay me money,
他们需要拿出信用卡 ，付给我钱，
and then I can see if the idea is validated.
然后我可以看看这个 想法是否有效。
And most ideas don't work, like as you say,
大多数想法都行不 通，就像你说的，
most fail.
大多数失败。
- So there's this rapid iterative phase
- 所以有这个快速迭代阶段
where you just build a prototype that works, launch it.
您只需构建一个可以 工作的原型，然后启动它。
- Yeah. - See if people like it,
- 是的。 - 看看人们是否喜欢它，
improving it really, really quickly
改进得非常非常快
to see if people like it
看看人们是否喜欢它
a little bit more enough to pay, and all that.
多一点就够付钱 了，等等。
That whole rapid process is how you think of.
整个快速过程就是 你所想到的。
- Yeah, I think it's very rapid,
- 是的，我认为速度非常快，
and it's like if I compare to,
就像如果我比较的话
for example, Google, like big tech companies.
例如，谷歌等 大型科技公司。
Especially Google right now is kind of struggling.
尤其是谷歌现在 正陷入困境。
They made transformers.
他们制造了变压器。
They invented all the AI stuff years ago,
他们几年前发明了所有人工智能的东西
and they never really shipped.
他们从未真正发货。
They could have shipped ChatGPT, for example,
例如，他们可以 发布 ChatGPT，
I think I heard in 2019,
我想我在2019年听说过
and they never shipped it
他们从未发货
because they were so stuck in bureaucracy.
因为他们深陷官僚主义之中。
But they had everything, they had the data,
但他们拥有一切，他们 拥有数据，
they had the tech, they had the engineers,
他们有技术，有工程师，
and they didn't do it.
但他们没有这么做。
And it's because these big organizations,
这是因为这些大组织，
it can make you very slow.
它会让你变得非常慢。
So being alone by myself on my laptop,
所以独自一人在我的笔记本电脑上，
in my underwear in a hotel room or something,
在酒店房间或其他 地方穿着我的内衣，
I can ship very fast,
我可以很快发货，
and I don't need to ask legal for like,
我不需要向法律部门寻求类似的帮助
"Oh, can you vouch for this?"
“噢，你能证明这一点吗？”
I can just go and ship.
我可以直接去发货。
- Do you always code in your underwear?
- 你总是在内裤里写代码吗？
Your profile picture, you're slouching-
你的个人资料照片，你没精打采——
- Yeah. - On a couch
- 是的。 - 在沙发上
in your underwear, chilling on a laptop.
穿着内衣，坐在笔记本电脑上。
- No, but I do wear shorts a lot,
- 不，但我确实经常穿短裤，
and I usually just wear shorts and no T-shirt
我通常只穿短裤 ，不穿T恤
'cause I'm always too hot.
因为我总是太热了。
I'm always overheating.
我总是过热。
- Thank you for showing up
- 谢谢你的出现
not just in your underwear but-
不只是在你的内衣里，而且——
- Yeah. - Wearing shorts.
- 是的 。 - 穿短裤。
- And I'm still wearing this for you,
- 我仍然为你穿着这件衣服
but- - Thank you.
但是 - - 谢谢你。
Thank you for dressing up.
谢谢你精心打扮。
(Pieter chuckles)
（彼得笑了）
- Since I go to the gym, I'm always too hot.
- 自从我去健身房 后，我总是太热。
- What's your favorite exercise in the gym?
- 你在健身房最喜欢 的运动是什么？
- Man, overhead press.
- 伙计，过头推举。
- Overhead press like shoulder press?
- 过头推举和肩部推举一样吗？
- Yeah. - Okay.
- 是的。 - 好的。
- But it feels good 'cause you win,
- 但感觉很好，因为你赢了
'cause when you- (Lex laughs)
因为当你——（Lex 笑）
I do 60 kilos. - Yeah.
我做60公斤。 - 是 的。
- So it's like 120 pounds or something.
- 所以大概是 120 磅什么的。
It's my only thing I can do well in the gym.
这是我在健身房里 唯一能做好的事情。
And you stand like this and you're like, "I did it,"
你像这样站着，然后 说：“我做到了”
like a winner pose. - It's victory thing.
就像胜利者的姿势。 - 这是胜利的事情。
Yeah. - The victory pose.
是的 。 - 胜利姿势。
I do bench press, squat, deadlifts.
我做卧推、深蹲、硬拉。
(Lex and Pieter laughs)
（莱克斯和彼得笑了）
- Hence the mug. - Yes.
- 因此是杯子。 - 是 的。
- Talking to my therapist. - Yeah.
- 和我的治疗师交谈。 - 是
- It's a deadlift.
- 这是硬拉。 - 是 的。
Because it acts like therapy for me.
因为它对我来说就像一种治疗。
- [Lex] Yeah, yeah, it is.
- [Lex] 是的，是的，是的。
- Which is controversial to say.
- 这是有争议的说法。
If I say this on Twitter, people get angry,
如果我在 Twitter 上这么说 ，人们会生气，
- Physical hardship is a kind of therapy.
- 身体上的困难是一种治疗。
- Yeah. - I just rewatched
- 是的。 - 我刚刚又看了一遍
"Happy People" A Year In The Taiga,"
《幸福的人们》针叶林一年》
that Werner Herzog film,
沃纳·赫尔佐格的那部电影，
where they document people that are doing trapping.
他们记录了人们进行 诱捕的情况。
They're essentially just working for survival
他们本质上只是为了 生存而工作
in the wilderness year round. - Yeah.
常年在旷野。 - 是的 。
- And there's a deep happiness to their way of life-
-他们的生活方式充满了 深深的幸福感-
- Yeah. - Because they're so busy
- 是的 。 - 因为他们太忙了
in it, in nature. - Yeah, 100%.
在其中，在自然中。 - 是的，100%。
- There's something about that physical-
- 身体上有一些东西 -
- Physical, yeah. - Toil.
- 身体上的，是的。 - 辛苦。
- Yeah, my dad taught me that.
- 是的，我爸爸教我的。
My dad always did construction in the house.
我爸爸总是在 房子里做建筑工作。
He's always renovating the house.
他总是在装修房子。
He breaks through one room
他冲破了一个房间
and then he goes to the next room,
然后他去了隔壁房间
and he is just going in a circle around the house
他只是绕着房子 转了一圈
for the last 40 years.
过去 40 年。
So he is always doing construction in the house
所以他总是在 房子里做建筑
and it's his hobby.
这是他的爱好。
He taught me, when I'm depressed or something,
他教我，当我沮丧或 其他什么的时候，
he says, "Get a big," what do you call it?
他说，“买个大的”，你怎么称呼它？
Like a big mountain of sand or something from construction,
就像一座大沙山或者 建筑中的东西，
and just get a shovel
拿一把铲子
and bring it to the other side
并把它带到另一边
and just do physical labor, do hard work,
只做体力劳动，做艰苦的工作，
and do something.
并做某事。
Set a goal, do something.
设定一个目标，做某事。
And I kind of did that with startups too.
我对初创公司也这样做过。
- Yeah, construction is not about the destination, man.
- 是的，建设与目的地无关 ，伙计。
It's about the journey. - Yeah. (chuckles)
这是关于旅程的。 - 是 的。 （笑声）
- Sometimes I wonder people
- 有时我想知道人们
who are always remodeling their house.
他们总是在改造他们的房子。
Is it really about the remodeling or-
真的是关于改造吗，还是——
- [Pieter] No, no, its not.
- [彼得] 不，不，不是。
- Is it about the project? - It's the journey.
- 与项目有关吗？ - 这 就是旅程。
- The puzzle of it.
- 它的谜题。
- No, he doesn't care about the results.
- 不，他不在乎结果。
Well, he shows me, he's like, "It's amazing."
好吧，他向我展示了，他 说，“这太棒了。”
I'm like, "Yeah, it's amazing."
我想，“是的，太棒了。”
But then he wants to go to the next room.
但随后他想去隔壁房间。
But I think it's very metaphorical for work,
但我认为这对于工作 来说是非常隐喻的，
'cause I also, I never stop work.
因为我也从来没有停止过工作。
I go to the next website,
我转到下一个网站，
or I make a new one, right?
或者我再做一个新的，对吗？
or I make a new startup.
或者我开始新的创业。
So I'm always like...
所以我总是像...
To give you something to wake up in the morning,
为了给你早上起床 提供一些东西，
and like, have coffee and then
就像，喝咖啡，然后
kiss your girlfriend,
亲吻你的女朋友，
and then you have like a goal.
然后你就有了一个目标。
Today I'm gonna fix this .
今天我要解决这个问题。
Today I'm gonna fix this bug or something.
今天我要修复这个错误或者其他什么。
I'm gonna do something.
我要做点什么。
You have something to wake up to.
你有一些事情要醒来。
And I think
我认为
maybe especially as a man, also women,
也许尤其是作为一个男人，也可能是女人，
but you need a hard work.
但你需要努力工作。
You need like an endeavor, I think.
我认为你需要努力。
- How much of the building that you do is about money?
- 你建造的建筑有多少 是与金钱有关的？
How much is it about just a deep internal happiness?
有多少只是内心 深处的幸福？
- It's really about fun,
- 这真的很有趣，
'cause I was doing it when I didn't make money, right?
因为我在没赚钱的时候 就这么做了，对吗？
That's the point.
这就是重点。
So I was always coding, I was making music.
所以我一直在编码， 我在制作音乐。
I made electronic music,
我制作电子音乐，
drum bass music 20 years ago,
20年前的鼓贝斯音乐，
and I was always making stuff.
我总是在做东西。
So I think creative expression is like
所以我认为创意表达就像
a meaningful work that's so important.
一项非常重要且有意义的工作。
It's so fun.
太有趣了。
It's so fun to have like a daily challenge
每天都有挑战真是太有趣了
where you try figure stuff out.
你尝试解决问题的地方。
- But the interesting thing is
- 但有趣的是
you built a lot of successful products
你打造了很多成功的产品
and you never really wanted to take it to that level
而你从来没有真正想过把 它提升到那个水平
where you scale real big- - Yeah.
在那里你的规模真的很大-- 是的。
- And sell it to a company or something like this.
- 并将其出售给公司 或类似的机构。
- Yeah, the problem is I don't dictate that, right?
- 是的，问题是我不 这么规定，对吧？
If more people start using it,
如果更多的人开始使用它
if millions of people suddenly start using it
如果数百万人突然 开始使用它
and it becomes big,
并且它变大了，
I'm not gonna say,
我不会说，
"Oh, stop signing up to my website and pay me money."
“哦，停止注册我的 网站并付钱给我。”
But I never raised funding for it.
但我从未为此筹集过资金。
And I think, 'cause I don't like
我想，因为我不喜欢
the stressful life that comes with it.
随之而来的压力生活。
I have a lot of founder friends
我有很多创始人朋友
and they tell me secretly.
他们偷偷地告诉我。
With hundreds of millions of dollars in funding and stuff,
拥有数亿美元的 资金和物资，
they tell me, "Next time, if I'm gonna do it,
他们告诉我，“下 次，如果我要这么做，
I'm gonna do it like you
我会像你一样做
because it's more fun, it's more indie,
因为它更有趣，更独立，
it's more chill, it's more creative."
它更冷静，更有创意。”
They don't like to be manager, right?
他们不喜欢当经理，对吗？
You become like a CEO, you become a manager.
你变得像一个首席执行官 ，你成为一个经理。
And I think a lot of people that start startups,
我认为很多 人开始创业，
when they become a CEO,
当他们成为首席执行官时，
they don't like that job actually,
他们实际上并不喜欢那份工作
but they can't really exit it.
但他们无法真正退出。
But they like to do the groundwork, the coding.
但他们喜欢做基础 工作，即编码。
So I think that keeps you happy,
所以我认为这会让你快乐
doing something creative.
做一些有创意的事情。
- Yeah, it's interesting how people are pulled towards that,
- 是的，有趣的是人们是 如何被吸引到这一点的，
to scale to go really big,
规模变得非常大，
and you don't have that honest reflection with yourself,
你对自己没有诚实 的反思，
like what actually makes you happy?
比如什么真正让你快乐？
'Cause for a lot of great engineers,
因为对于很多伟大的工程师来说
what makes them happy is the building,
让他们高兴的是建筑，
the quote, unquote, "individual contributor."
引用，取消引用 ，“个人贡献者”。
- Yeah. - like where you're actually
- 是的。 - 就像你实际所在的地方一样
still coding or you're- - Yeah.
仍在编码，否则你- - 是 的。
- Actually still building.
- 实际上仍在建设中。
And they let go of that,
然后他们就放弃了，
and then they become unhappy,
然后他们变得不快乐，
but some of that is the sacrifice needed
但其中有些是需要牺牲的
to have a impact at scale
产生大规模影响
if you truly believe in a thing you're doing.
如果你真正相信你正在 做的一件事。
- But look at Elon.
- 但是看看埃隆。
He's doing things million times bigger than me,
他做的事情比我 大一百万倍
and would I wanna do that?
我愿意这样做吗？
I don't know, you can't really choose these things, right?
我不知道，你真的不能选择 这些东西，对吗？
But I really respect that.
但我真的很尊重这一点。
I think Elon's very different from VC founders.
我认为埃隆与风险 投资创始人非常不同。
VC, it's like software.
VC，就像软件一样。
There's a lot of bullshit in this world, I think.
我觉得这个世界上 有很多废话。
There's a lot of there's dodgy,
有很多都是狡猾的，
finance stuff happening there, I think.
我认为那里发生了金融方面的事情。
And I never have concrete evidence about it,
我从来没有这方面 的具体证据
but your gut tells you something's going on
但你的直觉告诉你 发生了什么事
with companies getting sold to-
公司被出售给-
- Yeah. - Friends and VCs,
- 是的。 - 朋友和风险投资家，
and then they do reciprocity
然后他们互惠互利
and this shady financial dealings.
以及这种不正当的金融交易。
With Elon, that's not.
对于埃隆来说，情况并非如此。
He's just raising money from investors
他只是从投资者那里筹集资金
and he's actually building stuff.
他实际上正在建造东西。
He needs the money to build stuff,
他需要钱来建造东西
hard hardware stuff,
硬硬件的东西，
and that I really respect.
我真的很尊重。
- You said that there's been
- 你说有过
a few low points in your life.
你生活中的一些低谷。
You've been depressed,
你曾经郁郁寡欢，
and building is one of the ways you get out of that.
建造是摆脱困境 的方法之一。
Can you talk to that?
你能谈谈吗？
Can you take me to that place,
你能带我去那个地方吗
that time when you were at a low point?
那个时候你处于低谷？
- So I was in Holland and I graduated university,
- 所以我在荷兰， 大学毕业了，
and I didn't wanna get a normal job,
我不想找一份正常的工作
and I was making some money with YouTube
我通过 YouTube 赚了一些钱
'cause I had this music career
因为我有这个音乐事业
and I uploaded my music to YouTube.
我将我的音乐上传到 YouTube。
And YouTube started paying me with AdSense,
YouTube 开始通过 AdSense 向我付款，
like $2,000 a month, $3,000 a month.
比如每月2000美元，每月3000美元。
And all my friends got normal jobs,
我所有的朋友都找到了正常的工作
and we stopped hanging out,
我们不再出去玩了，
'cause people would, like in university, hang out,
因为人们会像在大学 里一样闲逛，
chill at each other's houses,
互相到对方家里避暑，
you go party.
你去参加派对吧。
But when people get jobs,
但当人们找到工作后
they only party in the weekend,
他们只在周末聚会，
and they don't hang anymore in the week
这周他们就不再挂了
'cause you need to be at the office.
因为你需要在办公室。
And I was like, "This is not for me.
我当时想，“这不适合我。
I wanna do something else."
我想做点别的事。”
And I was starting getting this like,
我开始意识到，
I think it's like Saturn return when you turn 27.
我觉得这就像你27岁的 时候土星回归一样。
It's like some concept where Saturn returns
这就像土星回归 的一些概念
to the same place in the orbit that it was
到原来轨道上的同一个地方
when you're born. - I'm learning so many things.
当你出生的时候 。 - 我学到了很多东西。
- [Pieter] It's some astrology thing.
- [Pieter] 这是一些占星学的事情。
- So many truly special artists died when they were 27.
- 很多真正特别的艺术家 在 27 岁时就去世了。
- [Pieter] Exactly, there's something with 27, man.
- [Pieter] 确实，27 是有 道理的，伙计。
And it was for me.
这是为了我。
I started going crazy- - Yeah.
我开始发疯--是 的。
- Because I didn't really see my future in Holland,
- 因为我并没有真正看到 自己在荷兰的未来，
buying a house, going living in the suburbs, and stuff.
买房子，去郊区 生活等等。
So I flew out, I went to Asia,
所以我飞出去，去了亚洲，
started digital nomading,
开始数字游牧，
and did that for a year.
并这样做了一年。
And then that made me feel even worse,
这让我感觉更糟了，
'cause I was like alone in hotel rooms,
因为我就像一个人呆在酒店房间里，
looking at the ceiling.
看着天花板。
What am I doing with my life?
我的一生在做什么？
I was working on startups and stuff on YouTube,
我当时在初创公司工作， 在 YouTube 上工作，
but what is the future here?
但这里的未来是什么？
While my friends in Holland were doing really well
虽然我在荷兰的朋友们 过得很好
and living normal life.
并过着正常的生活。
So I was getting very depressed
所以我变得非常沮丧
and I'm like an outcast.
而我就像一个被遗弃的人。
My money was shrinking.
我的钱在缩水。
I wasn't making money anymore a lot.
我不再赚很多钱了。
I was making $500 a month or something,
我每个月赚500美元左右，
And I was looking at the ceiling thinking like,
我看着天花板 想，
"Now I'm 27, I'm a loser."
“现在我27岁了，我是个失败者。”
And that's the moment when I started building startups.
那就是我开始创办初创 公司的那一刻。
And it was because my dad said,
也是因为我爸爸说，
"If you're depressed,
“如果你感到沮丧，
you need to get sand, get shovel,
你需要拿沙子，拿铲子，
start shoveling, doing something.
开始铲土，做某事。
You can't just sit still."
你不能坐以待毙。”
Which is kinda like a interesting way
这有点像一种有趣的方式
to deal with depression.
来应对抑郁症。
It's not like, "Oh, let's talk about it."
这不像是“哦，我们来谈谈吧”。
It's more like, "Let's go do something."
更像是“我们去做点什么吧”。
And I started doing a project called
我开始做一个名为
12 Startups in 12 Months
12 个月内 12 家初创公司
where every month I would make something, like a project,
每个月我都会做一些事情 ，比如一个项目，
and I would launch it with Stripe,
我会和 Stripe 一起推出它，
so people could pay for it.
这样人们就可以为此付费。
- So the basic format is try to build a thing,
- 所以基本格式是尝试 构建一个东西，
put it online, and put Stripe
把它放到网上，然后把Stripe
to where you can pay money for it.
到你可以付钱的地方。
- Yeah, add a Stripe...
- 是的，添加一个条纹......
I'm not sponsored by Stripe,
我没有得到 Stripe 的赞助，
but add a Stripe checkout button.
但添加一个 Stripe 结帐按钮。
- Is that still the easiest way
- 这仍然是最简单的方法吗
to just like pay for stuff, Stripe?
只是喜欢花钱买东西，Stripe？
- 100%, I think so, yeah.
- 100%，我想是的，是的。
- It's a cool company.
- 这是一家很酷的公司。
They just made it so easy.
他们只是让它变得如此简单。
You can just click and- - Yeah.
您只需点击- - 是 的。
And they're really nice.
他们真的很好。
The CEO, Patrick, is really nice.
首席执行官帕特里克（Patrick）非常友善。
- Behind the scenes, it must be difficult
- 幕后一定很困难
to actually make that happen
真正实现这一目标
because that used to be a huge problem.
因为这曾经是一个大问题。
- [Pieter] Merchant.
- [彼得]商人。
- Just adding a thing, a button
- 只需添加一个东西，一个按钮
where you can pay for a thing.
在那里你可以支付某物的费用。
- Dude. - It's-
- 伙计。 - 它是-
- Dude, I know this because when I was-
- 伙计，我知道这一点是因为当我-
- Trustworthy. - Nine years old,
- 值得信赖 。 - 九岁，
I was making websites also,
我也在做网站，
and I tried to open a merchant account.
我尝试开设一个商家帐户。
There was like before Stripe you would have like,
就像在 Stripe 之前 你会喜欢的那样，
I think it was called Worldpay.
我想它叫 Worldpay。
So I had to fill out all these forms,
所以我必须填写所有这些表格
and then I had to fax them to America
然后我不得不将它们传真到美国
from Holland with my dad's fax.
从荷兰寄来的，带着我爸爸的传真。
It was on my dad's name,
这是我父亲的名字
and he had to sign for this,
他必须为此签字，
and he started reading these terms and conditions,
他开始阅读这些 条款和条件，
which is he's liable for 100 million in damages.
也就是说他要承担 1亿的损失。
And he's like, "I don't wanna sign this."
他说：“我不想签这个。”
I'm like, "Dad, come on, I need a merchant account.
我说，“爸爸，来吧， 我需要一个商业账户。
I need to make money on the internet."
我需要在互联网上赚钱。”
- Yeah. (chuckles) - And he signed it,
- 是的。 （笑） - 他签了字，
and we faxed it to America,
我们把它传真到美国，
and I had a merchant accounts,
我有一个商人账户，
but then nobody paid for anything,
但后来没有人支付任何费用，
so that was the problem,
这就是问题所在
But it's much easier now.
但现在容易多了。
You can sign up, you add some codes, and yeah.
您可以注册，添加一些代码 ，然后就可以了。
- So 12 startups in 12 months.
- 12 个月内有 12 家初创公司。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Startup number one, what was that?
- 排名第一的初创公司，那是什么？
What were you feeling?
你有什么感觉？
Were you sitting behind the computer,
你坐在电脑后面，
how much do you actually know
你到底知道多少
about building stuff at that point?
那时要建造东西吗？
- Well, I could code a little bit
- 好吧，我可以写一点代码
'cause I did the YouTube channel
因为我制作了 YouTube 频道
and I made a website for...
我做了一个网站...
I would make websites for the YouTube channel.
我会为 YouTube 频道 制作网站。
It was called "Panda Mix Show."
它被称为“熊猫混合秀”。
And it was like these electronic music mixes,
就像这些电子音乐 混音一样，
like dubstep, or drum bass, or techno house.
比如 Dubstep、Drum bass 或 Techno House。
- [Lex] I saw one of them had Flash.
- [Lex] 我看到其中一个有 Flash。
Were you using Flash?
你用的是Flash吗？
- Yeah, my album, my CD album was using Flash.
- 是的，我的专辑，我的 CD 专辑使用的是 Flash。
Yeah, yeah. - Yeah.
是啊是啊。 - 是的。
- I sold my CD, yeah.
- 我卖掉了我的 CD，是的。
- Kids, Flash was a- - Flash was cool.
- 孩子们，Flash 太棒了 - Flash 太酷了。
- Software.
- 软件。
This is the break that- - Yeah, like grandpa,
这就是休息--是的， 就像爷爷一样，
but Flash was cool.
但Flash很酷。
- Yeah, and there was...
- 是的，还有……
What it is called?
它叫什么？
Boy, I should remember this ActionScript.
天哪，我应该记住这个 ActionScript。
There's some kind of programming language
有某种编程语言
- Script, yeah, yeah, ActionScript.
- 脚本，是的，是的，ActionScript。
- Oh, yeah. - It was in Flash.
- 哦，是的。 - 这是在 Flash 中。
Back then that was the JavaScript.
那时那是 JavaScript。
- The JavaScript, yeah. - Yeah.
- JavaScript，是的。 - 是 的。
And I thought that's gonna,
我以为那会，
that's supposed to be the dynamic thing
这应该是动态的事情
that takes over the internet. - Yeah.
接管互联网。 - 是的 。
- I invested so many hours in learning that.
- 我投入了很多时间 来学习这一点。
- And Steve Jobs killed it. - Steve Jobs.
- 史蒂夫·乔布斯杀死了它。 - 史蒂夫 ·乔布斯。
- Steve Jobs said, "Flash Sucks, stopped using it."
- 史蒂夫·乔布斯说：“闪存 很糟糕，停止使用它。”
Everyone is like, "Okay."
每个人都说：“好吧。”
- That guy was right though, right?
- 那家伙是对的，对吧？
- Yeah, I don't know, yeah.
- 是的，我不知道，是的。
Well, it was a closed platform I think and-
嗯，我认为这是一 个封闭的平台——
- Closed. - But this is ironic
- 关闭。 ——但这很讽刺
'cause Apple, they're not very open.
因为苹果，他们不是很开放。
- Right. - But back then Steve want
- 正确的 。 - 但当时史蒂夫想要
was like, this is closed.
就像，这已经关闭了。
We should not use it.
我们不应该使用它。
And it's a security problems I think,
我认为这是一个安全问题
which sounded like a cop out.
这听起来就像是警察出局了。
I just wanted to say that
我只是想说
to make it look kind of bad.
让它看起来有点糟糕。
But Flash was cool, yeah.
但 Flash 很酷，是的。
- Yeah, it was cool for a time.
- 是的，有一段时间很酷。
- Yeah. - Listen,
- 是的。 - 听，
animated GIFs were cool for a time too.
动画 GIF 也一度很酷。
- Yeah. - They came back
- 是的。 - 他们回来了
in a different way.
以不同的方式。
- Yeah. - As a meme though.
- 是的。 - 不过作为一个模因。
I mean like, I even remember when GIFs
我的意思是，我什至记得 GIF
were actually cool, not ironically cool.
实际上很酷，而不是讽刺性的酷。
- Yeah. - There's like,
- 是的。 - 有这样的，
on the internet you would have like
在互联网上你会喜欢
a dancing rabbit or something like this.
跳舞的兔子或类似的东西。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And that was really exciting.
- 这真的很令人兴奋。
- No, you had like the Lex homepage.
- 不，您喜欢 Lex 主页。
Everything was centered. - Yeah.
一切都集中在中心。 - 是 的。
- And you had like Pieter's homepage
- 你喜欢彼得的主页
and on the construction.
以及关于建设。
- Yeah. - GIF which was like
- 是的 。 - GIF 就像
a guy with a helmet and the lights.
一个戴着头盔和灯的家伙。
It was amazing. - And there banners.
太棒了。 - 还有横幅。
Yeah, that's before like Google AdSense,
是的，这就是之前的 Google AdSense，
you would've like banners for advertising.
您想要广告横幅。
- It was amazing, yeah.
- 太棒了，是的。
- And a lot of links to porn I think.
- 我认为还有很多色情链接。
- Yeah. - Or porny type things.
- 是的。 - 或者色情类型的东西。
- I think that devil's squared,
- 我认为魔鬼是平方的
and merchant accounts people would use for,
人们使用的 商业账户，
people would make money a lot.
人们会赚很多钱。
Only money made on internet was like porn or a lot of it.
只有在互联网上赚的钱 才像色情片或很多。
- Yeah, it was a dark place.
- 是的，那是一个黑暗的地方。
It's still a dark place. - Yeah.
这仍然是一个黑暗的地方。 - 是的。
- But there's beauty in the darkness.
- 但黑暗中也有美丽。
Anyway, so you did some basic HTML.
无论如何，您已经完成了一些基本的 HTML 操作。
- Yeah, yeah, but I had to learn the actual like coding.
- 是的，是的，但我必须 学习实际的编码。
So this was good.
所以这很好。
It was a good idea to like launch startup,
喜欢启动启动是个好主意，
so I could learn the codes, learn basic stuff.
这样我就可以学习代码 ，学习基本的东西。
But it was still very scrappy
但还是很斗志旺盛
'cause I didn't have time to,
因为我没有时间，
which is on purpose.
这是故意的。
I didn't have time to spend a lot of,
我没有时间花很多时间
I had a month to do something,
我有一个月的时间做某事
so I couldn't spend more than a month.
所以我不能花超过一个月的时间。
And I was pretty strict about that.
我对此非常严格。
And I published it as a blog post.
我将其作为博客文章发布。
So people, I think I put it on Hacker News
所以大家，我想我把它放在了黑客新闻上
and people would check kinda like, oh,
人们会检查一下，哦，
did you actually, you know.
你真的知道吗？
I felt like accountability,
我觉得自己有责任感，
'cause I put it public,
因为我把它公开了
that I actually had to do it.
我实际上必须这样做。
- Do you remember the first one you did?
- 你还记得你做的第一个吗？
- I think it was Play My Inbox,
- 我认为是播放我的收件箱，
'cause back then my friends,
因为那时我的朋友们
we would send like cool...
我们会很酷地发送...
It was before Spotify, I think, we would send like...
我想，那是在 Spotify 出现 之前，我们会发送......
2013, we would send music to each other,
2013年，我们会互相发送音乐，
like YouTube links.
就像 YouTube 链接一样。
This is a cool song, this is a cool song.
这是一首很酷的歌，这是一首很酷的歌。
And it was these giant email threads on Gmail.
这就是 Gmail 上这些巨大 的电子邮件线程。
And they were like unnavigable.
他们就像无法航行一样。
So I made an app that would log into your Gmail,
所以我制作了一个可以 登录你的 Gmail 的应用程序，
get them emails and find ones of YouTube links
向他们发送电子邮件并 找到 YouTube 链接
and then make kinda like a gallery of your songs.
然后制作得有点 像你的歌曲库。
Essentially Spotify,
本质上是 Spotify，
and my friends loved it.
我的朋友们很喜欢它。
- Was it scraping it?
- 是不是刮伤了？
Like what was API?
比如 API 是什么？
- No, it uses like a POP like POP or IMAP,
- 不，它使用像 POP 或 IMAP 这样的 POP，
Actually check your email,
实际上检查你的电子邮件，
so that like privacy concerns,
因此，就像隐私问题一样，
'cause it would get all your emails to find YouTube links.
因为它会通过您的所有电子 邮件来查找 YouTube 链接。
But then I wouldn't save anything.
但那样我就不会保存任何东西了。
But that was fun.
但这很有趣。
And that first product already would get pressed,
第一个产品已经 受到压力，
when think like some tech media and stuff.
当像一些科技媒体之类的东西思考时。
And I was like, that's cool.
我当时想，这很酷。
It didn't make money,
没赚到钱，
there was no payment button,
没有付款按钮，
but actually people using it.
但实际上人们在使用它。
I think tens of thousands of people used it.
我想有成千上万的人 使用过它。
- That's a great idea.
- 这是个好主意。
I wonder why, why don't we have that?
我想知道为什么，为什么我们没有这个？
Why don't we have things that access Gmail
为什么我们没有可以访问 Gmail 的东西
and extract some useful aggregate information.
并提取一些有用 的聚合信息。
- Yeah, yeah, you could tell Gmail,
- 是的，是的，你可以告诉 Gmail，
don't give me all the emails,
不要给我所有的电子邮件，
just give me the ones with YouTube links-
只要给我那些带有 YouTube 链接的-
- Yeah. - Or something like that.
- 是的。 - 或者类似的东西。
- Yeah, I mean there is a whole ecosystem
- 是的，我的意思是有一个完整的生态系统
of apps you can build on top of the Google.
您可以在 Google 之上 构建的应用程序。
- Yeah. - But people don't really-
- 是的 。 - 但人们并不真的-
- [Pieter] Never do this, I've ever see them.
- [Pieter] 永远不要 这样做，我见过他们。
- They build...
- 他们建造...
I've seen a few, like Boomerang,
我见过一些，比如回旋镖，
there's a few apps that are like good,
有一些应用程序非常好，
but just- - Yeah.
但只是- - 是 的。
- I wonder what...
- 我想知道什么...
Maybe it's not easy to make money.
也许赚钱并不容易。
- I think it's hard to get people to pay
- 我认为很难让人们付钱
for these like extensions and plugins, you know.
对于扩展和插件之类的 东西，你知道。
- Yeah. - 'Cause it's not a real app,
- 是的。 - 因为这不是一个真正的应用程序，
so it's not like people don't value it.
所以人们并不是不重视它。
People value, oh this...
人们重视，哦，这个...
And a plugin should be free.
并且插件应该是免费的。
When I want to use a plugin
当我想使用插件时
in Google Sheets or something,
在 Google 表格或其他东西中，
I'm not gonna pay for it.
我不会付钱的。
It should be free.
它应该是免费的。
But if you go to a website
但如果你访问一个网站
and you actually, okay, I need this product,
事实上，好吧，我需要 这个产品，
I'm gonna pay for this 'cause it's a real product.
我要付钱，因为 它是正品。
So even though it's the same code in the back.
所以即使后面的代码 是相同的。
It's a plugin.
这是一个插件。
- Yeah, I mean you could do it through extensions,
- 是的，我的意思是你可以 通过扩展来做到这一点，
like Chrome extensions through from the browser.
就像通过浏览器的 Chrome 扩展一样。
- Yeah, but who pays for Chrome extensions, right?
- 是的，但是谁为 Chrome 扩展付费，对吧？
- Nobody. - Barely anybody.
- 没有人。 - 几乎没有人。
- [Lex] Nobody.
- [莱克斯] 没有人。
- That's not a good place to make money, probably.
- 这可能不是一个 赚钱的好地方。
- Yeah, that sucks.
- 是的，那很糟糕。
- Chrome extension should be a extension for your startup.
- Chrome 扩展程序应该是您 初创公司的扩展程序。
You know, you have a product. - Yeah.
你知道，你有一个产品。 - 是 的。
- Oh, we also have a Chrome extension.
- 哦，我们还有一个 Chrome 扩展程序。
- I wish the Chrome extension would be the product.
- 我希望 Chrome 扩展 成为产品。
I wish Chrome would support that.
我希望 Chrome 能够支持这一点。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Where you could pay for it easily.
- 您可以轻松支付的地方。
Because imagine, I can imagine a lot of products
因为想象，我可以 想象很多产品
that would just live as extensions,
它只是作为扩展存在，
like improvements for social media.
比如社交媒体的改进。
- Yeah. - A thing that-
- 是的。 - 一个东西 -
- It's GPTs. - GPTs, yeah.
- 这是 GPT。 - GPT，是的。
- Like these ChatGPTs,
- 像这些 ChatGPT 一样，
they're gonna charge money for now.
他们现在要收钱。
And you get a rev share, I think from OpenAI.
我想，你会从 OpenAI 那里 获得收益份额。
I made a lot of them also.
我也做了很多。
- Why?
- 为什么？
We'll talk about it. - Yeah.
我们会讨论它。 - 是 的。
- So let's rewind back. (Pieter laughs)
- 那么让我们倒回过去。 （彼得笑）
It's a pretty cool idea to do 12 startups in 12 months.
在 12 个月内创办 12 家初创 公司是一个非常酷的想法。
What's it take to build a thing in 30 days?
在 30 天内建造一个东西 需要什么？
At that time, how hard was that?
那个时候，有多难呢？
- I think the hard part is figuring out
- 我认为最困难的部分是弄清楚
what you shouldn't add, right?
你不应该添加什么，对吧？
Which you shouldn't build because you don't have time.
你不应该建造它， 因为你没有时间。
So you need to build a landing page.
所以你需要建立一个登陆页面。
Well, you need to make the... (Lex laughs)
好吧，你需要做……（Lex 笑）
You need to build the product actually,
你需要实际构建产品，
'cause it need to be something they pay for.
因为这需要他们 付出代价。
Do you need to build a login system?
您需要建立一个登录系统吗？
Maybe no, maybe you can build some scrappy login system.
也许不，也许你可以构建一些 杂乱的登录系统。
For Photo AI, you sign up,
对于 Photo AI，您需要注册，
you pay, Stripe checkout,
你付款，Stripe 结帐，
and you get a login link.
然后你会得到一个登录链接。
And when I started out,
当我开始时，
there was only a login link with a hash
只有一个带有哈希值的登录链接
and that's just a static link.
这只是一个静态链接。
So it's very easy to log in.
所以登录非常容易。
- Yeah. - It's not so safe.
- 是的 。 - 不太安全。
What if you link the link
如果你链接链接怎么办
and now I have real Google login,
现在我有了真正的谷歌登录，
but that took like a year.
但这花了大约一年的时间。
So keeping it very scrappy is very important too,
所以保持斗志旺盛 也很重要，
because you don't have time.
因为你没有时间。
You need to focus on what you can build fast.
您需要专注于可以 快速构建的内容。
So money, Stripe,
所以钱，条纹，
build a product,
构建一个产品，
build a landing page.
构建一个登陆页面。
You need to think about how are people gonna find this?
你需要考虑人们 如何找到这个？
So are you gonna put it on Reddit or something?
那么你会把它放到 Reddit 或者其他什么地方吗？
How are you gonna put it on Reddit
你打算如何把它放到 Reddit 上
without being looked at as a spammer, right?
不会被视为垃圾邮件 发送者，对吧？
If you say, "Hey, this is my new startup,
如果你说，“嘿，这是我的新创业公司，
you should use it."
你应该使用它。”
No, nobody gets deleted.
不，没有人被删除。
Maybe if you find a problem
也许如果你发现问题
that a lot of people on Reddit already have
Reddit 上很多 人已经有了
and sub-Reddit,
和 Reddit 子版块，
and you solve that problem and say,
然后你解决了这个问题并说，
"Sub-people, I made this thing
“子人们，这东西是我做的
that might solve your problem
这可能会解决你的问题
and maybe it's free for now."
也许现在是免费的。”
That could work.
那可行。
But you need to be very
但你需要非常
narrow it down, what you're building.
缩小范围，你正在构建什么。
- Time is limited. - Yeah.
- 时间有限。 - 是 的。
- Actually, can we go back to the,
- 事实上，我们可以回到过去吗？
you laying in a room feeling like a loser?
你躺在房间里感觉自己像个失败者吗？
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- I still feel like a loser sometimes
- 有时我仍然觉得自己是个失败者
Can you speak to that feeling,
能说说那种感觉吗
to that place of just like,
到那个地方就像，
feeling like a loser?
感觉自己像个失败者？
Because I think a lot of people in this world
因为我觉得这个 世界上有很多人
are laying in a room right now listening to this.
现在正躺在房间 里听这个。
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - And feeling like a loser.
- 是啊，是啊，是啊 。 - 感觉自己像个失败者。
- Okay, so I think it's normal if you're young
- 好吧，所以我认为如果 你还年轻的话这很正常
that you feel like a loser, first of all.
首先，你感觉自己是个失败者。
- Especially, when you're 27. - Yes.
- 尤其是当你27岁的时候。 - 是 的。
Yeah, especially. - There's like a peak.
是的，特别是。 - 就像一个高峰。
- Yeah, yeah, I think 20 is the peak.
- 是的，是的，我认为20岁是巅峰。
And so I would not kill yourselves.
所以我不会自杀。
It's very important.
这非常重要。
Just get through it.
只要熬过去就好了。
Because you have nothing, probably no money,
因为你一无所有，可能 没有钱，
you have no business, you have no job yet.
你还没有生意，你还没有工作。
Jordan Peterson said this, I saw it somewhere,
乔丹·彼得森说过这句 话，我在某处看到过，
people are depressed because they have nothing.
人们因为一无所有 而感到沮丧。
They don't have a girlfriend.
他们没有女朋友。
They don't have a boyfriend.
他们没有男朋友。
They don't have a...
他们没有...
You need stuff, you need like, or a family.
你需要东西，你需要 喜欢，或者一个家庭。
You need things around you.
你需要你身边的东西。
You need to build a life for yourself.
你需要为自己创造生活。
If you don't build a life for yourself, you'll be depressed.
如果你不为自己创造生活 ，你就会感到沮丧。
So if you're alone in Asia in a hostel
所以如果你独自一人在亚洲的旅馆里
looking at the ceiling,
看着天花板，
and you don't have any money coming in,
而且你没有任何钱进来
you don't have a girlfriend,
你没有女朋友，
you don't, of course, you're depressed.
当然，你不会，你很沮丧。
It's logic.
这是逻辑。
But back then, if you're in a moment,
但那时候，如果你有一刻，
you think there's not logic,
你觉得没有逻辑
there's something wrong with me.
我有问题。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- And also I think I started getting like anxiety,
- 而且我想我开始 变得焦虑，
and I think I started going a little bit crazy
我想我开始变得 有点疯狂
where I think travel can make you sane.
我认为旅行可以让你保持理智。
And I know this because I know that there's like
我知道这一点是因为 我知道有这样的事情
digital nomads that they kill themselves.
数字游牧民自杀了。
I haven't checked the comparison
我没有检查过比较
with baseline people, like suicide rate.
与基线人群相比，比如自杀率。
But I have a hunch,
但我有预感，
especially in the beginning
尤其是在开始的时候
when it was a very new thing like 10 years ago,
十年前，当它还是一个 非常新鲜的事物时，
that it can be very psychologically taxing.
这可能会造成很 大的心理负担。
And you're alone a lot,
而你却常常孤身一人，
back then when you travel alone,
那时候一个人旅行的时候
there was no other digital nomads back then, a lot.
那时还没有很多其他 数字游牧民。
So you're in a strange culture.
所以你处于一种奇怪的文化之中。
You look different in everybody.
每个人的你看起来都不一样。
I was in Asia,
我当时在亚洲，
everybody's really nice in Thailand,
泰国人都很好
but you're not part of the culture.
但你不是文化的一部分。
You're traveling around,
你到处旅行，
you're hopping from city to city.
你从一个城市跳到另一个城市。
You don't have a home anymore.
你已经没有家了。
You feel disrooted.
你感觉自己失去了根基。
- And you're constantly in the outcast
- 而你却一直处于被排斥的境地
and that you're different from everybody else.
并且你与其他 人不同。
- Yes, exactly.
- 是的，完全正确。
Like Thailand, people are so nice.
就像泰国一样，人们都很友善。
- [Lex] Yes.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- But you still feel like outcast.
- 但你仍然感觉自己被抛弃了。
And then I think the digital nomads I met then
然后我想我当时遇到 的数字游牧民族
were all kinda like,
都有点像，
it was like shady business.
这就像阴暗的生意。
But they were like vigilantes
但他们就像义务警员
'cause it was a new thing.
因为这是一个新事物。
And one guy was selling illegal drugs.
其中一名男子正在出售非法毒品。
It was an American guy.
那是一个美国人。
It was selling illegal drugs
原来是贩卖非法毒品
via UPS to Americans on this website.
通过 UPS 在此网站上寄给美国人。
There were a lot of dropshippers doing shady stuff.
有很多代发货商 在做不正当的事情。
There's a lot of shady things going on there.
那里发生了很多 阴暗的事情。
And they didn't look like very balanced people.
他们看起来不像是非常 平衡的人。
They didn't look like people I wanted to hang with.
他们看起来不像是我想 与之相处的人。
So I also felt outcast from other foreigners
所以我也感到被其他 外国人排斥
in Thailand, other digital nomads.
在泰国，还有其他数字游牧民族。
And I was like, "Man, I made a big mistake."
我当时想，“伙计，我 犯了一个大错误。”
And then I went back to Holland
然后我就回到了荷兰
and then I got even more depressed.
然后我变得更加沮丧。
- You said digital nomad.
- 你说的是数字游牧者。
What is digital nomad?
什么是数字游民？
What is that way of life?
那是什么生活方式？
What is the philosophy there?
那里的哲学是什么？
And the history of the movement.
以及运动的历史。
- I struck upon it on accident.
- 我偶然发现了它。
'Cause I was like, I'm gonna graduate university
因为我当时想， 我要大学毕业了
and then I need to get out of here.
然后我需要离开这里。
I'll fly to Asia,
我将飞往亚洲，
'cause I've been before in Asia.
因为我以前去过亚洲。
I studied in Korea in 2009.
我2009年去韩国留学。
Study exchange.
学习交流。
I was like, Asia is easy.
我当时想，亚洲很容易。
Thailand is easy.
泰国很简单。
And I'll just go there, figure things out.
我会去那里解决问题。
And it's cheap.
而且很便宜。
It's very cheap.
非常便宜。
Chiang Mai, I would live like for $150 per month rent.
清迈，我愿意以每月 150 美元的租金生活。
- Yeah. - For like a private room.
- 是的。 - 像私人房间一样。
Pretty good.
不错。
So I struggled on this on accident.
所以我偶然在这件事上挣扎了。
I was like, okay, there's other people on laptops
我当时想，好吧，还有其他 人在使用笔记本电脑
working on their startup or working remotely.
正在启动或远程 工作。
Back then nobody worked remotely,
那时候没有人远程工作，
but they worked on their businesses, right?
但他们都在做自己 的生意，对吧？
And they would live in Columbia or Thailand
他们会住在哥伦比亚 或泰国
or Vietnam or Bali.
或越南或巴厘岛。
They would live kind of like in more cheap places.
他们会像住在更便宜 的地方一样生活。
And it looked a very adventurous life.
这看起来是一种非常冒险的生活。
You travel around, you build your business.
你到处旅行，你建立 你的事业。
There's no pressure from your home society, right?
没有来自家乡 的压力吧？
You're American.
你是美国人。
So you get pressure from American society
所以你会受到来自美国社会的压力
telling you kind of what to do.
告诉你该做什么。
You need to buy a house or you need to do this stuff.
你需要买房子或者你 需要做这些事情。
I had this in Holland too.
我在荷兰也吃过这个。
And you can get away from this pressure.
并且你可以摆脱这种压力。
You can kind of feel like you're free.
你可以感觉自己是自由的。
There's nobody telling you what to do.
没有人告诉你该做什么。
But that's also why you start feeling like you go crazy
但这也是为什么你开始 感觉自己疯了
'cause you are free,
因为你是自由的，
you're disattached from anything and anybody,
你对任何事、任何 人都超脱了，
you're disattached from your culture.
你与你的文化脱节了。
You're disattached from the culture you're probably in,
你可能脱离了你 所处的文化，
'cause you're staying very short.
因为你停留的时间很短。
- I think Franz Kafka said, "I'm free, therefore I'm lost."
- 我想弗朗茨·卡夫卡说过，“ 我自由了，所以我迷失了。”
- Man, that's so true.
- 伙计，那是真的。
Yeah, that's exactly the point.
是的，这就是重点。
And yeah, freedom is like,
是的，自由就像，
it's the definition of no constraints, right?
这是没有约束的 定义，对吗？
Anything is possible.
一切皆有可能。
You can go anywhere.
你可以去任何地方。
And everybody's like, "Oh, that must be super nice."
每个人都会说，“哦， 那一定非常好。”
Freedom, you must be very happy.
自由了，你一定很幸福。
And it's opposites, I don't think that makes you happy.
这是相反的，我不认为 这会让你快乐。
I think constraints probably make you happy,
我认为约束可能 会让你快乐，
and that's a big lesson I learned then.
这是我当时学到的一个重要教训。
- But what were they making for money?
- 但他们是靠什么赚钱的呢？
So you're saying they were doing shady stuff at that time?
那你是说他们当时在 做一些见不得人的事？
- For me, 'cause I was more like a developer.
- 对我来说，因为我更 像是一名开发人员。
I wanted to make startups kind of,
我想创办一家这样的公司
and it was like drugs being shipped to America,
就像毒品被运到 美国一样
like diet pills and stuff.
比如减肥药之类的。
Non-FDA proof stuff.
非 FDA 证明的东西。
And they would like let...
他们想让...
They would say with beers
他们会说用啤酒
and they would laugh about like
他们会笑说
all the dodgy shit kind of they're doing.
他们正在做的所有狡猾的事情。
- That part of, okay. - That kind of vibe.
- 那部分，好吧。 - 那种氛围。
Kind of sleazy, e-comm vibe.
有点低俗的电子商务氛围。
I'm not saying all e-comm is these.
我并不是说所有的电子商务都是这些。
- Right. - But, you know, this vibe.
- 正确的。 - 但是，你知道，这种氛围。
- It could be a vibe
- 这可能是一种氛围
and your vibe was more build cool shit.
你的氛围更酷。
- Make cool stuff. - That's ethical.
- 制作很酷的东西。 - 这是道德的。
- You know, the guys with sports cars in Dubai,
- 你知道，迪拜那些 开跑车的人，
these people, you know. - Yes.
这些人，你知道。 - 是 的。
- E-comm like, oh bro, you gotta drop ship.
- 电子商务就像，哦兄弟 ，你必须放弃发货。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And you'll make 100 million a month.
- 这样你每个月就能赚一亿。
Those people was this shit.
那些人就是这样的狗屎。
And I was like, this is not my people.
我当时想，这不是我的人。
- Yeah, I mean there's nothing wrong
- 是的，我的意思是没有什么问题
with any of those individual components.
与任何这些单独的组件。
- No, no judgment.
- 不，没有判断。
- But there's a foundation that's not quite ethical.
- 但有一个基金会 不太道德。
What is that?
那是什么？
I don't know what that is, but yeah, I get you.
我不知道那是什么，但是 ，是的，我明白你的意思。
- No, I don't wanna judge.
- 不，我不想评判。
I noted for me, it wasn't my world,
我为自己指出，这不是我的世界，
it wasn't my subculture.
这不是我的亚文化。
I wanted to make cool shit.
我想做一些很酷的事情。
But they also think their shit is cool.
但他们也认为自己的东西很酷。
But I wanted to make real startups and that was my thing.
但我想创办真正的初创 公司，这就是我的事。
I would read Hacker News, like Y Combinator,
我会阅读黑客新闻 ，比如 Y Combinator，
and they were making cool stuff.
他们正在制作很酷的东西。
So I wanted to make cool stuff.
所以我想做一些很酷的东西。
- I mean, that's a pretty cool way of life.
- 我的意思是，这是 一种很酷的生活方式。
Just if you romanticize it for a moment.
只要你把它浪漫化一会儿就好了。
- It's very romantic man.
- 这是一个非常浪漫的人。
It's colorful.
它是丰富多彩的。
If I think about the memories.
如果我想起那些回忆。
- What are some happy memories?
- 有哪些幸福的回忆？
Just like working,
就像工作一样，
working in cafes or working in
在咖啡馆工作或在
just the freedom that envelopes you
只是包裹着你的自由
from that way of life,
从那样的生活方式，
'cause anything is possible,
因为一切皆有可能
you can just get off of. - I think it was amazing.
你就可以下车了。 - 我认为这太棒了。
We would work.
我们会工作。
I would make friends
我会交朋友
and we would work until 6:00 AM in Bali, for example,
例如，在巴厘岛我们会 工作到早上 6:00，
with Andre, my best friend
和我最好的朋友安德烈
was still my best friend and another friend,
仍然是我最好的朋友 和另一个朋友，
and we would work until the morning
我们会工作到早上
when the sun came up.
当太阳升起的时候。
Because at night, the coworking space was silence.
因为到了晚上，联合 办公空间一片寂静。
There was nobody else.
没有其他人。
And I would wake up 6:00 PM or 5:00 PM.
我会在下午 6:00 或 5:00 起床。
I would drive to the coworking space on a motorbike.
我会骑摩托车前往联合 办公空间。
I would buy 30 hot lattes from a cafe.
我会从咖啡馆买 30 杯热拿铁。
- How many? - 30.
- 有多少？ - 30.
'Cause there was like six people coming
因为大约有六个人来了
or we didn't know.
或者我们不知道。
Sometimes people would come in.
有时会有人进来。
- Did you say three, zero, 30?
- 你说的是三、零、30？
- Yeah. - Nice.
- 是的。 - 好的。
- And we would drink like four per person or something.
- 我们会每人喝 四杯什么的。
- Yeah. - Man, it's Bali.
- 是的。 - 伙计，这是巴厘岛。
I don't know if they were powerful lattes,
我不知道它们是否是强力拿铁咖啡
but they were lattes and we'd put 'em in a plastic bag
但它们是拿铁咖啡，我们 把它们放在塑料袋里
and then we'd drive there
然后我们开车去那里
and all the coffee was like falling everywhere.
所有的咖啡都掉 得到处都是。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- And then we'd go negotiate
- 然后我们就去谈判
and have these coffees here
在这里喝这些咖啡
and we'd work all night.
我们会整夜工作。
We'd play like techno music,
我们会像科技音乐一样演奏，
and everybody would just work in there.
每个人都会在那里工作。
This was literally like business people.
这实际上就像商人一样。
They would work in their startup
他们会在自己的初创公司工作
and we'd all try and make something.
我们都会尝试做点什么。
And then the sun would come up
然后太阳就会升起
and the morning people,
还有早起的人们，
the yoga,
瑜伽，
yoga girls and yoga guys would come in
瑜伽女孩和瑜伽男孩会进来
after the yoga class at six,
六点的瑜伽课结束后，
and they'd say, "Hey, good morning."
他们会说：“嘿，早上好。”
And we're like, we look like this.
我们就像，我们看起来像这样。
- Yeah. - And we're like,
- 是的。 - 我们就像，
what's up, how are you doing?
怎么了，你好吗？
And we didn't know how bad we looked,
我们不知道自己看起来有多糟糕，
but it was very bad.
但这非常糟糕。
And then we'd go home, sleep in a hostel or a hotel
然后我们就回家， 睡在旅馆或酒店里
and do the same thing and again and again and again.
并一次又一次地 做同样的事情。
And it was this lock-in mode, like working.
这就是这种锁定模式， 就像工作一样。
And that was very fun.
这非常有趣。
- So it's just a bunch of you
- 所以这只是你们一群人
techno music blasting
科技音乐爆炸
all through the night, yeah.
整个晚上，是的。
- More like (imitates techno music)
- 更像（模仿电子音乐）
Like industrial. - Rap chase.
喜欢工业。 - 说 唱追逐。
- Not like this cheesy.
- 不像这么俗气。
- For me, it's such an interesting thing
- 对我来说，这是一件很有趣的事情
because the speed of the beat
因为节拍的速度
affects how I feel about a thing.
影响我对某件事的感受。
- Yeah. - So the faster it is,
- 是的。 - 所以速度越快，
the more anxiety I feel.
我感觉越焦虑。
But that anxiety is channeled into productivity.
但这种焦虑会 转化为生产力。
But if it's a little too fast,
但如果速度有点太快的话
the anxiety overpowers that.
焦虑压倒了这一点。
- So you don't like drum bass music?
- 所以你不喜欢鼓贝斯音乐？
- No, probably not.
- 不，可能不会。
- No, it's too fast. - I mean, for working,
- 不，太快了。 - 我的 意思是，为了工作，
I have to play with it. - Yeah.
我必须玩它。 - 是 的。
- It's like you can actually,
- 就像你实际上可以，
I can adjust my- - Yeah.
我可以调整我的- - 是的。
- Level of anxiety.
- 焦虑程度。
There's a must be a better word than anxiety.
一定有一个比 焦虑更好的词。
It's like productive anxiety
这就像生产性焦虑
that I like. - Yeah.
我喜欢的。 - 是 的。
- Whatever that is.
- 不管那是什么。
- It also depends what kind of work you do, right?
- 这也取决于你从事什么 类型的工作，对吧？
If you're writing,
如果你正在写作，
you probably don't want drum bass music.
您可能不想要鼓贝斯音乐。
I think for codes like industrial techno,
我认为对于像工业技术这样的代码，
this kind of stuff, kind of fast.
这种东西，速度有点快。
It works well, 'cause you really get locked in
效果很好，因为你 真的被锁在里面了
and combined with caffeine,
并与咖啡因结合，
you go deep. - (laughs) Yeah.
你深入。 -（ 笑）是的。
- And I think you balance on this edge of anxiety,
- 我认为你在焦虑的 边缘保持平衡，
'cause this caffeine is also hitting your anxiety.
因为咖啡因也会 消除你的焦虑。
And you want to be on the edge of anxiety
而你想要处于焦虑的边缘
with this techno running.
随着这个技术的运行。
Sometimes it gets too much.
有时它变得太多了。
It's like stop the techno, stop the music is like,
就像停止电子音乐， 停止音乐就像，
but those are good memories.
但那些都是美好的回忆。
And also like travel memories.
也喜欢旅行的回忆。
You go from city to city. - Yeah.
你从一个城市到另一个城市。 - 是的。
- And it feels like, it's kinda like jet set life.
- 感觉有点像喷气式 飞机的生活。
It's feels very beautiful.
给人的感觉是非常的美丽。
You're seeing a lot of cool cities.
你会看到很多很酷的城市。
- What was your favorite place
- 你最喜欢的地方是哪里
that you remember, you visited?
你还记得，你去过吗？
- I think still Bangkok is the best place.
- 我认为曼谷仍然是最好的地方。
And Bangkok and Chiang Mai.
还有曼谷和清迈。
I think Thailand is very special.
我觉得泰国很特别。
I've been to the other place.
我去过另一个地方。
I've been to Vietnam
我去过越南
and I've been to South America and stuff.
我还去过南美之类的地方。
I still think Thailand wins in how nice people are.
我仍然认为泰国的胜利 在于人民的友善。
How easy of a life people have there.
那里的人们的生活多么轻松啊。
- Everything is cheap.
- 一切都很便宜。
- Yeah. - And good.
- 是的。 - 很好。
- Well, Bangkok is getting expensive now,
- 嗯，曼谷现在越来越贵了，
but Chiang Mai is still cheap.
不过清迈还是便宜。
I think when you're starting out.
我想当你刚开始的时候。
It's a great place.
这是一个很棒的地方。
Man, the air quality sucks.
哎呀，空气质量太糟糕了。
It's a big problem.
这是一个大问题。
And it's quite hot.
而且天气很热。
But that's a very cool place.
但这是一个非常酷的地方。
- [Lex] Pros and cons.
- [Lex] 优点和缺点。
- I love Brazil also.
- 我也爱巴西。
My girlfriend is Brazilian.
我女朋友是巴西人。
Not just because of that, but I like Brazil.
不仅因为这个， 而且我喜欢巴西。
The problem still is the safety issue.
问题仍然是安全问题。
It's like in America, like it's localized.
就像在美国一样，它是本地化的。
It's hard for Europeans to understand.
欧洲人很难理解。
Safety is localized to specific areas.
安全仅限于特定区域。
So if you go to the right areas, it's amazing.
所以如果你去对了地方 ，那就太棒了。
Brazil is amazing.
巴西真是太棒了。
If you go to wrong areas, maybe you die.
如果你走错了地方，也许你就会死。
Right? - Yeah.
正确的？ - 是的。
Yeah, I mean that's true.
是的，我的意思是那是真的。
- But it's not true in Europe.
- 但在欧洲却并非如此。
In Europe it's much more- - That's true.
在欧洲，情况要严重得多—— 这是事实。
That's true. - More average.
这是真的。 - 更平均。
- You're right, you're right.
- 你是对的，你是对的。
It's more averaged out. - Yeah.
它更加平均。 - 是 的。
- I like it when there's strong neighborhoods,
- 我喜欢有强大 的社区，
when you're like, you cross a certain street
当你穿过某 条街道时
and you're in a dangerous part of town.
而你正处于城镇的危险区域。
- Man, yeah.
- 伙计，是的。
- I like it.
- 我喜欢它。
I like there's certain cities
我喜欢某些城市
in the United States like that.
在美国就是这样。
- Yeah. - I like that.
- 是的。 - 我喜欢这样。
And you're saying Europe is more about that.
你是说欧洲更注重 这一点。
- But you don't feel scared?
- 但你不感到害怕吗？
- Well, I don't,
- 嗯，我不，
I like danger. - Well, you BJJ.
我喜欢危险。 - 好 吧，你巴西柔术。
- No, not even just that.
- 不，不仅如此。
I think dangers interesting. - Yeah.
我认为危险很有趣。 - 是 的。
- Danger reveals something about yourself, about others.
- 危险揭示了关于你自己 和他人的一些事情。
Also, I like the full range of humanity.
另外，我喜欢全方位的人性。
- Yeah. - So I don't like
- 是的。 - 所以我不喜欢
the mellowed out aspects of humanity.
人性成熟的方面。
- I have friends like,
- 我有这样的朋友，
nomad friends that are exactly like this.
游牧朋友正是这样的。
They go to the kind of broken areas.
他们去那种破碎的地区。
They like this reality.
他们喜欢这个现实。
They like the authenticity more.
他们更喜欢真实性。
They don't like luxury.
他们不喜欢奢侈。
They don't like- - Oh, yeah, I hate luxury.
他们不喜欢—— 哦，是的，我讨厌奢侈。
- Yeah.
- 是的。 - 是的。
- It's very European view, right? (laughs)
- 这是非常欧洲的观点，对吧？ （笑）
- Wait, was that? (Lex and Pieter laughs)
- 等等，是吗？ （ 莱克斯和彼得笑了）
That's a whole nother conversation.
那是另一场谈话了。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- So you quoted Freya Stark quote,
- 所以你引用了弗雷娅·史塔克的话，
"To awaken quite alone in a strange town
“在一个陌生的小镇独自醒来
is one of the most pleasant sensations in the world."
是世界上最令人愉悦 的感觉之一。”
- Yeah. - Do you remember a time
- 是的。 - 你还记得有一次吗
you had woken in a strange town and felt like that?
你在一个陌生的小镇醒来 并有这样的感觉吗？
We're talking about small towns or big towns or?
我们谈论的是小城镇 还是大城市？
- Man, anywhere.
- 伙计，任何地方。
I think I wrote it in some blog posts and like...
我想我在一些博客文章中 写过它并且喜欢......
It was a common thing when you would wake up
当你醒来时这是 很常见的事情
and this was like...
这就像...
I have this website.
我有这个网站。
I started a website about this digital nomads,
我创建了一个关于这个数字 游牧民族的网站，
called nomadlist.com.
名为 nomadlist.com。
And this was a community,
这是一个社区，
so it was like 3,000 other digital nomads,
所以它就像其他 3,000 名数字游牧民一样，
'cause I was feeling lonely.
因为我感到孤独。
So I built this website and I stopped feeling lonely.
所以我建立了这个网站 ，我不再感到孤独。
I started organizing meetups and making friends
我开始组织聚会 并结交朋友
and it was very common that people would say,
人们很常见 地会说，
they would wake up and they would forget where they are.
他们会醒来，然后 忘记自己在哪里。
- Yeah. - For the first half minute.
- 是的 。 - 前半分钟。
And I had to look outside like, where am I?
我必须向外 看，我在哪里？
Which country?
哪个国家？
Which sounds really like privileged,
这听起来真的很特权，
but it was more like funny.
但这更像是有趣。
You literally don't know where you are
你根本不知道自己在哪里
because you're so disrooted.
因为你是如此的无根。
But there's something...
但有件事...
Man, it's like Anthony Bourdain.
伙计，这就像安东尼·波登。
There's something pure about this kinda
有一些纯粹的东西
vagabond travel thing.
流浪者旅行的事情。
It's behind me, I think.
我想它就在我身后。
Now I travel with my girlfriend, right?
现在我和女朋友一起旅行，对吗？
It's very different.
这是非常不同的。
But it is a romantic,
但这是一种浪漫，
memories of this kind of like vagabond,
这种像流浪者一样的回忆，
individualistic solo life.
个人主义的独居生活。
But the thing, it didn't make me happy,
但事情并没有让我高兴，
but it was very cool.
但这非常酷。
But it didn't make me happy, right?
但这并没有让我高兴，对吧？
It made me anxious.
这让我很焦虑。
- There's something about it that make you anxious.
- 有一些事情让 你感到焦虑。
I don't know, I still feel like that,
不知道，我还是有这样的感觉
it's a cool feeling.
这是一种很酷的感觉。
It's scary at first,
一开始很害怕
but then you realize where you are.
但随后你就会意识到自己在哪里。
I don't know, it's like you awaken
我不知道，就像你醒了一样
to the possibilities of this place-
这个地方的可能性-
- That's it. - When you feel like that.
- 就是这样。 - 当你有这样的感觉时。
- That's great.
- 那太棒了。
And it's even when you're doing some basic travel.
即使您进行一些基本 的旅行也是如此。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Go to San Francisco or something else.
- 去旧金山或者其他地方。
- Yeah, you have like the novelty effect.
- 是的，你喜欢新奇的效果。
You're in a new place.
你到了一个新地方。
Here things are possible.
在这里一切皆有可能。
You don't get bored yet.
你还不会感到无聊。
And that's why people get addicted to travel.
这就是人们沉迷于 旅行的原因。
- Back to startups.
- 回到初创公司。
You wrote a book on how to do this thing
你写了一本关于如何做这件事的书
and gave a great talk on it, how to do startups.
并就如何创业做了 精彩的演讲。
The book is called "Make: Bootstrapper's Handbook."
这本书的名字叫《Make：Bootstrapper's Handbook》。
- Yeah. - I was wondering
- 是的 。 - 我想知道
if you could go through some of the steps.
如果您可以完成一些步骤。
It's idea, build, launch, grow,
它的创意、构建、启动、成长，
monetize, automate, and exit.
货币化、自动化并退出。
There's a lot of fascinating ideas in each one.
每一个都有很多有趣 的想法。
So idea stage. - Yeah.
所以想法阶段。 - 是的。
- How do you find a good idea?
- 你如何找到一个好主意？
- So I think you need to be able to spot problems.
- 所以我认为你需要 能够发现问题。
So for example, you can go in your daily life,
例如，你可以在 日常生活中，
when you wake up and you're like,
当你醒来的时候你会想
what are stuff that I'm really annoyed with?
我真正生气的事情 是什么？
In my daily life that doesn't function well,
在我的日常生活中 ，功能不太好，
and that's a problem that you can see.
这是一个你可以看到的问题。
Okay, maybe that's something I can add, write code about,
好吧，也许我可以添加 一些东西，编写代码，
code for and it will make my life easier.
代码，它会让我的生活更轻松。
So I would say make like a list
所以我会说像列表一样
of all these problems you have
你遇到的所有这些问题
and like an idea to solve it,
并喜欢一个解决它的想法，
and see which one is like viable.
看看哪一个是可行的。
You can actually do something and then start building it.
您实际上可以做一些事情 ，然后开始构建它。
- So that's a really good place to start.
- 所以这是一个非常好的起点。
Become open to all the problems in your life.
对生活中的所有问题 保持开放的态度。
Like actually start noticing them.
就像真正开始注意到他们一样。
- Yeah. - I think that's actually
- 是的。 - 我认为这实际上是
not a true real thing to do,
不是真正要做的事情，
to realize that some aspects of your life
意识到你生活的某些方面
could be done way, way better.
可以做得更好。
- Yeah. - Because we kinda
- 是的。 - 因为我们有点
very quickly get accustomed to discomforts.
很快就习惯 了不适。
- [Pieter] Exactly.
- [彼得] 没错。
- Like for example, like doorknobs.
- 例如，像门把手。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Design of certain things. (laughs)
- 某些事物的设计。 （笑）
- I knew you like scream and doorknob.
- 我知道你喜欢尖叫和门把手。
- Yeah. - 50 tons.
- 是的。 - 50吨。
- Well, that one I know how much
- 嗯，那个我知道多少
incredible design work has gone into.
令人难以置信的设计工作已经投入使用。
It's a really interesting.
这真的很有趣。
- Yeah. - Doors and doorknobs.
- 是的 。 - 门和门把手。
Just the design of everyday things.
只是日常用品的设计。
- Yeah. - Forks and spoons.
- 是的。 - 叉子和勺子。
It's gonna be hard to come up with a fork
拿出叉子会很困难
that's better than the current-
这比现在的好——
- Yeah. - Fork designs.
- 是的。 - 叉子设计。
- And the other aspect of it
- 是的 。 -还有它的另一个方面
is you're saying like,
你是说，
in order to come up with interesting ideas,
为了想出有趣 的想法，
you gotta try to live a more interesting life.
你必须尝试过一种 更有趣的生活。
- Yeah, but that's where travel comes in.
- 是的，但这就是旅行的用武之地。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- Because when I started traveling,
- 因为当我开始旅行时
I started seeing stuff in other countries
我开始看到其他国家的东西
that you didn't have in Europe, for example,
例如，你在欧洲 没有的，
or America even.
甚至是美国。
If you go to Asia,
如果你去亚洲，
dude, especially 10 years ago,
老兄，尤其是10年前，
nobody knew about this WeChats,
没有人知道这个微信，
all these apps that they already had
他们已经拥有的所有这些应用程序
before we had them,
在我们拥有它们之前，
these everything apps, right?
这些应用程序应有尽有，对吗？
Now Elon's trying to make X,
现在埃隆正在努力创造 X，
this everything app like WeChat, same thing.
这个一切应用程序 就像微信一样。
In Indonesia or Thailand,
在印度尼西亚或泰国，
you have one app that you can order food,
你有一个可以订餐的应用程序，
if you can order groceries,
如果您可以订购杂货，
you can order massage,
您可以订购按摩，
you can order car mechanic.
您可以订购汽车修理工。
Anything you can think of is in the app.
你能想到的一切都在应用程序中。
And that stuff, for example,
那些东西，例如，
that's called arbitrage.
这就是所谓的套利。
You can go to back to your country
你可以回你的国家了
and build that same app for your country, for example.
例如，为您所在的国家/地区 构建相同的应用程序。
So you start seeing problems,
所以你开始看到问题，
you start seeing solutions
你开始看到解决方案
that other people already did in the rest of the world.
世界其他地方的 人已经这么做了。
And also traveling in general
还有一般的旅行
just gives you more problems,
只会给你带来更多的问题
'cause travel is uncomfortable.
因为旅行不舒服。
Airports are horrible.
机场太可怕了。
Airplanes are not comfortable either.
飞机也不舒服。
There's a lot of problems you start seeing,
你开始看到很多 问题
just getting outta your house, you know.
刚离开你的家，你知道。
- But also you can, I mean in the digital world
- 但你也可以，我 是说在数字世界
you can just go into different communities
你可以去不同的社区
and see what can be improved-
看看有什么可以改进的地方-
- Yes. - In that.
- 是的。 - 在那。
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 是啊，是啊，是啊。
- What specifically is your process of generating ideas?
- 您产生想法的具体 过程是什么？
Do you like do idea dumps?
你喜欢倾倒创意吗？
Do you have a document where you just keep writing stuff?
你有一个可以让你不断 写东西的文档吗？
- Yeah, I used to have like a...
- 是的，我曾经有过这样的...
'Cause when I wasn't making money,
因为当我不赚钱的时候
I was trying to like make this list of ideas to see like,
我试图将这个想法列表 看起来像，
so I need to build...
所以我需要建立...
I was thinking statistically already,
我已经在考虑统计了
like I need to build all these things,
就像我需要建造所有这些东西，
and one of these will work out probably.
其中之一可能会成功。
So I need to have a lot of things to try.
所以我需要有很多事情去尝试。
And I did that.
我就这么做了。
Right now I think like,
现在我想，
because I already have money,
因为我已经有钱了
I can do more things based on technology.
我可以依靠技术做更多的事情。
So for example, AI,
例如，人工智能，
when I found out about
当我发现
when Stable Diffusion came or ChatGPT and stuff,
当稳定扩散或 ChatGPT 之类的东西出现时，
all these things were like,
所有这些事情就像，
I didn't start working with them because I had a problem.
我没有开始与他们合作 ，因为我遇到了问题。
I had no problems.
我没有任何问题。
But I was very curious about technology
但我对技术很好奇
and I was like playing with it
我就像在玩它
and figuring out like...
并弄清楚像...
First just playing with it
首先只是玩玩它
and then you find something like,
然后你会发现类似的东西
okay, this generates...
好的，这会生成...
Stable Diffusion generates houses
稳定扩散生成房屋
very beautiful and interiors.
非常漂亮和内饰。
- So it's less about problem solving,
- 所以这不是解决问题的问题，
it's more about the possibilities
更多的是可能性
of new things you can create.
您可以创造的新事物。
- Yeah, but that's very risky
- 是的，但是这非常危险
because that's the famous like
因为那是著名的
solution trying to find a problem.
试图找到问题的解决方案。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And usually, it doesn't work.
- 通常情况下，这是行不通的。
And that's very common with startup funds.
这在启动基金中很常见。
I think they have tech,
我认为他们有技术，
but actually people don't need the tech, right?
但实际上人们并不需要 技术，对吧？
- Can you actually explain,
- 你能具体解释一下吗
it'd be cool to talk about some of the stuff you've created.
谈论您创建的一些 东西会很酷。
Can you explain
你能解释一下吗
the photoai.com?
photoai.com？
- Yeah, yeah, so it's like fire your photographer.
- 是的，是的，所以这就 像解雇你的摄影师。
The idea is like, you don't need a photography anymore.
这个想法就像，你 不再需要摄影了。
You can train yourself as AI model
你可以将自己训练成AI模型
and you can take as many photos
你可以拍尽可能多的照片
as you want anywhere in any clothes
随心所欲 穿着任何衣服
with facial expressions,
和面部表情，
like happy or sad,
喜欢快乐或悲伤，
or poses, all this stuff.
或姿势，所有这些东西。
- So how does it work?
- 那么它是如何运作的呢？
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- (laughs) You send me.
-（笑）你发给我。
- So you could press- - A link to a gallery
- 所以你可以按 - - 画廊链接
of ones done on me. - Yeah.
对我所做的事情。 - 是 的。
- Which is?
- 哪个是？
- So on the left you have the prompt, the box.
- 所以在左边 你有提示框。
Yeah, so you can write like,
是的，所以你可以这样写：
so model is your model, this Lex Fridman.
所以模特就是你的模特，这个莱克斯·弗里德曼。
- Yeah. - So you can write like model
- 是的。 - 所以你可以像模型一样写
as a blah, blah, blah, whatever you want.
作为废话，废话，废话，无论你想要什么。
- Yep. - Then press the button
- 是的 。 - 然后按下按钮
and it will take photos.
它会拍照。
It will take one minute.
这将需要一分钟。
- Photos, what are you using for the hosting
- 照片，你用 什么来托管
for the compute? - Replicate.
用于计算？ - 复制。
- Okay. - Replicate.com.
- 好的。 - 复制.com。
They're very, very good.
他们非常非常好。
- Okay, it's cool like this interface wise.
- 好吧，这个 界面很酷。
It's cool that you're showing how long it's gonna take.
很酷的是你展示了它 需要多长时间。
This is amazing.
这太棒了。
So I'm presuming you just loaded
所以我假设你刚刚加载
in a few pictures from the internet.
来自互联网的几张图片。
- Yeah, so I went to Google Images,
- 是的，所以我去了谷歌图片，
typed in Lex Fridman.
莱克斯·弗里德曼 (Lex Fridman) 输入。
I added like 10 or 20 images.
我添加了大约 10 或 20 张图像。
You can open 'em in the gallery,
你可以在画廊里打开它们，
and you can use your cursor to, yeah.
你可以使用光标，是的。
So some don't look like you,
所以有些人看起来不像你，
so the hit and miss rate is like,
所以命中率和未命中率是这样的
I don't know, I'd say like 50/50 or something.
我不知道，我会 说 50/50 之类的。
- But when I was watching it tweet,
- 但是当我看它的推文时，
like it's been getting better and better and better.
就像它变得越来越 好一样。
- It was very bad in the beginning.
- 一开始情况非常糟糕。
It was so bad.
太糟糕了。
But still people sign up to it, you know.
但你知道，仍然有人报名参加。
- (laughs) There's two Lex is great.
-（笑）有两个 Lex 很棒。
It is getting more and more sexual.
它变得越来越性感。
It's making me very uncomfortable.
这让我很不舒服。
- Man, but that's the problem with these models.
- 伙计，但这就是 这些模型的问题。
'cause (Lex laughs)
因为（ 莱克斯笑）
we need to talk about this,
我们需要谈谈这个
'cause the models- - I'm sure.
因为模型——我 确定。
- In Stable Diffusion.
- 处于稳定扩散状态。
- Yeah. - So the photo
- 是的。 - 所以照片
realistic models that are like fine tunes.
像微调一样的逼真模型。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- They were all trained on porn in the beginning.
- 他们一开始都接受 过色情训练。
And it was a guy called Hassan.
这是一个叫哈桑的人。
So I was trying to figure out
所以我想弄清楚
how to do photo realistic AI photos.
如何制作逼真的AI照片。
Stable Diffusion by itself is not doing that well.
稳定扩散本身效果 并不好。
The faces look all mangled. - Yep.
脸上看起来都被毁坏了。 - 是 的。
- And it doesn't have enough resolution
- 而且分辨率不够
or something to do that well.
或者做一些能做好的事情。
But I started seeing these base models,
但我开始看到这些基本模型，
these fine models and people would train on porn
这些优秀的模特和 人们会接受色情训练
and I would try them and they would be very photorealistic.
我会尝试它们，它们 会非常逼真。
They would have bodies that actually made sense
他们会有真正 有意义的身体
like body anatomy.
就像身体解剖学一样。
But if you look at the photo realistic models
但如果你看看照片 逼真的模型
that people use now,
人们现在使用的
still, there's still core of porn there,
尽管如此，那里仍然有色情的核心，
of naked people. - Yeah.
裸体的人。 - 是 的。
- So I need to prompt out the naked
- 所以我需要提示裸体
and everyone needs to do this with AI startups,
每个人都需要通过人工智能 初创公司做到这一点，
with imaging.
与成像。
You need to prompt out the naked stuff.
你需要提示出赤裸裸的东西。
You need to put a naked-
你需要放一个裸体-
- You have to keep reminding the model.
- 你要不断提醒模特。
You need to put clothes on the thing.
你需要给这个东西穿上衣服。
- Yeah, don't put naked 'cause it's very risky.
- 是的，不要裸露， 因为这非常危险。
I have Google Vision that checks-
我有 Google Vision 来检查-
- Yeah. - Every photo
- 是的。 - 每张照片
before it's shown to the user
在显示给用户之前
to like check for NSFW. - Like the nipple detector.
喜欢检查 NSFW。 - 就 像乳头探测器一样。
Oh, NSFW detector.
哦，NSFW 探测器。
- Because the journalists get very angry
- 因为记者们非常生气
if they, you know. - If you sexualized.
如果他们，你知道。 - 如果你性化了。
- There was a journalist I think,
- 我想有一位记者，
that would got angry to use this.
使用这个会生气。
And it was like, oh, it showed like a nipple,
就像，哦，它看起来 像乳头，
'cause Google Vision didn't detect it.
因为 Google Vision 没有检测到它。
So that's like these kind of problems
所以就像这类问题
you need to deal with,
你需要处理，
that's what I'm talking about.
这就是我要说的。
This is with cats.
这是和猫一起的。
But look at the cat face.
但看看猫的脸。
It's also kind of mangled.
它也有点破损。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
- I'm a little bit disturbed.
- 我有点不安。
- Can zoom in on the cat if you want.
- 如果需要，可以放大猫。
Yeah, it's a very sad cut.
是的，这是一个非常悲伤的剪辑。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
It doesn't have a nose.
它没有鼻子。
- It doesn't have a nose.
- 它没有鼻子。
Wow.
哇。
- Man, but this is the problem with AI startup
- 伙计，但这就是人工 智能启动的问题
'cause they all act like it's perfect.
因为他们都表现得很完美。
This is groundbreaking.
这是开创性的。
But it's not perfect. - Yeah.
但它并不完美。 - 是 的。
- It's like really bad half the time.
- 有一半时间真的很糟糕。
- So if I wanted to sort of update model as?
- 那么如果我想 将模型更新为？
- Yeah, so you remove this stuff
- 是的，所以你删除这些东西
and you write whatever you want,
然后你想写什么就写什么
like in Thailand or something,
比如在泰国什么的
or in Tokyo.
或在东京。
- In Tokyo? - Yeah.
- 在东京？ - 是的。
- And then-
- 进而-
- You could say like at night with neon lights,
- 你可以说就像在霓虹 灯闪烁的夜晚，
you can add more detail to make you.
你可以添加更多的细节来让你。
- I'll go in Austin.
- 我会去奥斯汀。
Do you think you'll know in Texas?
你认为你在德克萨斯州会知道吗？
- Yeah, Austin. - In Austin, Texas.
- 是的，奥斯汀。 - 在德克萨斯州奥斯汀。
- With cowboy hats. - In Texas, yeah.
- 带着牛仔帽。 - 在德克萨斯州 ，是的。
- As a cowboy.
- 作为一名牛仔。
It's gonna go towards the porn direction.
它将朝着色情方向发展。
Man, I hope not.
伙计，我希望不会。
It's the end of my career.
这是我职业生涯的结束。
(Pieter and Lex laughs)
（彼得和莱克斯笑了）
- Or the beginning, it depends.
- 或者开始，这取决于。
We can send you a push notification
我们可以向您发送推送通知
when your photos are done.
当你的照片完成后。
Yeah, all right, cool.
是的，好吧，酷。
- Yeah, let's see. - Oh, wow.
- 是的，让我们看看。 - 哦，哇。
So this whole interface you've built.
所以你已经构建了整个界面。
- Yeah. - This is really well done.
- 是的 。 - 这确实做得很好。
- It's so jQuery.
- 太 jQuery 了。
- So I still use jQuery. - Yes.
- 所以我仍然使用 jQuery。 - 是 的。
- The only one. - Still.
- 唯一的一个。 - 仍然。
- After 10 years. - To this day.
- 10年后。 - 直 到今天。
You're not the only one, the entire of the web.
您不是唯一的一个， 而是整个网络。
- Yeah. - This PHP.
- 是的。 - 这个PHP。
- PHP and jQuery.
- PHP 和 jQuery。
Yeah, SQLite.
是的，SQLite。
- You're just like one of the top performers
- 你就像表现最 好的演员之一
from a programming perspective
从编程的角度来看
that are still openly talking about it.
仍在公开谈论它。
But everyone's using PHP.
但每个人都在使用 PHP。
Most of the web is still probably PHP and jQuery.
大多数 Web 可能仍然 是 PHP 和 jQuery。
- I think 70%, 'cause of WordPress, right?
- 我认为 70% 是因为 WordPress，对吧？
'Cause the blogs are- - Yeah, that's true.
因为博客是——是 的，确实如此。
- Yeah. - That's true.
- 是的。 - 这是真的。
- I'm seeing a revival now.
- 我现在看到了复兴。
People are getting sick of frameworks.
人们已经厌倦了框架。
Like all the JavaScript frameworks are
就像所有 JavaScript 框架一样
so like, what do you call it?
就像这样，你怎么称呼它？
Like wieldy,
如同挥手般，
so it takes so much work to just maintain this code
所以维护这段代码 需要花费很多工作
and then it updates to a new version.
然后它更新到新版本。
You need to change everything.
你需要改变一切。
PHP just stays the same and works.
PHP 保持不变并且可以工作。
- Yeah, can you actually just speak to that stack?
- 是的，你真的能和 那个堆栈说话吗？
You build all your websites, apps, startups, projects,
您构建所有网站、应用程序 、初创公司、项目，
all of that with mostly vanilla HTML.
所有这些都主要是用普通的 HTML 实现的。
- [Pieter] Yeah, yeah..
- [彼得] 是啊，是啊..
- JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, and SQLite.
- JavaScript、jQuery、PHP 和 SQLite。
And so that's a really simple stack,
这是一个非常简单的堆栈，
and you get stuff- - Yeah.
然后你就得到了东西-- 是的。
- Done really fast.
- 做得真快。
Can you just speak to the philosophy behind that?
您能讲一下这背后 的哲学吗？
- I think it's accidental, 'cause that's the thing I knew,
- 我认为这是偶然的， 因为那是我所知道的，
like I knew PHP, I knew HTML, CSS,
就像我了解 PHP，我了解 HTML、CSS，
'cause you make websites
因为你制作网站
and when my startups started taking off,
当我的初创公司开始腾飞时
I didn't have time to...
我没有时间...
I remember putting on my to-do list like learn Node.js,
我记得在我的待办事项列表 中添加了学习 Node.js 之类的内容，
'cause it's important to switch,
因为转换很重要
'cause- - Yeah.
因为- - 是 的。
- This obviously is much better language than PHP,
- 这显然是比 PHP 更好的语言，
and I never learned it.
我从来没有学过。
I never did it,
我从来没有这样做过，
'cause I didn't have time.
因为我没有时间。
These things were growing like this,
这些东西就这样生长着，
and I was launching more project and I never had time.
我正在启动更多项目 ，但我一直没有时间。
It's like one day,
就好像有一天，
I'll start coding properly and I never got to it.
我将开始正确编码，但我 从未做到这一点。
- I sometimes wonder if I need to learn that stuff.
- 我有时想知道我是否 需要学习这些东西。
It's still to do for me to really learn Node.js
真正学习 Node.js 还需要做
or Flask or these kind of-
或 Flask 或此类-
- React. - Yeah, React.
- 反应。 - 是的，反应。
It feels like a responsible software engineer
感觉就像一个负责任的 软件工程师
should know how to use these,
应该知道如何使用这些，
but you can get stuff done so fast
但你可以很快完成工作
with vanilla versions of stuff.
与香草版本的东西。
- Yeah, it's like software developers if you wanna get a job
- 是的，如果你想找工作 ，就像软件开发人员一样
and it's like, you know, people making stuff like startups
就像，你知道，人们在创建 初创公司之类的东西
and if you want to be entrepreneur probably
如果你想成为 企业家
maybe shouldn't, right?
也许不应该，对吧？
- I wonder if there's like,
- 我想知道是否有类似的，
I really wanna measure performance and speed.
我真的想衡量 性能和速度。
I think there's a deep wisdom in that.
我认为这里面蕴藏着深刻的智慧。
- Yeah. - I do think that frameworks
- 是的 。 - 我确实认为框架
and just constantly wanting to learn the new thing
并且不断地想学习 新事物
that's complicated way
那是复杂的方式
of software engineering gets in the way.
软件工程的阻碍。
I'm not sure what to say about that
我不知道该说什么
because definitely like you shouldn't build everything
因为你绝对不应该 建造一切
from just vanilla JavaScript or vanilla C, for example.
例如，仅来自普通 JavaScript 或普通 C。
- Yeah. - C++
- 是的。 - C++
when you're building systems engineering is like,
当你构建系统 工程时就像，
there's a lot of benefits for a pointer safety
指针安全有 很多好处
and all that kind of stuff.
以及所有类似的东西。
So I don't know,
所以我不知道，
but it just feels like
但感觉就像
you can get so much more stuff done
你可以完成更多的事情
if you don't care about how you do it.
如果你不关心你是如何做到的。
- Man, this is my most controversial take, I think,
- 伙计，我认为这是 我最具争议性的观点，
and maybe I'm wrong,
也许我错了
but I feel like there's frameworks now that raise money.
但我觉得现在有可以 筹集资金的框架。
They raise a lot of money.
他们筹集了很多钱。
They raise 50 million, 100 million, $30 million.
他们筹集了 5000 万、1 亿、3000 万美元。
And the idea is that you need to make the developers,
这个想法是你需要 让开发人员，
the new developers,
新的开发商，
like when you're 18 or 20 years old, right?
就像你18岁或20岁的时候 一样，对吧？
Get them to use this framework and add a platform to it.
让他们使用这个框架并为 其添加一个平台。
Where the framework can...
框架可以在哪里...
It's open source,
它是开源的，
but you probably should use the platform
但你可能应该使用该平台
which is paid to use it.
使用它需要付费。
And the cost of the platforms to host it
以及托管平台的成本
are a thousand times higher than just hosting it
比仅仅托管 它高出一千倍
on a simple AWS server or a VPS on DigitalOcean, right?
在简单的 AWS 服务器或 DigitalOcean 上的 VPS 上，对吗？
So there's obviously like a monetary incentive here.
所以这里显然 有金钱激励。
We wanna get a lot of developers to use this technology
我们希望让很多开发人员 使用这项技术
and then we need to charge them money
然后我们需要向他们收费
'cause they're gonna use it in startups
因为他们会在初创公司中使用它
and then the starters can pay for the bills.
然后首发者就可以 支付账单了。
It kind of destroys the information out there
它有点破坏了 那里的信息
about learning to code because they pay YouTubers,
关于学习编码是因为 他们付钱给 YouTuber，
they pay influencers,
他们付钱给有影响力的人，
developer influencers is a big thing to like...
开发者影响者是一件很 值得喜欢的事情......
And same thing what happens with like
同样的事情也会发生在 like
nutrition and fitness or something.
营养和健身什么的。
Same thing happens in developing,
同样的事情也发生在开发中，
they pay this influencer to promote this stuff,
他们付钱给这位有影响力 的人来推广这些东西，
use it, make stuff with it, make demo products with it.
使用它，用它制作东西 ，用它制作演示产品。
And then a lot of people are like,
然后很多人就会这样，
"Wow, use this."
“哇，用这个吧。”
And I started noticing this
我开始注意到这一点
'cause when I would ship my stuff,
因为当我要运送我的东西时
people would ask me, "What are you using?"
人们会问我：“你用什么？”
I would say, "Just PHP, jQuery, why does it matter?"
我会说，“只是 PHP、jQuery， 为什么这很重要？”
And people would start kind of attacking me like,
人们会开始攻击 我，比如，
"Why are you not using this new technology,
“你为什么不使用 这项新技术，
this new framework, this new thing?"
这个新框架，这个新事物？”
And I say, "I don't know, 'cause this PHP thing works
我说，“我不知道，因为 这个 PHP 东西可以工作
and I'm optimizing for anything,
我正在针对任何事情进行优化，
it just works."
它就是有效的。”
And I never understood like why,
我从来不明白为什么，
I understand there's new technologies that are better
我知道有更 好的新技术
and there should be improvement,
并且应该有改进，
but I'm very suspicious of money.
但我对钱很怀疑。
Just like lobbying.
就像游说一样。
There's money in this developer framework scene.
这个开发者框架 场景里有钱。
There's hundreds of millions
有数亿
that goes to ads or influencer or whatever.
这将用于广告或影响者 或其他什么。
It can't all go to developers.
不能全部归开发商所有。
You don't need so many developers for a framework,
一个框架不需要 那么多开发人员，
and it's open source.
而且它是开源的。
To make a lot of more money on these startups.
在这些初创公司 身上赚更多的钱。
- So that's a really good perspective.
- 所以这是一个非常好的观点。
But in addition to that is like, when you say better,
但除此之外，当 你说更好时，
it's like, can we get some data on the better?
就像，我们可以获得 一些更好的数据吗？
(Pieter laughs)
（彼得笑）
Because I wanna know
因为我想知道
from the individual developer perspective
从个人开发者的角度来看
and then from a team of five, team of 10,
然后从五人小组，十人小组，
team of 20 developers- - Yeah.
20 名开发人员组成的团队- - 是的。
- Measure how productive they are in shipping features.
- 衡量他们在运输功能 方面的生产力。
How many bugs they create,
他们创造了多少错误，
how many security holes result.
导致多少安全漏洞。
- PHP was not good with security for a while,
- PHP 有一段时间的 安全性不太好，
but now it's good.
但现在好了。
- In theory, in theory- - Yeah.
- 理论上，理论上- - 是 的。
- Is it though? - Now it's good.
- 是吗？ - 现在 好了。
- No, now as you're saying it,
- 不，正如你所说，
I wanna know if that's true
我想知道这是不是真的
because PHP was just the majority-
因为 PHP 只是大多数 -
- Yeah. - Of websites on the internet.
- 是的 。 - 互联网上的网站。
- [Pieter] Could be true.
- [彼得] 可能是真的。
- Is it just overrepresented?
- 是否只是比例过高？
Same with WordPress? - Yeah.
与 WordPress 一样吗？ - 是 的。
- Yes, there's a reputation that WordPress
- 是的，WordPress 享有盛誉
has a gigantic number of security holes.
存在大量安全漏洞。
I don't know if that's true.
我不知道这是不是真的。
I know it gets attacked a lot because it's so popular.
我知道它受到很多攻击 ，因为它太受欢迎了。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- It definitely does have security holes,
- 它肯定有安全漏洞，
but maybe a lot of other systems
但也许还有很多其他系统
have security holes as well.
也有安全漏洞。
Anyway, I just sort of questioning
无论如何，我只是想问一下
the conventional wisdom that keeps wanting to push
一直想要推动 的传统智慧
software engineers towards frameworks, towards complex.
软件工程师走向框架 ，走向复杂。
- [Pieter] Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
- [彼得] 是啊，是啊，是啊，是啊。
- Like super complicated
- 喜欢超级复杂
sort of software engineering approaches
软件工程方法的种类
that stretch out the time
从而延长时间
it takes to actually build a thing.
实际构建一个东西需要。
- Man, 100%.
- 伙计，100%。
And it's the same thing with big corporations.
大公司也是 如此。
80% of the people don't do anything.
80%的人什么都不做。
It's like- - Right.
就好像—— 对了。
- It's not efficient.
- 这效率不高。
Your benchmark is like people building stuff
你的基准就像人们 建造东西
that actually gets done and like for society, right?
这实际上已经完成并为社会 所喜欢，对吧？
If we wanna save time,
如果我们想节省时间
we should probably use technology
我们或许应该使用科技
that's simple, that's pragmatic,
就是这么简单，就是这么实用
that works, that's not overly complicated.
有效，这并不太复杂。
It doesn't make your life like a living hell.
它不会让你的生活变得 像活生生的地狱。
- And use a framework one that obviously solves a problem,
- 并使用一个明显可以 解决问题的框架，
a direct problem that you- - Of course, yeah, of course.
一个直接的问题是你—— 当然，是的，当然。
I'm not saying you should code without a framework.
我并不是说你应该在没有 框架的情况下编码。
You should use whatever you want.
你应该使用任何你想要的东西。
Yeah, think it's suspicious.
是啊，觉得很可疑。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
And I think it's suspicious.
我认为这很可疑。
When I talk about it on the Twitter,
当我在推特上谈论这件事时，
there's this army comes out. - Yeah.
这支军队出来了。 - 是 的。
- There's these framework armies.
- 有这些框架军队。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- Man, something...
- 伙计，有什么...
My gut tells me.
我的直觉告诉我。
- I wanna ask the framework army,
- 我想问问框架军，
what have they built this week?
他们这周建造了什么？
It's the Elon question.
这是埃隆的问题。
What did you do this week?
这周你做了什么？
- Yeah, did you make money with it?
- 是啊，你赚到钱了吗？
Did you charge users?
向用户收费了吗？
Is it a real business?
这是真正的生意吗？
Yeah.
是的。
- So going back to the cowboy.
- 那么回到牛仔。
- First of all, some never look like you, right?
- 首先，有些人看起来根本 不像你，对吧？
But some do.
但有些人这样做。
- Every aspect of this is pretty incredible.
- 这一切的各个方面都 非常令人难以置信。
I'm also just looking at the interface.
我也只是看界面而已。
It's really well done.
确实做得很好。
So this is all just jQuery.
所以这只是 jQuery。
- Yeah. - This is really well done.
- 是的 。 - 这确实做得很好。
So take me through the journey of Photo AI.
那么请带我经历一下 Photo AI 的旅程。
Most of the world doesn't know much about Stable Diffusion
世界上大多数人对稳定 扩散知之甚少
or any of this- - Yeah.
或其中任何一个-- 是的。
- Any of the generative AI stuff.
- 任何生成人工智能的东西。
And so you're thinking, okay,
所以你在想，好吧，
how can I build cool stuff with this?
我怎样才能用这个构建很酷的东西？
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- So what was the origin story of Photo AI?
- 那么 Photo AI 的起源故事 是什么呢？
- I think it started, 'cause Stable Diffusion came out.
- 我认为它开始了，因为 稳定扩散出现了。
So Stable Diffusion is like this-
所以稳定扩散是这样的——
- Yeah. - The first like generative
- 是的 。 - 第一个喜欢生成
image model, AI model.
图像模型、AI模型。
And I started playing with it,
我开始玩它，
like you could install it on your Mac,
就像您可以将其安装在 Mac 上一样，
somebody forked it and made it work for MacBooks.
有人将其分叉并使 其适用于 MacBook。
So I downloaded it and cloned the Repo,
所以我下载了它并克隆了 Repo，
started using it to generate images
开始使用它来生成图像
and it was like amazing.
这真是太棒了。
I found it on Twitter
我在推特上找到的
because you see things happen on Twitter
因为你可以在 Twitter 上看到发生的事情
and I would post what I was making on Twitter as well
我也会在 Twitter 上发布 我所做的事情
and you could make any image,
你可以制作任何图像，
you could write a prompt.
你可以写一个提示。
So essentially write a prompt
所以本质上写一个提示
and then it generates a photo of that
然后它会生成一张照片
or image of that in any style.
或任何风格的图像。
They would use like artist names
他们会使用像艺术家的名字
to make like a Picasso kind of style and stuff.
做出像毕加索那样 的风格和东西。
And I was trying to see like what is it good at?
我想看看它 擅长什么？
Is it good at people?
对人好吗？
No, it's really bad at people,
不，对人真的很不好
but it was good at houses.
但它擅长做房子。
So architecture, for example,
以建筑为例，
I would generate like architecture houses.
我会生成类似建筑的房子。
So I made a website called thishousedoesnotexist.org.
所以我创建了一个名为 thishousedoesnotexist.org 的网站。
And it generated like,
它生成了，
they called it like house porn at that one.
他们称其为 家庭色情片。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
House porn is like a subreddit.
家庭色情就像一个 Reddit 子版块。
And this was Stable Diffusion like the first version.
这就是像第一个版本一样 的稳定扩散。
So it looks really...
所以看起来真的...
You can click for another photo.
您可以点击查看另一张照片。
So it generates all these kind of non-existing houses.
所以它产生了所有这些 不存在的房子。
- It is house porn.
- 这是家庭色情片。
- But it looked kind of good.
- 但看起来还不错。
Especially back then.
尤其是那时候。
- It looks really good.
- 看起来真的不错。
- Now things look much better.
- 现在情况看起来好多了。
- That's really, really well done.
- 这真的非常非常好。
Wow.
哇。
- And it also generates like a description.
- 它也像描述一样 生成。
- And you can upvote.
- 你可以投票。
Is it nice? - Yeah.
好看吗？ - 是 的。
- Upvote it.
- 点赞。 - 是
- Man, there's so much to talk to you about.
- 伙计，有很多 话要跟你说。
Like the choices here. (Pieter chuckles)
喜欢这里的选择。 （ 彼得笑了）
It's really well done. - This is very scrappy.
确实做得很好。 - 这 太斗志旺盛了。
In the bottom, there's like a ranking
最下面好像有一个排名
of the most upvoted houses.
最受欢迎的房屋之一。
So these are the top vote.
所以这些是最高票数。
And if you go to old time,
如果你回到过去，
you see quite beautiful ones.
你会看到非常漂亮的。
Yeah, so this one is my favorite.
是的，所以这是我最喜欢的。
The number one, it's kinda like a.
第一个，有点像。
- How is this not more popular?
- 这怎么不更受欢迎？
- It was really popular for like a while,
- 它确实流行了一段时间，
but then people got so bored of it, I think,
但后来人们对此感到 厌倦了，我想，
'cause I was getting bored of it too.
因为我也厌倦了。
Just continuous house porn.
只是连续的家庭色情。
Everything starts looking the same.
一切开始看起来都一样了。
But then I saw it was really good at interior,
但后来我发现它的 内饰真的很不错，
so I pivoted to interiorai.com where
所以我转向了 Interiorai.com，在那里
I tried to like upload first generate interior designs.
我尝试先上传生成室内 设计。
And then I tried to do like,
然后我尝试这样做，
there was a new technology called Image to Image
有一种新技术叫做 图像到图像
where you can input an image, like a photo,
您可以在其中输入图像 ，例如照片，
and it would kind of modify the thing.
这会改变事情。
So you see it looks almost the same as Photo AI.
所以你看它看起来和 Photo AI 几乎一样。
It's the same code essentially.
本质上是相同的代码。
- Nice.
- 好的。
- So I would upload a photo of my interior where I lived,
- 所以我会上传一张 我住的室内的照片，
and I would ask like change this into like a,
我想把它改成 这样，
I don't know, like maximalist design.
我不知道，比如极简主义设计。
And it worked and it worked really well.
它奏效了，而且效果非常好。
So I was like, okay, this is a startup,
所以我想，好吧，这是一家初创公司，
'cause obviously interior design AI,
因为显然室内设计人工智能，
and nobody's doing that yet.
但还没有人这样做。
So I launched this and I was successful
所以我推出了这个并且成功了
and made like within a week, made 10K, 20K a month,
一周内就制作完成， 一个月制作1万、2万，
and now still makes like 40K, 50K a month.
现在每个月还是4万、5万左右。
And it's been like two years.
而且已经过去两年了。
So then I was like, how can I improve this interior design?
然后我就想，我该如何 改进这个室内设计呢？
I need to start learning fine tuning.
我需要开始学习微调。
And fine tuning is where you have this existing AI model
微调就是现有人工 智能模型的所在
and you fine tune it on a specific goal you wanted to do.
然后你根据你想要实现 的特定目标对其进行微调。
So I would find really beautiful interior design,
所以我会找到非常 漂亮的室内设计，
make a gallery and train a new model
建立一个画廊并训练一个新模型
that was very good at interior design.
那是非常擅长室内设计的。
And it worked and I used that as well.
它有效，我也使用了它。
And then for fun, I uploaded photos of myself,
然后为了好玩，我 上传了自己的照片，
and here's where it happened.
这就是事情发生的地方。
And to train myself like,
并训练自己，
and this would never work obviously.
这显然是行不通的。
And it worked.
它奏效了。
And actually it started understanding me as a concept.
事实上，它开始将 我理解为一个概念。
So my face worked,
所以我的脸起作用了，
and you could do like different styles,
你可以喜欢不同的风格，
me as like very cheesy,
我很俗气，
medieval warrior, all this stuff.
中世纪的战士，所有这些东西。
So I was like, this is another startup.
所以我想，这是另一家初创公司。
So now I did avatarai.me.
所以现在我做了 avatarai.me。
I couldn't get to.com
我无法访问.com
And this was-
这是——
- This still up? - Yeah, avatarai.me.
- 还这样吗？ - 是 的，avatarai.me。
Well, now it's forwards to photo AI, 'cause it pivoted.
好吧，现在它转向了照片人工 智能，因为它发生了转变。
- Got it.
- 知道了。
- But this was more like cheesy thing.
- 但这更像是俗气的事情。
So this is very interesting 'cause this went so viral.
所以这非常有趣，因为 它非常流行。
It made like, I think 150K in a week or something.
我想一周之内就 赚了 15 万。
So most money I ever made.
所以我赚的钱最多。
And then big, this is very interesting,
然后大了，这个很有趣，
the big VC companies like Lenze,
像Lenze这样的大型风险投资公司，
which are much better at iOS and stuff than me,
他们在 iOS 方面 比我强得多，
I didn't have iOS app.
我没有 iOS 应用程序。
They quickly built an iOS app that does the same.
他们很快构建了一个具有相同 功能的 iOS 应用程序。
And they found technology,
他们发现了技术，
and it's all open technology.
而且都是开放技术。
So it's good.
所以这很好。
And I think they made like $30 million with it.
我认为他们用它赚 了大约 3000 万美元。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- They became like the top grossing app after that.
- 此后它们就成为了最 畅销的应用程序。
- How do you feel about that?
- 你对此有何感想？
- I think it's amazing, honestly.
- 说实话，我认为这太棒了。
And it's not like-
而且这并不像——
- You didn't have like a feeling like, ah, fuck.
- 你没有那种感觉 ，啊，操。
- No, I was a little bit like sad,
- 不，我有点悲伤，
'cause all my products would work out
因为我所有的产品都会成功
and I never had like real fierce competition.
我从来没有经历过 真正激烈的竞争。
And now I have fierce competition
现在我面临着激烈的竞争
from like a very skilled high talent.
来自像一个非常熟练的高人才。
I was developer studio or something that,
我是开发工作室之类的，
and they already had an app.
他们已经有了一个应用程序。
They had an app, an App Store for like,
他们有一个应用程序，一个应用程序商店，
I think retouching your face or something.
我想修饰一下你的脸什么的。
So they were very smart.
所以他们非常聪明。
They add these avatars to there.
他们将这些化身添加到那里。
It's a feature.
这是一个特点。
They had the users,
他们有用户，
they do a push notification to everybody.
他们向每个人发送推送通知。
We have this avatars.
我们有这个头像。
- Yeah. - Man, they create,
- 是的。 - 人，他们创造，
I think they made so much money.
我认为他们赚了很多钱。
I think they did a really great job.
我认为他们做得非常出色。
And I also made a lot of money with it.
我也用它赚了很多钱。
But I quickly realized it wasn't my thing,
但我很快意识到这不是我的事
'cause it was so cheesy.
因为它太俗气了。
It was like Kitch,
就像基奇一样，
it's kind of like me as a Barbie
这有点像我作为芭比娃娃
or me as a...
或者我作为...
- Yeah. - It was too cheesy.
- 是的 。 - 太俗气了。
I wanted to go for like,
我想去，
what's a real problem we can solve?
我们能解决的真正问题是什么？
'Cause this is gonna be a hype.
因为这将是一场炒作。
This is gonna be,
这将会是，
and it was a hype, these avatars.
这些化身是一种炒作。
It's like let's do real photography.
就像让我们进行真正的摄影一样。
How can you make people look really photo realistic?
如何才能让人物 看起来非常逼真？
And it was difficult.
这很困难。
And that's why these avatars work,
这就是这些化身发挥作用的原因，
'cause they were all like in a cheesy Picasso style,
因为它们都像俗气 的毕加索风格，
and art is easy 'cause you interpret...
艺术很容易，因为你可以解释......
All the problems that AI has
AI 所面临的所有问题
with your face are like artistic.
和你的脸一样有艺术感。
If you call it Picasso.
如果你称它为毕加索。
But if you make a real photo,
但如果你拍一张真实的照片
all the problems with your face,
你脸上的所有问题，
you look wrong.
你看起来错了。
So I started making Photo AI,
所以我开始制作 Photo AI，
which was like a pivot of it
就像它的一个支点
where it was like a photo studio
那里就像一个照相馆
where you could take photos without actually needing,
在那里你可以拍照而 不需要实际需要，
a photographer, needing a studio.
一个摄影师，需要一个工作室。
You just type it.
您只需输入即可。
And I've been working on it for like the last year.
去年我就一直在 研究这个问题。
- Yeah, it's really incredible.
- 是的，这确实令人难以置信。
That journey is really incredible.
那段旅程真是不可思议。
Let's go to the beginning of Photo AI though,
让我们从 Photo AI 开始吧，
'cause I remember seeing a lot of really, (laughs)
因为我记得真的 看过很多（笑）
really hilarious photos.
真的很搞笑的照片。
I think you were using yourself as a case study.
我认为您正在以自己 作为案例研究。
Right? - Yeah.
正确的？ - 是的。
- Yeah, so there's a tweet here.
- 是的，这里有一条推文。
Sold $100,000 in AI generated avatars.
人工智能生成的头像售价为 10 万美元。
- Yeah, and it's a lot like,
- 是的，这很像，
it's a lot for anybody.
这对任何人来说都意义重大。
It's a lot for me.
这对我来说意义重大。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
Making 10K a day on this, you know.
靠这个一天能赚一万，你知道的。
- That's amazing.
- 太棒了。
That's amazing.
太棒了。
- And then the nested tweet,
- 然后是嵌套的推文，
like that's the launch tweet,
就像那条发布推文一样，
and then the before that it's like the me hacking on it.
然后在那之前就像我在 黑客攻击它一样。
- Oh, I see.
- 我懂了。
So that...
以便...
Okay, so October 26th, 2022.
好的，2022 年 10 月 26 日。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- I trained an ML model on my face.
- 我在我的脸上训练了一个机器学习模型。
- Because my eyes are quite far apart.
- 因为我的眼睛距离很远。
I learned when I did YouTube,
当我做 YouTube 时我了解到，
I would put a photo of like my DJ photo, my mixture.
我会放一张像我的 DJ 照片 、我的混合物的照片。
And people would say I look like a hammerhead shark.
人们会说我看起来 像锤头鲨。
It was like the top comment.
就像置顶评论一样。
So then I realized my eyes are far apart.
然后我意识到我的眼睛距离很远。
- Yeah, the internet helps you figure out
- 是的，互联网可以帮助你弄清楚
who you look like. - Yeah,
你看起来像谁。 - 是 的，
helps realize how you look.
帮助了解您的外表。
- Boy, do I love the internet.
- 男孩，我喜欢互联网吗？
- So first trap.
- 所以第一个陷阱。
- Well what is, is this?
- 嗯，这是什么？
Wait.
等待。
- It's water from the waterfall,
- 这是瀑布的水，
but the waterfalls in the back,
但后面的瀑布，
you know, so what's going on?
你知道，那是怎么回事？
- So how much of this is real?
- 那么这其中有多少是真实的呢？
- It's all AI.
- 都是人工智能。
- Yeah.
- 都是人工智能。 - 是的。
- That's pretty good, though, for the early days.
- 不过，对于早期来 说，这已经相当不错了。
- Exactly.
- 确切地。
But this was hit or miss,
但这是偶然的，
so you had to do a lot of curation,
所以你必须做很多策划，
'cause 99% of it was really bad.
因为 99% 的情况真的很糟糕。
So these are the photos I uploaded.
这些是我上传的照片。
- How many photos did you use?
- 你用了多少张照片？
Only these, I will try more up to date picks later.
只有这些，稍后我会尝试 更多最新的选择。
These are the only photos you uploaded?
这些是您上传的唯一照片？
- Yeah, yeah. - Wow.
- 是啊是啊。 - 哇。
Wow, okay, so you were learning all this super quickly.
哇，好吧，所以你学 得非常快。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- What are some interesting details
- 有哪些有趣的细节
you remember from that time
你还记得那时
for what you had to figure out to make it work?
为了让它发挥作用，你必须 弄清楚什么？
And for people just listening,
对于那些只是倾听的人来说，
he uploaded just a handful of photos
他只上传了几张照片
that don't really have a good capture of the face.
确实没有很好地 捕捉到脸部。
And he is able to-
他能够——
- I think it's cropped,
- 我认为它被裁剪了，
it's like a cropped by the layout.
就像按布局裁剪的一样。
But they're square photos.
但它们是方形照片。
So they're 512 by 512,
所以他们是 512 x 512，
because that's Stable Diffusion.
因为那是稳定扩散。
- But nevertheless not great capture the face.
- 但仍然没有很好 地捕捉到脸部。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- It's not like a collection of several hundred photos
- 这不像是几百张 照片的集合
that are like 360 overview. - Exactly.
就像 360 度全景一样。 - 确切 地。
I would imagine that too when I started I was like,
我也能想象，当我开始 的时候，我会想，
oh, this must be like some 3D scan technology, right?
哦，这一定像某种 3D 扫描技术吧？
- Yeah. - So I think
- 是的。 -所以我认为
the cool thing with AI,
人工智能最酷的事情，
it trains the concept of you.
它训练你的概念。
So it's literally like learning,
所以这就像学习一样，
just like any AI model learns, it learns how you look.
就像任何人工智能模型的学习一样 ，它会学习你的外表。
So I did this and then I was getting DMs,
所以我这样做了，然后我收到了私信，
like Telegram messages,
就像电报消息一样，
how can I do the same thing?
我怎样才能做同样的事情？
I want these photos.
我想要这些照片。
My girlfriend wants these photos.
我女朋友想要这些照片。
So I was like, okay, this is obviously a business,
所以我想，好吧，这 显然是一门生意，
but I didn't have time to code it,
但我没有时间编写代码，
make a whole like app about it.
制作一个完整的类似应用程序。
So I made a HTML page,
所以我做了一个 HTML 页面，
registered domain name.
注册域名。
It was a Stripe payment link,
这是一个 Stripe 付款链接，
which means you have literally a link to Stripe to pay,
这意味着您确实有一个 Stripe 支付链接，
but there's no code in the back.
但后面没有代码。
So all you know is you have customers that paid money.
所以你所知道的就是 你有付款的客户。
Then I added like some a Typeform link.
然后我添加了一些 Typeform 链接。
So Typeform is a site
所以 Typeform 是一个网站
where you can create your own
您可以在其中创建自己的
input form like Google forms.
输入表单，如 Google 表单。
So they would get a email with a link to the Typeform
因此他们会收到一封电子邮件 ，其中包含 Typeform 的链接
or actually just a link after the checkout
或者实际上只是结帐后的链接
and they could upload their photos.
他们可以上传他们的照片。
So enter the email, upload the photos and I launched it,
输入电子邮件，上传照片 ，然后我启动了它，
and I was like, here first sale,
我当时想，这是第一次销售，
so it's October 2022.
现在是 2022 年 10 月。
And I think within the first 24 hours was like,
我认为在最初的 24 小时内就像，
I'm not sure it was a thousand customers or something.
我不确定是一千名顾客 还是其他什么。
But the problem was I didn't have code to automate this.
但问题是我没有代码来自动 执行此操作。
So I had to do manually.
所以我必须手动完成。
So the first few hundred,
所以前几百个，
I just literally took their photos, train them,
我只是拍了他们的 照片，训练他们，
and then I would generate the photos with the prompts,
然后我会根据提示 生成照片，
and I had this text file with the prompts,
我有这个带有提示的文本文件，
and I would do everything manually.
我会手动完成所有事情。
And this quickly became way too much.
这很快就变得太过分了。
But that's another constraint.
但这是另一个限制。
I was forced to code something up that would do that.
我被迫编写一些可以做到 这一点的代码。
And that was essentially making it
这基本上就是成功的
into a real website, right?
进入一个真正的网站，对吗？
- So at first it was the Typeform
- 所以一开始是 Typeform
and they uploaded through the Typeform.
他们通过 Typeform 上传。
- [Pieter] Stripe checkout platform, yeah.
- [Pieter] Stripe 结帐平台，是的。
- And then you were like, that image is downloaded.
- 然后你就像，那个 图像被下载了。
Did you write a script to export downloaded?
您是否编写了导出 下载的脚本？
- No, it downloaded the images myself.
- 不，它自己下载了图像。
It was a zip file, to unzipped the zip file.
这是一个zip文件 ，解压zip文件。
- Literally, and you unzipped it.
- 从字面上看，你把它解压了。
One by one. - Yes.
逐个。 - 是 的。
No, because you know, do things that don't scale.
不，因为你知道，做那些 无法扩展的事情。
Paul Graham says, right?
保罗·格雷厄姆说，对吗？
And then I would train,
然后我会训练，
and I would email them the photos,
我会把照片通过电子邮件发送给他们，
I think from my personal email say,
我想从我的个人电子邮件中可以看出，
"Here's your avatars."
“这是你的头像。”
And they liked it.
他们喜欢它。
They were like, "Wow, it's amazing."
他们惊叹道：“哇，太棒了。”
- You emailed them with your personal email.
- 您用您的个人电子邮件给 他们发了电子邮件。
- So I didn't have an email address on this-
-所以我没有电子 邮件地址-
- Yeah. - Domain.
- 是的。 - 领域。
- And this is like a hundred people.
- 这就像一百个人。
- Yeah, and then you know who signed up like,
- 是的，然后你 就知道谁报名了，
man, I cannot say it, but really famous people,
伙计，我不能说 ，但确实是名人，
like really, really billionaires,
就像真的真的亿万富翁一样，
famous tech billionaires did it.
著名的科技亿万富翁做到了。
And I was like, "Wow, this is crazy."
我当时想，“哇，这太疯狂了。”
And I was like so scared to mess them.
我很害怕弄乱他们。
So I said, "Thanks so much for using my sites."
所以我说：“非常感谢 您使用我的网站。”
And he's like, "Yeah, amazing app. Great work."
他说，“是的，很棒的 应用程序。干得好。”
So I was like, this is different than normal reaction.
所以我想，这 与正常反应不同。
- It's Bill Gates isn't, it?
- 这是比尔·盖茨，不是吗？
- Cannot say anything. (Lex laughs)
- 不能说什么。 （莱克斯 笑）
- Just like shirtless picks. - GDPR like privacy.
- 就像赤裸上身的选择一样 。 - GDPR 等隐私。
- Right, right. - European regulation.
- 对，对。 - 欧洲监管。
- Right. - Cannot share anything.
- 正确的 。 - 无法分享任何东西。
I was like, wow.
我当时想，哇。
But this shows like...
但这表明...
So you make something
所以你做了一些东西
and then if it takes off very fast,
然后如果它起飞得很快
you're like, it's validated.
你就像，它已经被验证了。
You're like, here's something that people really want.
你会说，这是人们真正 想要的东西。
But then also thought, this is a hype,
但转念一想，这是炒作，
this is gonna die down very fast,
这会很快消亡，
and it did because it's too cheesy.
这样做是因为它太俗气了。
- But you had to automate the whole thing.
- 但你必须使整个事情自动化。
How'd you automate it?
你是如何自动化它的？
So what's the AI component?
那么人工智能组件是什么？
How hard was that to figure out?
弄清楚这一点有多难？
- Okay, so that's actually in many ways the easiest thing,
- 好吧，这实际上在很多方面 都是最简单的事情，
'cause there is all these platforms already back then.
因为那时已经有所有 这些平台了。
There was platforms for fine tune, Stable Diffusion.
有微调、稳定 扩散的平台。
Now I use Replicate,
现在我使用复制，
back then I use different platforms,
那时我使用不同的平台，
which was funny 'cause that platform
这很有趣，因为那个平台
when this thing took off, I would tweet,
当这件事开始流行时，我会发推文，
'cause I tweet always like how much money
因为我总是发推特喜欢多少钱
these websites make.
这些网站使。
You call it vendor, right?
你称其为供应商，对吗？
The platform that did the GPUs,
做GPU的平台，
they increased their price for training from $3 to $20.
他们将培训价格从 3 美元 提高到 20 美元。
After they saw that I was making so much money.
他们看到我赚 了这么多钱后。
So immediately my profit is gone,
所以我的利润立刻就没了，
'cause I was selling them for $30
因为我以 30 美元的价格出售它们
and I was in a Slack with them like saying, "What is this?"
我和他们一起坐在 Slack 里，好像 在说：“这是什么？”
Can you just put it back to $3?
你能把它恢复到3美元吗？
They say, "Yeah, maybe in the future,
他们说：“是的，也许在未来，
we're looking at it right now."
我们现在正在研究它。”
I'm like, "What are you talking about?"
我说：“你在说什么？”
You just took all my money,
你刚刚拿走了我所有的钱
and they're smart.
他们很聪明。
- Well, they're not that smart
- 嗯，他们没那么聪明
because like you also have a large platform
因为像你们一样 也有一个大平台
and a lot of people respect you.
很多人尊重你。
So you can literally come out and say that.
所以你完全可以 站出来这么说。
- I think it's like kind of dirty
- 我觉得这有点脏
to cancel a company or something.
取消公司或其他东西。
I prefer just bringing my business elsewhere.
我更喜欢将我的业务 带到其他地方。
But there was no elsewhere-
但其他地方没有——
- Right. - Back then.
- 正确的 。 - 那时。
- [Lex] Right.
- [莱克斯] 对。
- So I started talking to other AI model, ML platforms.
- 所以我开始与其他人工智能 模型、机器学习平台交谈。
So Replicate was one of those platforms.
所以 Replicate 就是这些平台之一。
And I started DMing, the CEO say,
我开始私聊，首席执行官说，
"Can you please create,"
“你能创造吗？”
it's called Dream Booth,
它的名字叫“梦想摊位”
this fine tuning of yourself.
对自己的这种微调。
Can you add this to your site?
您可以将其添加到您的网站吗？
'Cause I need this, 'cause I'm being price guard.
因为我需要这个，因为 我是价格卫士。
And he said "No, because it takes too long to run.
他说：“不，因为 跑的时间太长了。
It takes half an hour to run,
跑完需要半个小时
and we don't have the GPUs for it."
而且我们没有相应的 GPU。”
I said, "Please, please, please,
我说：“拜托，拜托，拜托，
and then after a week he said,
一周后他说，
"We're doing it, we're launching this."
“我们正在做，我们正在推出这个。”
And then this company became,
然后这家公司就变成了，
it was like not very famous company.
这就像不是很有名的公司。
It became very famous with this stuff,
凭借这个东西变得非常出名
'cause suddenly everybody was like,
因为突然间每个人都像
oh, we can build similar apps like avatar apps.
哦，我们可以构建类似的应用程序 ，例如头像应用程序。
And everybody started building avatar apps
每个人都开始构建头像应用程序
and everybody started using Replicate for it.
每个人都开始使用 Replicate 来实现它。
And it was from these early DMs
这是来自这些早期的 DM
with like the CEO, like Ben Firshman.
像首席执行官一样，比如本·菲尔什曼（Ben Firshman）。
Very nice guy.
非常好的人。
And he was like, they never prized media.
他说，他们从不重视媒体。
They never treated me bad.
他们从来没有对我不好。
They always been very nice.
他们一直都很好。
It's a very cool company.
这是一家非常酷的公司。
So you can run any AI model, LLMs,
所以你可以运行任何人工智能模型、法学硕士、
you can run on here.
你可以继续往这里跑。
- And you can scale?
- 你可以扩展吗？
- Yes, they scale, yeah, yeah.
- 是的，它们会扩展，是的，是的。
And I mean you can do now,
我的意思是你现在可以做
you can click on the model and just run it already.
您可以单击模型 并运行它。
It's like super easy.
这就像超级简单。
You log in with GitHub. - That's great.
您使用 GitHub 登录。 - 那太棒了。
- And by running it on the website,
- 通过在网站上运行它，
then you can automate with the API,
然后你可以使用 API 实现自动化，
you can make a website that runs the model.
您可以制作一个运行 该模型的网站。
- Generate images, generate text, generate videos,
- 生成图像、生成文本 、生成视频、
generate music, generate speech.
产生音乐，产生语音。
- Video. - Fine tune models.
- 视频。 - 微调模型。
- They do anything, yeah.
- 他们做任何事，是的。
It's a very cool company.
这是一家非常酷的公司。
- Nice.
- 好的。
And you're like growing with them, essentially.
本质上，你就像和 他们一起成长。
They grew because of you,
他们因你而成长，
because it's like a big use case.
因为它就像一个大用例。
- Yeah, the website even looks weird now.
- 是的，这个网站现在看起来甚至很奇怪。
It started as a machine learning platform
它最初是一个机器学习平台
that was like, I didn't even understand what it did.
就像，我什至不 明白它做了什么。
It was just too ML.
这实在是太机器学习了。
You would understand 'cause you're in the ML world.
你会理解的，因为你身处 机器学习世界。
I wouldn't understand - Now it's newb friendly.
我不明白 - 现在 它对新手很友好。
- Yeah, exactly.
- 是的，完全正确。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
And I didn't know how it worked
我不知道它是如何运作的
but I knew that they could probably do this and they did it.
但我知道他们可能能做到 这一点并且他们做到了。
They built the models and now I use them for everything.
他们建立了模型，现在我用 它们来做一切事情。
And we trainedlike, I think now 36,000 models,
我们训练了，我想现在 有 36,000 个模型，
36,000 people already.
已有 36,000 人。
- But is there some tricks to fine tuning
- 但是有没有一些微调的技巧
to like the collection of photos that are provided?
喜欢所提供的 照片集吗？
- Yes. - Like how do you?
- 是的。 - 就像你怎么样？
- Yes, man, there's so many hacks.
- 是的，伙计，有这么多黑客。
- The hacks. - Yeah,
- 黑客。 - 是 的，
it's like 100 hacks to make it work.
需要 100 次 hack 才能让它发挥作用。
(Lex and Pieter laughs)
（莱克斯和彼得笑了）
- It get my secrets now. - Well, not the secrets,
- 现在它得到了我的秘密 。 - 好吧，不是秘密，
but the more like,
但更喜欢的是，
insights maybe about the human face
或许关于人脸的见解
and the human body.
和人体。
What kind of stuff get messed up a lot?
什么样的东西经常乱七八糟？
- I think people, well man, as a living,
- 我认为人们，好吧，作为一种生活，
people don't know how they look.
人们不知道自己的样子。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- They generate photos of themselves
- 他们生成自己的照片
and then they say, "Ah, it doesn't look like me."
然后他们说：“啊， 它看起来不像我。”
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- You can check the training photos.
- 您可以查看训练照片。
It does look like you. - Yeah.
它看起来确实像你。 - 是 的。
- But you don't know how you look.
- 但你不知道自己的样子。
So there's a face dysmorphia of yourself
所以你自己有一张脸畸形
that you have known idea how you look.
你知道自己的样子。
- Yeah, that's hilarious.
- 是的，这很搞笑。
I mean I've got to one of the least pleasant activities
我的意思是我要做 最不愉快的活动之一
in my existence is having to listen to my voice
我的存在就是必须 倾听我的声音
and look on my face.
看看我的脸。
So I get to like really,
所以我真的很喜欢，
really have to sort of
确实必须有点
come into terms with the reality of how I look
接受我的真实 外表
and how I sound. - Man, everybody.
以及我的声音如何 。 - 伙计，大家。
- But people often don't,
- 但人们常常不这样做，
right? - Really?
正确的？ - 真的吗？
- You have a distorted view perspective.
- 你的视角是扭曲的。
- I know that like if I would make a selfie
- 我知道就像我 会自拍一样
how I think I look that, that's nice.
我觉得我看起来就是这样，很好。
Other people think that's not nice.
其他人认为这不太好。
But then they make a photo of me,
但后来他们给我拍了一张照片
I'm like that's super ugly.
我觉得那太丑了
But then they're like, no, that's how you look.
但他们会说，不， 你就是这个样子。
And you look nice.
你看起来不错。
So how other people see you is nice.
所以别人怎么看你是很好的。
So you need to ask other people to choose your photos.
所以你需要请其他 人来选择你的照片。
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 是啊，是啊，是啊。
- You shouldn't choose them yourself
- 你不应该自己选择它们
'cause you don't know how you look.
因为你不知道自己的样子。
- Yeah, you don't know what makes you interesting,
- 是的，你不知道 什么让你变得有趣，
what makes you attractive or all this kind of stuff.
是什么让你有吸引力 或诸如此类的事情。
- Yeah, exactly. - And a lot of us,
- 是的，完全正确 。 - 我们很多人，
this is dark aspect of psychology.
这是心理学的阴暗面。
We focus on some small flaws. - Yeah.
我们关注一些小缺陷。 - 是 的。
- This is why I hate plastic surgery, for example.
- 例如，这就是我讨厌整形 手术的原因。
- Yeah. - People try to remove
- 是的 。 - 人们试图删除
the flaws when the flaws are the thing
当缺陷就是问题时的缺陷
that makes you interesting and attractive.
这让你变得有趣和有吸引力。
- I learned from the hammerhead shark eyes this,
- 我从锤头鲨的眼睛 中了解到这一点，
the stuff about you that looks ugly to you.
关于你的那些在你 看来丑陋的东西。
And it's probably what makes you,
这可能就是让你，
original makes you nice and people like it about you.
原创让你变得友善 ，人们喜欢你。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- And it's not like, oh my god.
- 这不像，天哪。
And people notice it.
人们注意到了这一点。
People notice your hammerhead eyes.
人们会注意到你的双髻鲨眼睛。
But it's like, that's me, that's my face.
但这就像，那就是我，那就是我的脸。
I love myself.
我爱自己。
And that's confidence,
这就是信心，
and confidence is attractive.
自信是有吸引力的。
- Yes. - Right?
- 是的。 - 正确的？
- Confidence is attractive.
- 自信是有吸引力的。
But yes, understanding what makes you beautiful.
但是，是的，了解 什么让你变得美丽。
It's the breaking of symmetry makes you beautiful.
对称性的破坏 让你变得美丽。
It's the breaking of the average face makes you beautiful.
打破一般脸型，让 你变得美丽。
All that.
所有这些。
- Yeah. - And obviously
- 是的 。 - 显然
different from men and women, a different age.
男女不同， 年龄不同。
It's all this kind of stuff. - Yeah, 100%.
都是这样的事情。 - 是 的，100%。
- But underneath it all the personality, all of that.
- 但在它的背后是所有的 个性，所有这些。
When the face comes alive,
当脸变得生动起来时，
that also is the thing that makes you beautiful.
这也是让你变得 美丽的原因。
- Yeah. - But anyway,
- 是的。 - 但无论如何，
you have to figure all that out with AI.
你必须用人工智能来解决这一切。
- Yeah, one thing that worked was like
- 是的，有一件事很有效，就像
people would upload full body photos themselves.
人们会自己上传 全身照片。
So I would crop the face, right?
所以我会把脸剪掉，对吗？
And then the model knew better
然后模型就知道了
that we're training mostly the face here.
我们在这里主要训练脸部。
But then I started losing resemblance of the body,
但后来我开始失去 身体的相似性，
'cause some people are skinny,
因为有的人很瘦
some people are muscular, whatever.
有些人肌肉发达，无论如何。
So you want to have that too.
所以你也想拥有它。
So now I mix full body in the training with face photos,
所以现在我把全身照片和脸部 照片混合在一起训练，
face crops, and it's all automatic.
面部作物，这一切都是自动的。
And I know that other people,
我知道其他人，
they use again AI models to detect like
他们再次使用人工智能模型来检测
what are the best photos in this training set?
这个训练集中最好 的照片是什么？
And then train on those.
然后进行这些训练。
But it's all about training data
但这全都与训练数据有关
and it's with everything in AI.
人工智能的一切都是如此。
How good your training data is,
你的训练数据有多好，
is in many ways more important than
在很多方面都比
how many steps you train for like
你训练了多少步
how many months or whatever with these GPUs.
使用这些 GPU 需要 几个月或其他什么。
The goals.
目标。
- Do you have any guidelines for people
- 您对人们有什么指导方针吗？
of how to get good data?
如何获得好的数据？
How to give good data to fine tune on?
如何提供好的数据进行微调？
- The photos should be diverse.
- 照片应该多样化。
So for example, if I only upload photos
例如，如果我只上传照片
with a brown shirt or green shirts,
搭配棕色衬衫或绿色衬衫，
the model will think that I'm training the green shirts.
模型会认为我正在 训练绿色衬衫。
So the things that are the same every photo
所以每张照片 都是一样的
are the concepts that are trained.
是训练的概念。
What you want is your face to be the concept that's trained
你想要的是你的脸成为 训练有素的概念
and everything else to be diverse, like different.
和其他一切都要多样化 ，喜欢不同。
- So diverse lighting as well, diverse everything.
- 照明也如此多样化 ，一切都多样化。
- Yeah, outside, inside.
- 是的，外面，里面。
But there's no, like, this is the problem.
但不存在，这就是问题所在。
There's no like manual for this,
没有类似的手册，
and nobody knew.
没有人知道。
We were all just...
我们都只是...
Especially two years ago,
尤其是两年前，
we're all hacking, trying to test anything.
我们都在黑客攻击 ，试图测试任何东西。
Anything you can think of.
你能想到的任何东西。
And it's frustrating.
这很令人沮丧。
It's one of the most frustrating and also fun
这是最令人沮丧但 也最有趣的事情之一
and challenging things to do because with AI,
并挑战要做的事情， 因为有了人工智能，
'cause it's a black box.
因为它是一个黑匣子。
And like Karpathy, I think says this.
就像卡帕蒂一样，我想也是这么说的。
We don't really know how this thing works,
我们真的不知道这东西是如何运作的
but it does something.
但它确实有作用。
But nobody really knows why, right?
但没有人真正知道为什么，对吧？
We cannot look into the model of an LLM,
我们无法研究LLM的模式，
like what is actually in there.
就像里面的实际情况一样。
We just know it's a 3D matrix of numbers, right?
我们只知道它是一个 3D 数字矩阵，对吧？
So it's very frustrating,
所以这是非常令人沮丧的
'cause some things you...
因为有些事你...
You think they're obvious
你认为它们是显而易见的
that they will improve things will make them worse.
他们会改善事情，但结果 却会使事情变得更糟。
And there's so many parameters you can tweak.
并且有很多参数 可以调整。
So you're testing everything to improve things.
所以你正在测试一切以 改进事情。
- I mean there's a whole field novel
- 我的意思是有一本全领域小说
of mechanistic interpretability that like studies
像研究一样的机械 解释性
that tries to figure out,
试图弄清楚，
tries to break things apart
试图打破事物
and understand how it works.
并了解它是如何工作的。
But there's also the data side
但还有数据方面
and the actual like consumer facing product side
以及实际面向 消费者的产品端
of figuring out how you get it to generate a thing
弄清楚如何让它 生成一个东西
that's beautiful or interesting or naturalistic,
那是美丽的、有趣 的或自然主义的，
all that kind of stuff. - Yeah.
诸如此类的事情。 - 是 的。
- And you're like at the forefront
- 而你就像在最前线
of figuring that out about the human face.
弄清楚人脸的这一点。
- Yeah. - And humans really care about
- 是的 。 - 人类真正关心的是
the human face. - They're very vain.
人脸。 - 他们 非常虚荣。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
- Like me, I want to look good on your podcast-
- 和我一样，我想在你的 播客上看起来不错 -
- Yeah. - For example.
- 是的 。 - 例如。
- Yeah, for sure.
- 是的，当然。
- And then one of the things I actually would love to
- 然后是我真正想 做的一件事
like rigorously use Photo AI,
比如严格使用Photo AI，
because for the thumbnails,
因为对于缩略图来说，
I take portraits of people.
我拍摄人物肖像。
I don't a shit about photography.
我对摄影一点兴趣都没有。
I basically used your approach for photography.
我基本上用你的 方法进行摄影。
I like Google.
我喜欢谷歌。
How do you take photographs? - Yeah.
你如何拍照？ - 是 的。
- Camera, lighting.
- 相机、灯光。
And also it's tough
而且也很艰难
because maybe you could speak to this also,
因为也许你也可以 谈论这个，
but with photography, no offense, Danny,
但对于摄影，无意冒犯，丹尼，
they're true artists, great photographers.
他们是真正的艺术家，伟大的摄影师。
But people take themselves way too seriously.
但人们把自己看得 太严肃了。
Think you need a whole lot of equipment.
认为您需要大量设备。
You definitely don't want one light,
你肯定不想要一盏灯，
you need like five lights.
你需要五盏灯。
- Man, I know this.
- 哥们，我知道这个。
- And you have to have like the lenses.
- 而且你必须有喜欢的镜片。
And I talked to a guy,
我和一个人聊天，
an expert of shaping the sound in a room, okay?
塑造房间声音的 专家，好吗？
Because I was thinking,
因为我在想，
I'm gonna do a podcast studio, whatever,
我要做一个播客工作室，无论如何
I should probably treat,
我可能应该治疗，
do a sound treatment on the room.
对房间进行声音处理。
And when he showed up and analyzed the room,
当他出现并 分析房间时
he thought everything I was doing was horrible.
他认为我所做的 一切都很可怕。
And then that's when I realized like, you know what?
然后我就意识 到，你知道吗？
I don't need experts in my life.
我的生活中不需要专家。
- You kick him outta the house.
- 你把他踢出家门。
- No, I didn't kick them.
- 不，我没有踢他们。
I mean, I said thank you, thank you very much.
我的意思是，我说 谢谢，非常感谢。
- Thank you.
- 谢谢。
Great tips, bye.
很棒的提示，再见。
- I just felt like there is...
- 我只是觉得有...
Focus on whatever the problems are.
专注于任何问题。
Use your own judgment, use your own instincts.
使用你自己的判断， 使用你自己的直觉。
Don't listen to other people,
别听别人胡言乱语
and only consult other people
并且只咨询其他人
when there's a specific problem.
当出现特定问题时。
And you consult them, not to offload the problem onto them,
你咨询他们，而不是 把问题推给他们，
but to gain wisdom from their perspective.
而是从他们的角度获得智慧。
Even if their perspective is ultimately
即使他们的观点最终是
one you don't agree with,
一个你不同意的，
you're gonna gain wisdom from that.
你将从中获得智慧。
I ultimately come up with like a PHP solution.
我最终想出了一个 类似 PHP 的解决方案。
PHP and jQuery solution- - PHP studio.
PHP 和 jQuery 解决方案- - PHP studio。
I have a little suitcase,
我有一个小行李箱
I use just the basic sort of consumer type of stuff.
我只使用基本的消费者 类型的东西。
One light, it's great.
一盏灯，真好。
- Yeah, and look at you,
- 是的，看看你，
you're like one of the top podcasts in the world
你就像世界上最 顶级的播客之一
and you get millions of views and it works.
你会获得数以百万计的观看 次数，而且它确实有效。
And the people that spend so much money on optimizing
还有那些花这么多 钱进行优化的人
for the best sound for the best studio,
为了给最好的录音室带来最好的声音，
they get like 300 views.
他们获得了大约 300 次观看。
So what is this about?
那么这是关于什么呢？
This is about that either you do really well
这是关于要么 你做得很好
or also that a lot of these things don't matter.
或者说很多这些 事情并不重要。
What matters is probably the content of the podcast.
重要的可能是 播客的内容。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- You get the interesting guests
- 你会遇到有趣的客人
- Focus on stuff that matters.
- 专注于重要的事情。
- Yeah, and I think that's very common.
- 是的，我认为这很常见。
They call it Gear Acquisition Syndrome.
他们称之为齿轮获取综合症。
Guests, like people in any industry do this,
客人们，就像任何 行业的人一样，
they just buy all the stuff.
他们只是买所有的东西。
There was a meme recently.
最近有一个梗。
What's the name for the guy that buys all the stuff
买所有东西的那个 人叫什么名字
before he even started doing the hobby, right?
在他开始做这个爱好 之前，对吗？
Marketing.
营销。
Marketing does that to people.
营销对人们就是这样。
They wanna buy this stuff. - Yeah.
他们想买这个东西。 - 是 的。
- But like, man,
- 但是就像，伙计，
you can make a Hollywood movie on an iPhone.
你可以用 iPhone 制作一部 好莱坞电影。
If the content is good enough,
如果内容足够好的话
and it will probably be original
它可能是原创的
because you would be using an iPhone for it.
因为你会使用 iPhone。
- That said, so the reason I brought that up
- 也就是说，这就是 我提出这个问题的原因
with photography.
与摄影。
There is wisdom from people
智慧来自于人
and one of the things I realized,
我意识到的一件事是
you probably also realized this,
你可能也意识到了这一点，
but how much power light has to convey emotion.
但光要传达情感需要 多大的力量。
Just take one light and move it around.
只需拿一盏灯并移动它即可。
See you're sitting in the darkness,
看你坐在黑暗中，
move it around your face.
将其移动到您的脸部周围。
The different positions are having
不同的职位有
a second light potentially,
潜在的第二盏灯，
you can play with how a person feels
你可以玩弄一个人的感受
just from a generic face.
只是来自一张普通的脸。
- Yeah. - It's interesting.
- 是的 。 - 很有趣。
You can make people attractive,
你可以让人们变得有吸引力，
you can make 'em ugly,
你可以让它们变得丑陋
you can make them scary,
你可以让他们害怕，
you can make them lonely.
你会让他们感到孤独。
All of this. - Yeah.
所有这一切。 - 是的。
- And so you kind of start to realize this.
- 所以你开始意识 到这一点。
And I would definitely love AI help
我肯定会喜欢人工智能的帮助
in creating great portraits of people.
创造伟大的人物肖像。
- Guest photos, yeah. - Guest photos, for example.
- 客人照片，是的 。 - 例如，客人照片。
That's a small use case.
这是一个小用例。
But for me,
但对我来说，
I suppose it's an important use case
我认为这是一个重要的用例
because I want people to look good
因为我希望人们看起来不错
but I also wanna capture who they are.
但我也想捕捉他们是谁。
Maybe my conception of who they are,
也许我对他们是谁的看法，
what makes them beautiful.
是什么让它们变得美丽。
- Yeah. - What makes their appearance
- 是的 。 - 是什么让它们出现
powerful in some ways.
在某些方面很强大。
Sometimes it's the eyes, oftentimes it's the eyes,
有时是眼睛，
but there's certain features of the face
但脸部有某些特征
can sometimes be really powerful.
有时真的很强大。
It's also kind of awkward for me to take.
这对我来说也有点尴尬。
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - Photographs.
- 是啊，是啊，是啊 。 - 照片。
So I'm not collecting enough. - Yeah.
所以我收集的还不够。 - 是 的。
- Photographs for myself to do it
- 为自己拍摄的照片
with just those photographs.
就用那些照片。
If I can load that off onto AI
如果我可以将其加载到人工智能上
and then start to play with lighting all that stuff.
然后开始玩照明所有 这些东西。
- Man, you should do,
- 伙计，你应该这样做，
and you should probably do it yourself.
你也许应该自己做。
You can use Photo AI,
您可以使用照片AI，
but it's even more fun if you do it yourself.
但如果你自己做 的话会更有趣。
So you train models,
所以你训练模型，
you can learn about like control nets.
您可以了解诸如控制网之类的知识。
Control net is where, for example,
例如，控制网是：
your photos in your podcast are usually
您播客中的照片通常是
like from the angle, right?
从角度看是这样吧？
So you can create a control net face post
这样你就可以创建一个控制网面帖子
that's always like this.
总是这样。
So every model, every photo you generate
所以你生成的每个模型、每张照片
uses this control net photos, for example.
以使用此控制网照片为例。
I think would be very fun for you to try out that something.
我想你尝试一下这个 东西会很有趣。
- Do you play with lighting at all?
- 你玩灯光吗？
Do you play with lighting, with pose with the?
你会玩灯光、摆姿势 吗？
- Man, actually, like this week
- 伙计，实际上，就像这周一样
or recently, there's some new model came out
或者最近有一些 新型号问世
that can adjust the light of any photo.
可以调整任何照片的光线。
But also AI image with Stable Diffusion.
还有具有稳定扩散的 AI 图像。
I think it's called Relight.
我想这就是所谓的“重新点燃”。
And it's amazing.
这太棒了。
You can upload kinda like a light map.
您可以上传类似光照图的内容。
So for example, red, purple, blue,
例如，红色、紫色、蓝色、
and use the light map
并使用光照图
to change the light on the photo you input.
更改您输入的照片 上的光线。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
So there's for sure a lot of stuff you can do.
因此，您肯定可以 做很多事情。
- What's your advice for people in general on how to learn
- 对于一般人如何学习 ，您有什么建议
all this state-of-the-art AI tools available?
所有这些最先进的人工智能 工具都可用吗？
You mentioned the new models coming out all the time.
您提到了不断推出 的新型号。
- Yeah. - How do you pay attention?
- 是的。 - 你如何集中注意力？
How do you stay on top of everything?
你如何掌控一切？
- I think you need to join Twitter X.
- 我认为你需要加入 Twitter X。
X is amazing now and the whole AI industry is on X,
X现在很厉害，整个 AI行业都在X上，
and they're all like anime avatars.
而且他们都像动漫头像。
So (chuckles) it's funny,
所以（笑）这很有趣，
'cause my friends ask me this.
因为我的朋友问我这个。
Who should I follow to stay up to date?
我应该关注谁以了解最新动态？
And I say go to X,
我说去X，
and follow all the AI anime models
并关注所有AI动漫模特
that this person is following or follows.
此人正在关注或关注。
And I send them something URL,
我向他们发送一些网址，
and they all start laughing like, what is this?
他们都开始大笑， 这是什么？
But they're real like people hacking around in AI.
但他们就像人工智能 中的人们一样真实存在。
They get hired by big companies and they're on X,
他们被大公司 聘用并且在X上，
and most of 'em are anonymous.
他们中的大多数都是匿名的。
It's very funny.
这很有趣。
They use anime avatar, I don't,
他们用动漫头像，我不用
but those people hack around
但那些人乱搞
and then they publish what they're discovering.
然后他们公布 他们的发现。
They talk about papers, for example.
例如，他们谈论论文。
So yeah, definitely X.
所以是的，绝对是X。
- It's great.
- 这很棒。
I almost exclusively all the people I follow are AI people.
我关注的人几乎都 是人工智能人士。
- Yeah, it's a good time now.
- 是的，现在正是好时机。
- Well, but also just brings happiness to my soul,
- 嗯，但也给我 的灵魂带来快乐，
'cause there's so much turmoil on Twitter.
因为推特上有太多的骚乱。
- Yeah, politics and stuff.
- 是的，政治之类的。
- There's battles going on.
- 战斗正在进行中。
It's like a war zone,
这里就像战区一样
and it's nice to just go into this happy place
很高兴能进入这个 快乐的地方
to where people are building stuff.
人们正在建造东西的地方。
- Yeah, 100%.
- 是的，100%。
I like Twitter for that most like building stuff,
我喜欢 Twitter，因为 它最喜欢构建东西，
like seeing other.
喜欢看其他的。
'Cause it inspires you to build
因为它激励你去建造
and it's just fun to see other people share
看到其他人 分享很有趣
what they're discovering and then you're like,
他们发现了什么 然后你就像
okay, I'm gonna make something too.
好吧，我也要做点什么。
It's just super fun.
这真是太有趣了。
And so if you wanna start going X
所以如果你想开始X
and then I would go to Replicate,
然后我会去复制，
and start trying to play with models.
并开始尝试玩模型。
And when you have something that kind of,
当你有这样的东西时，
you manually enter stuff,
你手动输入东西，
you set the parameters,
你设置参数，
something that works,
有效的东西，
you can make an app out of it or a website.
您可以用它制作一个 应用程序或一个网站。
- Can you speak a little bit more to the process
- 你能多谈谈 这个过程吗
of it becoming better and better and better Photo AI.
照片人工智能变得 越来越好。
- So I had this Photo AI,
- 所以我有了这个照片人工智能，
and a lot of people using it.
并且很多人都在使用它。
There was like a million
大约有一百万
or more photos a month being generated.
每月生成或更多照片。
And I discovered I was testing
我发现我正在测试
parameters like increase the step count
增加步数等参数
of generating a photo or chasing the sampler,
生成照片或追逐 采样器，
like a scheduler.
就像一个调度程序。
You have DPM++2 Karras
您有 DPM++2 卡拉斯
all these things I don't know anything about,
所有这些事情 我一无所知
but I know that you can choose them and you generate image
但我知道你可以选择 它们并生成图像
and they have different resulting images.
他们有不同的结果图像。
But I didn't know which one were better.
但我不知道哪一个更好。
So I would do it myself, test it.
所以我会自己做，测试一下。
But then I was like, why dot I test on these users?
但后来我想，为什么我要 对这些用户进行测试？
'Cause I have a million photos generated anyway.
因为无论如何我已经生成 了一百万张照片。
So unlike 10% of the users,
所以与 10% 的用户不同，
I would randomly test parameters,
我会随机测试参数，
and then I would see if they would,
然后我会看看他们是否愿意，
'cause you can favor the photo or you can download it.
因为您可以喜欢这张 照片，也可以下载它。
I would measure if they favorite or like the photo.
我会衡量他们是否喜欢 或喜欢这张照片。
And then I would AB test,
然后我会进行AB测试，
and you test for significance and stuff,
然后你测试重要性和东西，
which parameters were were better and which were worse?
哪些参数更好， 哪些参数更差？
- So you start starting to figure out
- 所以你开始开始弄清楚
which models are actually working well.
哪些模型实际上运行良好。
- Exactly, and then if it's significant enough data,
- 确实如此，如果数据 足够重要，
you switch to that for the whole, you know, all the users.
您可以为所有用户 切换到该模式。
And so that was like the breakthrough to make it better.
这就像是让它变得 更好的突破。
Just use the users to improve themselves.
只是利用用户来提高自己。
And I tell them when they sign up, we do sampling,
我告诉他们，当他们注册 时，我们会进行抽样，
we do testing on your photos of random parameters,
我们对您的照片 进行随机参数测试，
and that worked really well.
效果非常好。
I don't do a lot of testing anymore
我不再做很多测试
because it's like, I kind of reached
因为这就像，我达到了
a diminishing point where it's like,
一个递减点，就像
it's kind of good,
这有点好，
but there was a breakthrough, yeah.
但有一个突破，是的。
- So it's really about the parameters,
- 所以这实际上与参数有关，
the models that choose and letting the users
选择并让用户 选择的模型
help do the search in the space of models
帮助在模型空间中进行搜索
and parameters for you. - Yeah, yeah.
和参数给你。 - 是 啊是啊。
But actually, so like Stable Diffusion,
但实际上，就像稳定扩散一样，
I used 1.52, 2.0 came out
我用的是1.52，2.0出来了
as Stable Diffusion Excel came out,
随着稳定扩散 Excel 的出现，
all these new versions and they're all worse.
所有这些新版本 都变得更糟。
And so the core scene of people are still using 1.5
所以核心场景 人们还在用1.5
because it's also not like, what do you call neutered?
因为它也不像，你所 说的绝育是什么？
They neutered to make it super like,
他们绝育使其超级像，
with safety features and stuff.
具有安全功能和东西。
- Yeah. - So most of the people
- 是的 。 - 所以大多数人
are still on Stable Diffusion 1.5
仍处于稳定扩散 1.5
and meanwhile Stable Diffusion,
同时稳定扩散，
the company went like, the CEO left.
公司的情况就像是，首席执行官离开了。
A lot of drama happened. - Yeah.
发生了很多戏剧性的事情。 - 是的。
- Because they couldn't make money,
- 因为他们赚不到钱，
and yeah, so it's very interesting,
是的，这很有趣，
they gave us this open source model that everybody uses.
他们给了我们这个每个人 都使用的开源模型。
They raised like hundreds of millions of dollars.
他们筹集了数亿 美元。
They didn't make any money,
他们没有赚到钱，
there are not a lot.
数量不多。
And they did amazing job.
他们做得非常出色。
And now everybody uses open source model for free.
现在每个人都免费 使用开源模型。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
- You're not even using the latest one, you're saying?
- 你是说你甚至没有 使用最新的版本？
- No, and the strange thing is
- 不，奇怪的是
that this company raised hundreds of millions,
这家公司筹集了 数亿美元，
but the people that are benefiting from it are really small.
但从中受益的人实在 是太少了。
People like me who make these small apps
像我这样制作这些小应用程序的人
that are using the model.
正在使用该模型。
And now they're starting to charge money for the new models.
现在他们开始 对新型号收费。
But the new models are not so good for people.
但新模型对人们 来说不太好。
They're not sell open source, right?
他们不出售开源，对吧？
- Yeah, it is interesting because open source
- 是的，这很有趣 ，因为开源
is so impactful in the AI space,
在人工智能领域如此有影响力，
but you wonder like what is the business model behind that?
但你想知道这背后 的商业模式是什么？
But it's enabling this whole ecosystem of companies that-
但它使整个公司生态 系统成为可能——
- [Pieter] Yeah, yeah.
- [彼得] 是的，是的。
- They're using the open source models.
- 他们正在使用开源模型。
- So it's kinda like this frameworks,
- 所以它有点像这个框架，
but then they didn't bribe enough influence to use it,
但后来他们没有贿赂足够 的影响力来使用它，
and they didn't charge money for the platform.
而且他们不向 平台收费。
- Okay, so back to your book and the ideas.
- 好吧，回到你的 书和想法。
We didn't even get to the first step.
我们甚至还没有迈出第一步。
Generating ideas, so you had notebook,
产生想法，所以你有笔记本，
and you're filling it up.
你正在把它填满。
How do you know when an idea is a good one?
你怎么知道一个想法 是个好想法？
You have this just flood of ideas.
你的想法如潮水般涌来。
How do you pick the one that you actually try to build?
您如何选择您真正尝试 构建的一个？
- Man, mostly you don't know.
- 伙计，大多数时候你不知道。
Mostly, I choose the ones
大多数情况下，我选择那些
that are most viable for me to build.
这对我来说是最可行的。
I cannot build a space company now, right?
我现在不能建立一家太空公司，对吗？
It would be quite challenging.
这将是相当具有挑战性的。
But I can build something.
但我可以建造一些东西。
- Did you actually write down like space company?
- 你真的写得像太空 公司一样吗？
- No, I think asteroid mining would be very cool.
- 不，我认为小行星 采矿会非常酷。
'Cause like you go to an asteroid,
因为就像你去了小行星一样
you take some stuff from there, you bring it back,
你从那里拿走一些东西 ，然后把它带回来，
you sell it, you know.
你卖掉它，你知道。
But then you need to do...
但接下来你需要做...
And you can hire someone to launch the thing.
你可以雇人来启动 这个东西。
So all you need is like the robot that goes to the asteroid,
所以你所需要的只是像 去小行星的机器人一样，
and the robotic is interesting.
机器人很有趣。
I wanna also learn robotics.
我也想学机器人
So maybe that could be.
所以也许可能是这样。
- I think both the asteroid mining
- 我认为小行星采矿
and the robotics is- - Yeah.
机器人技术是——是 的。
- Together.
- 一起。
- I feel like.
- 我觉得。
- No, exactly, this is it.
- 不，确切地说，就是这个。
- It says- - We do this
- 它说- - 我们 这样做
not because it's easy,
不是因为它容易，
but because we thought it would be easy.
但因为我们认为这很容易。
Exactly- - Asteroid mining.
正是—— 小行星采矿。
- That's me with asteroid mining.
- 这就是我的小行星采矿工作。
Exactly. (Lex laughs)
确切地。 （ 莱克斯笑）
That's why I should do this.
这就是为什么我应该这样做。
- It's not nomadlist.com. (laughs)
- 这不是 nomadlist.com。 （笑）
- No, it's not. - It's asteroid mining.
- 不，不是。 - 这是小行星采矿。
You have to like build stuff.
你必须喜欢建造东西。
Gravity is really hard to overcome.
重力确实很难克服。
- Yeah, but it seems...
- 是的，但似乎...
Man, I sound like idiots, probably not.
伙计，我听起来像白痴，可能不是。
But it sounds quite approachable,
不过听起来很平易近人，
relatively approachable.
比较平易近人。
You don't have to build a rocket issue.
你不必建造火箭问题。
- Oh, you use something like SpaceX to get out the space.
- 哦，你可以使用像 SpaceX 这样 的东西来离开太空。
- Yeah, you hire SpaceX to send your, you know,
- 是的，你雇佣 SpaceX 来 发送你的，你知道，
this dog robot or whatever.
这个狗机器人或者别的什么。
- So is there actually existing notebook
- 那么实际存在笔记本吗
where you wrote down asteroid mining?
你在哪里写下了小行星采矿？
- No, back then I used Trello.
- 不，当时我用的是 Trello。
- Trello. - Yeah.
- 特雷洛。 - 是的。
But now I don't really, I used Telegram.
但现在我真的不知道了，我用的是 Telegram。
I rather than like saved messages
我不喜欢保存的消息
and I have like idea, I write it down.
我有类似的想法，我把它写下来。
- You type to yourself on Telegram?
- 你在 Telegram 上给自己打字吗？
- 'Cause you use WhatsApp, right?
- 因为你使用 WhatsApp，对吧？
I think, so you have messages to yourself,
我想，所以你有给自己的信息，
thing also, yeah, it's like a notepad.
还有，是的，它就像一个记事本。
- So you're talking to yourself on Telegram.
- 所以你是在 Telegram 上自言自语。
- Yeah, you use like a Notepad, to not forget stuff.
- 是的，你像记事本一样 使用，以免忘记东西。
And then I pin it.
然后我把它钉住。
- I love how like you're not using
- 我喜欢你不使用的样子
super complicated systems or whatever.
超级复杂的系统或其他什么。
People use Obsidian now.
人们现在使用黑曜石。
There's a lot of these-
有很多这样的——
- A notion where you have systems for note taking.
- 拥有记笔记系统 的概念。
Your notepad, your notepad.exe guy.
你的记事本，你的 notepad.exe 家伙。
If you're those user- - Yeah.
如果你是那些用户 - - 是 的。
Man, I saw some YouTubers doing this.
伙计，我看到一些 YouTuber 这样做了。
There's a lot of these productivity gurus also.
还有很多这样的 生产力专家。
And they do this whole iPad with a pencil.
他们用铅笔完成整个 iPad 的制作。
And then I also had an iPad and I also got the pencil
然后我也有了 iPad 和铅笔
and I got this app where you can like draw on paper.
我有这个应用程序， 你可以在纸上画画。
Like a calendar. - Yeah.
就像日历一样。 - 是的。
- People's students uses and you do coloring and stuff.
- 人们的学生使用而你做 着色和其他东西。
And I'm like, dude, I did this for a week.
我想，伙计，我这样做了一个星期。
And then I'm like, what am I doing in my life?
然后我就想，我这 一生在做什么？
I could just write it as a message to myself
我可以把它写成 给自己的信息
and it's good enough.
这已经足够好了。
- Speaking of ideas, you shared a tweet explaining
- 说到想法，你分享 了一条推文解释
why the first idea sometimes might be a brilliant idea.
为什么第一个想法有时可能 是一个绝妙的想法。
The reason for this you think is the first idea submerges
你认为的原因是第一 个想法被淹没了
from your subconscious,
从你的潜意识里，
and was actually boiling your brain for weeks, months,
实际上让你的大脑 沸腾了数周、数月，
sometimes years in the background.
有时在后台多年。
The eight hours of thinking can never compete
八个小时的思考 永远无法竞争
with a perpetual subconscious background job.
具有永久的 潜意识后台工作。
So this is the idea that if you think about an idea
所以这就是如果 你考虑一个想法
for eight hours versus like the first idea
八个小时与第一个想法相比
that pops into your mind.
这会突然出现在你的脑海中。
- Yeah. - And sometimes
- 是的 。 - 有时
there is subconscious,
有潜意识，
like stuff that you've been thinking about for many years.
就像你多年来一直在 思考的事情一样。
That's really interesting.
这真的很有趣。
- Yeah, I mean like emerges.
- 是的，我的意思是出现了。
I wrote it wrong because I'm not native English,
我写错了，因为我 不是英语母语
but it emerges from your subconscious, right?
但它是从你的潜意识中 出现的，对吗？
It comes from the like a water,
它来自于水，
your subconscious in here, it's boiling,
你的潜意识在这里沸腾，
and then when it's ready it's like ding.
然后当它准备好时，就像“叮”一样。
It's like a microwave comes out
就像微波炉出来了一样
and there you have your idea.
你就有了自己的想法。
- You think you have ideas like that?
- 你认为你有这样的想法吗？
- Yeah, all the time, 100%.
- 是的，一直都是，100%。
- It's just stuff that's been like there.
- 这只是那里的事情。
- Yes. - Yeah.
- 是的。
- And also, it comes up and I bring it,
- 而且，它出现了，我带来了它，
I send it back,
我寄回去，
like send it back to the kitchen-
就像把它送回厨房-
- Not ready yet. - To boil more.
- 还没准备好。 - 煮更多。
- Yeah. - And it's like
- 是的 。 - 这就像
a soup of ideas that's cooking.
正在煮的一锅创意汤。
It's 100%.
是100%。
This is how my brain works,
这就是我的大脑的运作方式
and I think most people.
我认为大多数人。
- But it's also about the timing.
- 但这也与时机有关。
Sometimes you have to send it back,
有时还得寄回去
not just because you're not ready,
不仅仅是因为你还没有准备好
but the world is not ready.
但世界还没有准备好。
- Yeah, so many times,
- 是啊，很多次了，
startup founders are too early with their idea.
初创公司创始人的想法 还为时过早。
Yeah, 100%.
是的，100%。
- Robotics is an interesting one for that
- 机器人技术是一个有趣的领域
because like there's been a lot
因为就像有很多
of robotics companies that failed.
失败的机器人公司。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Because it's been very difficult to build,
- 因为建造起来 非常困难，
a robotics company, make money,
一家机器人公司，赚钱，
'cause there's the manufacturing,
因为那里有制造业，
like the cost of everything.
就像一切的成本一样。
The intelligence of the robot is enough,
机器人的智能就够了，
is not sufficient to create
不足以创造
a compelling enough product from
足够引人注目的产品
which to make money.
哪个赚钱。
So there's this long line of robotics companies
所以有这么长的 机器人公司
that have tried, they had big dreams and they failed.
他们曾经尝试过，他们有远 大的梦想，但他们失败了。
- Yeah, like Boston Dynamics.
- 是的，就像波士顿动力公司一样。
I still don't know what they're doing,
我还是不知道他们在做什么
but they always upload YouTube videos,
但他们总是上传 YouTube 视频，
and it's amazing.
这太棒了。
But I feel like a lot of these companies don't have a,
但我觉得很多这样 的公司都没有，
it's like a solution looking for a problem for now.
这就像现在寻找问题 的解决方案。
Military obviously use this,
军方显然用这个，
do I need like a robotic dog now for my house?
我的房子现在需要 一只机器狗吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
It's fun, but it doesn't really solve anything yet.
这很有趣，但还没有 真正解决任何问题。
I feel the same kinda VR, like it's really cool.
我也有类似 VR 的感觉 ，感觉真的很酷。
Apple Vision Pro is very cool.
Apple Vision Pro 非常酷。
It doesn't really solve something for me yet.
它还没有真正为 我解决问题。
And that's kind of the tech looking for a solution, right?
这就是寻找解决方案 的技术，对吗？
But one day, will.
但有一天，会的。
- When the personal computer,
- 当个人电脑时，
when the Mac came along,
当 Mac 出现时，
there's a big switch that happened.
发生了一个大转变。
It somehow captivated everybody's imagination
它以某种方式吸引 了每个人的想象力
and like the application, the killer apps
和应用程序一样，杀手级应用程序
became apparent, you can type in a computer.
显而易见，你可以 在电脑上打字。
- But take became apparent like immediately.
- 但采取立即 变得明显。
Back then they also had like this thing where like,
那时候他们也 有这样的事情，
we don't need these computers.
我们不需要这些计算机。
They're like a hype.
他们就像一场炒作。
And it also went like in kinda like waves.
它也像波浪一样。
- Yeah, yeah, but the hype is the thing
- 是的，是的，但炒作才是重点
that allowed the thing to proliferate sufficiently
这使得该物质能够 充分增殖
to where people's minds would start
人们的思想开始的地方
opening up to it a little bit.
稍微开放一点。
- Yeah. - The possibility of it.
- 是的 。 - 它的可能性。
Right now, for example, with the robotics,
现在，例如，随着机器人技术的发展，
there's very few robots in the homes of people.
人们家里很少 有机器人。
- Exactly, yeah.
- 没错，是的。
- The robots that are Roombas,
- Roombas 机器人，
so the vacuum cleaners or they're Amazon Alexa.
所以真空吸尘器或者是 亚马逊 Alexa。
- Yeah, or dishwasher.
- 是的，或者洗碗机。
I mean it's essentially a robot.
我的意思是它本质上是一个机器人。
- Yes, but the intelligence is very limited.
- 是的，但是智力非常 有限。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- I guess is one way we can summarize all of them.
- 我想这是我们总结所有 这些的一种方式。
Except Alexa, which is pretty intelligent,
除了 Alexa 非常聪明之外，
but is limited with the kind of ways it interacts with you.
但受限于它与你 互动的方式。
That's just one example. - Yeah.
这只是一个例子。 - 是 的。
- I sometimes think about that as like,
- 我有时会想，
if some people in this world were
如果这个世界上有一些人
kind of born in the whole existence is like
那种诞生于 整个存在就像
they were meant to build the thing.
他们的目的是建造这个东西。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- I think I sometimes wonder like what I was meant to do.
- 我想我有时会想知道 我应该做什么。
Because you have these plans for your life,
因为你对自己的人生 有这些计划，
you have these dreams.
你有这些梦想。
- I think you're meant to build robots.
- 我认为你应该建造机器人。
- Okay, me personally.
- 好吧，就我个人而言。
(Pieter and Lex laughs)
（彼得和莱克斯笑了）
Maybe, maybe.
也许，也许。
That's a sense of habit,
这就是一种习惯，
but it could be other things.
但也可能是其他事情。
It could hilariously not be the thing
这可能不是问题
I was meant to be is to talk to people.
我的本意就是与人交谈。
- Yeah. - Which is weird,
- 是的。 - 这很奇怪，
because I always was anxious about talking to people.
因为我总是对与人交谈 感到焦虑。
It's like a- - Really?
这就像——真的 吗？
- Yeah, I'm scared of this.
- 是的，我很害怕这个。
I was scared is (laughs) yeah, exactly.
我很害怕（笑）是的，正是如此。
- I'm scared of you as well.
- 我也害怕你。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
- It's just anxiety throughout,
- 整个过程都是焦虑，
social interaction in general.
一般的社交互动。
I'm an introvert that hides from the world, so yeah.
我是一个内向的人，逃避 世界，所以是的。
It's really strange.
真的很奇怪。
- Yeah, but that's also kinda life.
- 是的，但这也是一种生活。
Life brings you to,
生活带你去，
it's very hard to super intently kind of choose
很难做出超级 专注的选择
what you're gonna do with your life.
你将如何度过你的一生。
It's more like surfing.
这更像是冲浪。
You're surfing the waves.
你正在冲浪。
You go in the ocean,
你走进大海，
you see where you end up.
你会看到你最终的结果。
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是啊是啊。
And there's universe has a kind of sense of humor.
宇宙有一种 幽默感。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- I guess you have to just,
- 我想你必须只是，
yeah, allow yourself to be carried away by the ways.
是的，让自己 随波逐流。
Yeah. - Exactly, yeah, yeah.
是的。 - 没错，是的，是的。
- Have you felt that way in your life?
- 你在生活中有过这样的感觉吗？
- Yeah, all the time.
- 是的，一直都是。
Yeah, I think that's the best way to live your life.
是的，我认为这是 最好的生活方式。
- So allow whatever to happen.
- 所以，无论发生什么，都要允许。
Do you know what you're doing in the next few years?
你知道未来几年 你要做什么吗？
Is it possible that it'll be completely,
有没有可能彻底，
like changed? - Possibly.
喜欢改变吗？ - 可能。
I think relationships,
我认为人际关系，
you wanna hold relationships, right?
你想维持人际关系，对吧？
You wanna hold your girlfriend,
你想抱住你的女朋友
you wanna become wife and all this stuff.
你想成为妻子以及所有这些东西。
I think you should stay open to where,
我认为你应该对哪里保持开放态度
like for example, where you wanna live.
例如，您想住在哪里。
I don't know,
我不知道，
we don't know where we wanna live, for example.
例如，我们不知道 我们想住在哪里。
That's something that will figure itself out.
这是会自行解决 的事情。
It will crystallize where
会在哪里结晶
you will get sent by the waves to somewhere
你会被海浪送到 某个地方
where you only live, for example, what you're gonna do.
你住的地方，例如 你要做什么。
I think that's a really good way to live your life.
我认为这是一种非常 好的生活方式。
I think most stress comes from trying to control,
我认为大部分压力 来自于试图控制
like hold things...
比如拿东西...
It's kind of Buddhist.
这有点佛系。
You need to like lose control, let it loose.
你需要喜欢失去控制 ，让它放松。
And things will happen.
事情将会发生。
When you do mushrooms, when you do drugs,
当你做蘑菇的时候，当你做毒品的时候，
like psychedelic drugs.
就像迷幻药一样。
The people that start,
那些开始的人，
that are like control freaks get bad trips, right?
就像控制狂会遭遇糟糕 的旅行一样，对吧？
'Cause you need to let go.
因为你需要放手。
I'm pretty control freak actually.
其实我是个控制狂。
When I did mushrooms when I was 17,
当我17岁的时候做蘑菇的时候
it was very good.
非常好。
And then at the end it wasn't so good,
然后到最后效果就不太好了
'cause I tried to control it was like,
因为我试图控制它就像
ah, now it's going too much.
啊，现在太过分了。
Let's stop.
我们停下来吧。
Bro, you can't stop it.
兄弟，你阻止不了。
You need to go through with it.
你需要经历它。
And I think it's a good metaphor for life.
我认为这是对生活的一个很好的比喻。
I think that's very tranquil way to lead your life.
我认为这是一种非常平静 的生活方式。
- Yeah, actually when I took Ayahuasca,
- 是的，实际上当我服用死藤水时，
that lesson is deeply within me already
这个教训已经深深地铭刻在我心中
that you can't control anything.
你无法控制任何事情。
- [Pieter] Yes.
- [彼得] 是的。
- I think I probably learned that the most in jiu-jitsu.
- 我想我在柔术中学到的 最多的可能是这一点。
So just let go and relax. - Yeah.
所以就放手放松吧。 - 是 的。
- And that's why I had just an incredible experience.
- 这就是为什么我有一次令 人难以置信的经历。
There's like literally no negative aspect
几乎没有负面影响
of my Ayahuasca experience
我的死藤水体验
or any psychedelics I've ever had.
或者我曾经吃过的任何迷幻药。
Some of that could be with my biology
其中一些可能与我的生物学有关
and my genetics, whatever.
还有我的基因，无论如何。
But some of it was just not trying to control.
但其中一些只是没有 试图控制。
- Yeah. - Just surf the wave.
- 是的 。 - 只是冲浪。
- For sure.
- 一定。
I think most stress in life comes from trying to control.
我认为生活中的大部分压力 都来自于试图控制。
- So once you have the idea- - Yeah.
- 所以一旦你有了想法- - 是 的。
- Step two, build.
- 第二步，构建。
How do you think about building
您如何看待建设
the thing once you have the idea?
一旦你有了这个想法？
- I think you should build
- 我认为你应该建造
with the technology that you know.
使用您所知道的技术。
So for example, Nomad List,
例如，Nomad List，
which is like this website I made
就像我做的这个网站
to figure out the best cities to live
找出最适宜居住的城市
and work as digital nomad.
并以数字游牧者的身份工作。
It wasn't a website,
这不是一个网站，
it launched as a Google spreadsheets.
它以谷歌电子表格的形式推出。
So it was a public Google spreadsheet.
所以这是一个公共的谷歌电子表格。
Anybody could edit.
任何人都可以编辑。
And I was like, I'm collecting cities
我当时想，我正在收集城市
where we can live with as nomads,
在那里我们可以像游牧民族一样生活，
with the internet speeds,
随着互联网的速度，
the cost of living, other stuff.
生活费，其他东西。
And I tweeted it,
我发推文说，
and back then I didn't have a lot of followers.
那时我没有很多 追随者。
I had like a few thousand followers or something.
我有大约几千名追随者 之类的。
And I went like viral for my skill viral back then,
那时我因为我的技能 而迅速走红，
you know, which was like five retweets.
你知道，这相当于五次转发。
And a lot of people started editing it.
很多人开始编辑它。
And there was like hundreds of cities in this list,
这份名单里大约有 数百个城市，
from all over the world with all the data.
来自世界各地的所有数据。
It was very crowdsourced.
这是非常众包的。
And then I made that into a website.
然后我把它做成了一个网站。
So figuring out like what technology
所以弄清楚像什么技术
you can use that you already know.
你可以使用你已经知道的。
So if you cannot code, you can use a spreadsheet.
因此，如果您不会编码 ，您可以使用电子表格。
If you cannot use a spreadsheet, like whatever,
如果你不能使用电子 表格之类的东西，
you can always use a, for example,
例如，您始终可以使用
a website generator like Wix
像 Wix 这样的网站生成器
or something or Squarespace, right?
或者什么或者 Squarespace，对吧？
You don't need to code to build a startup.
您不需要编写代码来建立一家初创公司。
All you need is idea for a product.
您所需要的只是产品的创意。
Build something like a landing page or something.
构建一些诸如登陆 页面之类的东西。
Put a Stripe button on there and then make it.
在那里放一个条纹按钮 ，然后就可以了。
And if you can code,
如果你会编码，
use the language that you already know
使用你已经知道的语言
and start coding with that
并开始编码
and see how far you can get.
看看你能走多远。
You can always rewrite the code later.
您以后随时可以重写代码。
The tech stack is not actually,
技术栈实际上并不是，
it's not the most important of a business
这不是企业最重要的
when you're starting on a business.
当你开始创业时。
The important thing is that you validate
重要的是你要验证
that there's a market,
说有市场，
that there's a product that people wanna pay for.
人们愿意为某 种产品付费。
So use whatever you can use.
因此，使用任何可以利用的东西。
And if you cannot code,
如果你不会编码，
use spreadsheets, landing page generators, whatever.
使用电子表格、登陆 页面生成器等等。
- Yeah, and the crowdsourcing element is fascinating.
- 是的，众包元素 很有趣。
It's cool, it's cool when a lot of people start using it.
很酷，当很多人开始 使用它时就很酷。
You get to learn so fast. - Yeah.
你学得很快。 - 是 的。
- I've actually did the spreadsheet thing.
- 我实际上已经做了电子表格的事情。
You share a spreadsheet publicly
您公开共享电子表格
and I made it editable.
我把它设置为可编辑的。
- Yeah. - It's so cool.
- 是的。 - 太酷了。
- [Pieter] Interesting things start happening.
- [Pieter] 有趣的事情 开始发生。
- Yeah, I did it for like a workout thing,
- 是的，我这样做是为了锻炼身体，
'cause I was doing a large
因为我正在做一个大的
amount of pushups and pull ups every day.
每天的俯卧撑和引体向上的数量。
- Yeah, I remember this man, yeah.
- 是的，我记得这个人，是的。
- (laugh) And well, I had Google Sheets is pretty limited
-（笑）好吧，我的 Google Sheets 非常有限
and that everything is allowed.
并且一切都是被允许的。
So people could just write anything in any cell
所以人们可以在任何 单元格中写任何东西
and they can create new sheets.
他们可以创建新的工作表。
- Yeah. - New tabs.
- 是的。 - 新标签。
And it just exploded.
它就爆炸了。
And one of the things
还有一件事
that I really enjoyed is there's very few trolls
我真正喜欢的是那里 的巨魔很少
because actually other people would delete the trolls.
因为实际上其他人 会删除巨魔。
There would be like this weird war-
会有这样奇怪的战争——
- Army, yeah. - Of like.
- 军队，是的。 - 喜欢。
They want like to protect the thing.
他们想要保护这个东西。
It's an immune system that's inherent to the thing.
这是事物固有的 免疫系统。
- It comes to society. - Yeah.
- 它来到了社会。 - 是 的。
- In the spreadsheets.
- 在电子表格中。
- And then there's the outcast
- 然后就是被遗弃的人
who go to the bottom of the spreadsheet
谁转到电子表格的底部
and they would try to hide messages,
他们会试图隐藏信息，
and they like, I don't wanna be
他们喜欢，我不想
with the cool kids up at the top of the spreadsheet,
那些很酷的孩子位于 电子表格的顶部，
so I'm gonna at the bottom. - Self-harmonizing.
所以我要在底部。 - 自我协调。
- Yes. - It's insane.
- 是的。 - 这太疯狂了。
- It's fast.
- 速度很快。
I mean, but that kind of
我的意思是，但是那种
crowdsourcing element is really powerful.
众包元素确实很强大。
And if you can create a product that use that
如果你可以创建一 个使用它的产品
to his benefit, that's really nice.
对他来说，这真的很好。
Any kind of voting system, any kind of rating system
任何类型的投票系统， 任何类型的评级系统
for A and B testing is really-
对于 A 和 B 测试来说确实是-
- Yeah. - Really, really fascinating.
- 是的 。 - 真的，真的很迷人。
So anyway, so Nomad List is great.
无论如何，Nomad List 很棒。
I would love for you to talk about that.
我很想让你谈谈这个。
But one sort of way to talk about it is
但谈论它的一种方式是
through you building Hoodmaps.
通过您构建 Hoodmaps。
- Yeah. - So you did an awesome thing,
- 是的。 - 所以你做了一件了不起的事情
which is document yourself building the thing
这是你自己构建这个 东西的文档
and doing so in just a handful of days,
并在短短几天内做到这一点，
like three, four, five days.
就像三、四、五天。
So people should definitely
所以人们绝对应该
check out the video in the blog post.
查看博客文章中的视频。
Can you explain what Hoodmaps is
你能解释一下Hoodmaps是什么吗
and what this whole- - Yeah.
这整个--是的 。
- This process was?
——这个过程是？
- So I was traveling,
- 所以我在旅行，
and I was still trying to find problems, right?
我仍然在寻找 问题，对吗？
I would discover that like everybody's experience of a city
我会发现就像每个人 对一座城市的经历一样
is different because they stay in different areas.
是不同的，因为他们 住在不同的地区。
- Yeah. - So I'm from Amsterdam
- 是的。 - 所以我来自阿姆斯特丹
and when I grew up in Amsterdam or I didn't grow up,
当我在阿姆斯特丹 长大或者我没有长大时，
but I lived there, in university,
但我大学时住在那里
I knew that center is like in Europe,
我知道那个中心就像欧洲一样，
the centers are always tourist areas.
这些中心始终是旅游区。
So they're super busy,
所以他们超级忙
they're not very authentic.
它们不是很正宗。
They're not really Dutch culture,
它们并不是真正的荷兰文化，
it's Amsterdam tourist culture.
这是阿姆斯特丹的旅游文化。
So when people would travel to Amsterdam would say,
所以当人们去阿姆斯特丹 旅行时会说，
don't go to the center, go to Southeast
不要去中心，去东南
of the center, Jordaan or the De Pijp or something,
中心的，Jordaan 或 De Pijp 之类的，
more hipster areas.
更多时髦区域。
A little more authentic culture of Amsterdam.
更真实的阿姆斯特丹 文化。
That's where I would live,
那就是我要住的地方
and where I would go.
以及我要去哪里。
And I thought this could be like an app
我认为这可能就像一个应用程序
where you can have like a Google maps
在那里你可以像谷歌地图一样
and you put colors over it.
然后你在上面涂上颜色。
You have areas that are like color code.
您有类似颜色代码的区域。
Red is tourists, green is rich,
红色是游客，绿色是富贵，
green money, yellow is hipster.
绿色是金钱，黄色是时髦。
You can figure out where you need to go
你可以弄清楚你需要去哪里
in the city when you travel,
当你在城市旅行时，
'cause I was traveling a lot.
因为我经常出差。
I wanted to go to the cool spots.
我想去那些很酷的地方。
- So just use color. - Yeah.
- 所以只使用颜色。 - 是 的。
Color, yeah.
颜色，是的。
Yeah, and I would use a Canvas.
是的，我会使用画布。
So I thought, okay, what do I need?
所以我想，好吧，我需要什么？
I need to-
我需要-
- Did you know that you would be using a Canvas?
- 您知道您会使用 画布吗？
- No, I didn't know it was possible,
- 不，我不知道这是可能的，
'cause I didn't know.
因为我不知道。
- So this is the cool thing.
- 所以这是很酷的事情。
People should really check out.
人们真的应该检查一下。
- This is how it started.
- 事情就是这样开始的。
- Because you're honestly capture so beautifully,
- 因为你真的拍 得很漂亮，
the humbling aspects,
谦卑的方面，
the embarrassing aspects of like not knowing what to do.
尴尬的方面是不 知道该怎么做。
It's like how do I do this?
这就像我该怎么做？
And you document yourself.
并且您记录自己。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你是对的。
Dude, I feel embarrassed about myself. (laughs)
哥们儿，我为自己感到 羞耻。 （笑）
- Oh, really, yeah.
- 哦，真的，是的。
- It's called being alive.
- 这就是所谓的活着。
Nice.
好的。
So you're like, you don't know anything about,
所以你就像，你什么 都不知道，
so Canvas is a HTML5 thing
所以 Canvas 是 HTML5 的东西
that allows you to draw shapes.
允许您绘制形状。
- Yeah, draw images.
- 是的，画图像。
Just draw pixels essentially so.
基本上就是这样绘制像素。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And that was special back then.
- 这在当时很特别。
Because before you could only have like elements, right?
因为以前只能有相似 的元素，对吗？
So you wanna draw a pixel, use a Canvas.
所以你想绘制一个像素，使用画布。
And I knew I needed to draw pixels
我知道我需要绘制像素
'cause I need to draw these colors.
因为我需要画这些颜色。
And I felt like, okay,
我感觉，好吧，
I'll get like a Google maps iframe embed,
我会像 Google 地图 iframe 嵌入一样，
and then I'll put a Dave on top of it with the colors,
然后我会把戴夫和 颜色放在上面，
and I'll do like opacity 50, so it kind of shows.
我会喜欢不透明度 50， 所以它有点显示。
So I did that with Canvas.
所以我用 Canvas 做到了这一点。
And then I started drawing,
然后我就开始画画了
and then I felt like,
然后我觉得，
obviously, other people need to edit this
显然，其他人需要编辑这个
'cause I cannot draw all these things myself.
因为我自己无法画出 所有这些东西。
So I crowdsource it again,
所以我又众包了，
and you would draw on the map
你会在地图上画画
and then it would send the pixel data to the server.
然后它将像素数据 发送到服务器。
It would put it in the database,
它将把它放入数据库中，
and then I would have a robot running like a cron job,
然后我会让一个机器人像 cron 作业一样运行，
which every week would calculate,
每周都会计算，
or every day would calculate.
或者每天都会计算。
Okay, so Amsterdam Center,
好的，阿姆斯特丹中心，
there's like six people say,
大约有六个人说，
it's tourist, this part of the center,
这是游客中心的这一部分，
but two people say, it's like hipster.
但有两个人说，这就像时髦。
Okay, so the tourist part wins, right?
好吧，那么游客部分获胜，对吗？
It's just an array.
这只是一个数组。
So find the most common value
所以找到最常见的值
in a little pixel area on a map.
在地图上的一个小像素区域中。
So if most people say it's tourists, it's tourists,
所以如果大多数人说是 游客，那就是游客，
and it becomes red.
它变成红色。
And I would do that for all the GPS corners in the world.
我会对世界上所有的 GPS 角落都这样做。
- Can we just clarify- - Yeah.
- 我们可以澄清一下吗- - 是的。
- As a human that's contributing to this,
- 作为一个为此做出贡献的人，
do you have to be in that location
你必须在那个位置吗
to make the label or do you?
做标签还是你做？
- No, people just type in cities and go like,
- 不，人们只需输入城市 然后就可以了，
go berserk and start drawing everywhere.
发狂并开始到处画画。
- Would they draw shapes or would they draw pixels?
- 他们会绘制形状 还是绘制像素？
- Man, they drew like crazy stuff.
- 伙计，他们画得很疯狂。
Like offensive symbols.
就像攻击性的符号一样。
I cannot mention they would draw penises.
我不能说他们会画阴茎。
- I mean, that's obviously a guy thing.
- 我的意思是，这显然是男人的事情。
- I would do the same thing, draw penises.
- 我会做同样的事情，画阴茎。
- That's the first thing. (Pieter laughs)
- 这是第一件事。 （ 彼得笑）
When I show up to Mars and there's no cameras,
当我出现在火星上时 ，那里没有相机，
I'm drawing penis on the sand.
我正在沙子上画阴茎。
- Man, I did it in the snow, you know,
- 伙计，我是在雪地里做的，你知道，
but the penises did not become a problem,
但阴茎并没有成为问题，
'cause I knew that not everybody would draw a penis
因为我知道不是 每个人都会画阴茎
and not in the same place.
并且不在同一个地方。
So most people would use it fairly.
所以大多数人都会公平地使用它。
So just if I had enough crowdsource data.
所以只要我有足够的众包数据。
So you have all these pixels on top of it.
所以所有这些像素都在它上面。
It's like a layer of pixels. - Yeah.
它就像一层像素。 - 是 的。
- And then you choose the most common pixel.
- 然后你选择最 常见的像素。
So yeah, it's just like a bowl, but in visual format.
是的，它就像一个碗， 但是是视觉形式的。
And it worked and within a week got enough data,
它奏效了，一周内就获得 了足够的数据，
and it was like cities that did really well,
就好像城市表现 得非常好，
like Los Angeles, a lot of people started using it.
就像洛杉矶一样，很多 人开始使用它。
Like most data's in Los Angeles.
就像洛杉矶的大多数数据一样。
- Because Los Angeles has defined neighborhoods.
- 因为洛杉矶有明确 的社区。
- Yeah. - And not just
- 是的。 - 不仅仅是
in terms of the official labels,
从官方标签来看，
but like what they're known for.
但就像他们出名的那样。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Did you provide the categories
- 您是否提供了类别
that they were allowed to use as labels?
他们被允许用作标签？
- The colors, yeah. - As colors.
- 颜色，是的。 - 作为 颜色。
- So I think you can see there,
- 所以我想你可以看到那里，
there's like hipster, tourist, rich, business.
有时髦人士、游客 、富人、商人。
There's always a business area, right?
总有一个商业区，对吧？
And then there's a residential.
然后还有一个住宅区。
Residential is gray.
住宅是灰色的。
So I thought those were the most common things
所以我认为这些是 最常见的事情
in the city kind of.
在城市之类的。
- And a little bit meme,
- 还有一点模因，
like it's almost fun to label it
就像给它贴标签几乎很有趣
as that, right? - Yeah.
就这样，对吧？ - 是的。
I mean obviously, it's simplified,
我的意思是显然，它被简化了，
but you need to simplify this stuff.
但你需要简化这个东西。
You don't wanna have too many categories.
您不想有太多类别。
And it's essentially just like using a paint brush
本质上就像使用 画笔一样
where you select the color in a bottom,
您可以在其中选择底部的颜色，
you stick the category and you start drawing.
你坚持类别并 开始绘画。
There's no instruction.
没有任何指示。
There's no manual.
没有手册。
And then I also added tagging so people could like
然后我还添加了标签 ，这样人们就会喜欢
write something on a specific location.
在特定位置写一些东西。
So don't go here or here's like nice cafe and stuff.
所以不要去这里，否则这里就 像不错的咖啡馆之类的。
And man, the memes that came from that.
伙计，模因就是由此而来的。
And I also had upvoting,
而且我还点赞了
so that the tags could be upvoted.
以便标签可以被投票。
So the memes that came from that is like amazing.
所以由此产生的 模因真是太棒了。
People in Los Angeles would write crazy stuff.
洛杉矶人会写一些 疯狂的东西。
It would go viral in all these cities.
它会在所有这些城市传播开来。
You can allow your location
您可以允许您的位置
and will probably send you to Austin.
可能会送你去奥斯汀。
- (laughs) Okay, so we're looking,
-（笑）好吧，所以我们正在寻找，
(laughs) oh boy, drunk hipsters.
（笑）哦，天哪，醉酒的嬉皮士。
- AirBroNBros.
- AirBroNBros。 - AirBroNBros。
- Gentrifiers.
- 中产阶级。
- Hipster girls who do cocaine.
- 吸食可卡因的时髦女孩。
- I saw a guy in a fish costume get beaten up here.
- 我看到一个穿着鱼装 的人在这里被殴打。
- Yep,
- 是的，
that seems also accurate.
这似乎也准确。
- Overpriced and underwhelming.
- 价格过高且平淡无奇。
- (laughs) Let me see, let me make sure this is accurate.
-（笑）让我看看，让我 确保这是准确的。
Let's see.
让我们来看看。
Dirty Sixth for people who know Austin
对于了解奥斯汀的人来说，肮脏的第六名
know that that's important to label.
知道标记很重要。
Sixth Street is famous in Austin.
第六街在奥斯汀很有名。
Dirty Sixth drunk frat boys, accurate.
肮脏的第六个醉酒的兄弟会男孩，准确。
Drunk frat bros.
喝醉了的兄弟会。
Continued on sixth, very well -known.
继续第六，非常有名。
- West Sixth douchebros.
- 西六混蛋。 - 西六混蛋。
- They go from frat to douche. - Douche.
- 他们从兄弟会变成混蛋。 - 灌洗。
I mean it's very accurate so far.
我的意思是到目前为止它非常准确。
- Really.
- 真的。
- They only let hot people live here.
- 他们只让性感的人住在这里。
(laughs) I think that might be accurate.
（笑）我认为这可能是准确的。
- It's like the district.
- 就像这个地区一样。
Exercise freaks on the river.
河边的锻炼狂人。
Yeah, that's true.
是的，确实如此。
- Dog runners accurate. - Yeah.
- 跑狗准确。 - 是 的。
- Saw a guy in the fish costume get beat up here.
- 看到一个穿着鱼服装 的人在这里被殴打。
- I wanna know the story.
- 我想知道这个故事。
- So that's all user contributed.
- 这就是所有用户贡献的。
- Yeah, and that's like stuff I couldn't come up with it,
- 是的，这就像我 想不出的东西，
'cause I don't know Austin,
因为我不认识奥斯汀
I don't know the memes here in the subcultures.
我不知道亚文化 中的模因。
- And then me as a user can upload or down vote this.
- 然后我作为用户可以 上传或拒绝投票。
- [Pieter] Yes.
- [彼得] 是的。
- So this is completely crowdsourced.
- 所以这完全是众包的。
- It's like 'cause of Reddit upvote, downvote,
- 就像 Reddit 的赞成 票、反对票一样，
took it from there.
从那里拿来的。
- That's really, really, really powerful.
- 这真的，真的，真的很强大。
Single people with dogs, accurate.
单身人士养狗，准确。
At which point did it go from colors
从什么时候开始，它从颜色开始
to the actually showing the text?
到实际显示文本？
- I think I added the text like a week after.
- 我想我是在一周 后添加的文字。
And so here's like the pixels.
这就是像素。
- So that's really cool.
- 所以这真的很酷。
The pixels, how do you go from that?
像素，你如何处理？
That's a huge amount of data.
这是一个巨大的数据量。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Now looking at an image where it's just
- 现在看一张图像，它只是
a sea of pixels that call it different colors.
称为不同颜色 的像素海洋。
- Yeah. - In a city.
- 是的。 - 在一个城市。
So how do you combine that to be a thing
那么你如何将它结合起来成为一个东西
that actually makes it some sense?
这实际上有道理吗？
- I think here the problem was that you have this data,
- 我认为这里的问题 是你有这些数据，
but it's like it's not locked to one location.
但它就像没有锁定 在一个位置。
- Yeah. - So I had to normalize it.
- 是的。 - 所以我必须将其标准化。
So when you click, when you draw on a map,
所以当你点击时，当你在地图上画图时，
it will show you the specific pixel location
它会显示具体 的像素位置
and you can convert the pixel location
你可以转换像素位置
to a GPS coordinate, right?
到 GPS 坐标，对吗？
Like latitude, longitudes.
比如纬度、经度。
But the number will have a lot of commas
但是数字会有很多逗号
or a lot of decimals, right?
或者很多小数，对吧？
Because it's very specific,
因为它非常具体，
it's like this specific part of the table.
就像桌子上的这个特定部分一样。
So what you wanna do is you wanna take that pixel
所以你想要做的就是 你想要获取那个像素
and you wanna normalize it by removing like decimals,
你想通过删除小数 来标准化它，
which I discovered,
我发现，
so you're talking about this neighborhood,
所以你说的是这个街区
or this street, right?
或者这条街，对吗？
And so that's what I did.
这就是我所做的。
I just took the decimals off
我刚刚把小数去掉了
and then I saved it like this.
然后我就这样保存了。
And then it starts going to like a grid.
然后它开始喜欢网格。
And then you have like a grid of data.
然后你就有了一个数据网格。
You get like a pixel map kind of.
你会得到类似像素图的东西。
- And then you said it looks kind of ugly,
- 然后你说它看起来有点丑
so then you smooth it.
那么你就平滑它。
- Yeah, I started adding blurring and stuff.
- 是的，我开始添加模糊 之类的东西。
I think now it's not smooth again,
我觉得现在又不顺利了
'cause I liked it better.
因为我更喜欢它。
People like the pixel look kinda.
人们喜欢像素的外观。
Yeah, a lot of people use it and it keeps going viral.
是的，很多人都在使用它， 而且它一直在病毒式传播。
And every time my maps bill like Mapbox,
每当我的地图像 Mapbox 一样计费时，
I had to stop using...
我不得不停止使用...
You first use Google Maps, it went viral,
你首先使用谷歌地图，它迅速传播开来，
and Google Maps, it was out of credits.
和谷歌地图，它的积分已经用完了。
It's so funny,
真是太搞笑了
when I launched it, it went viral.
当我推出它时，它迅速传播开来。
Google Maps, the map didn't load anymore.
谷歌地图，地图不再加载。
It says over the limits,
据说超出了限制，
you need to contact enterprise sales.
您需要联系企业销售。
But I need now like a map.
但我现在需要一张地图。
And I don't wanna contact enterprise sales.
而且我不想 联系企业销售。
I don't wanna go on a call schedule with some calendar.
我不想用日历来记录 通话时间表。
So I switched to Mapbox,
所以我改用Mapbox，
and then had Mapbox for years,
然后使用 Mapbox 多年，
and then it went viral
然后它就疯传了
and I had a bill of $20,000 was like last year.
和去年一样，我 的账单是 20,000 美元。
So they helped me with the bill.
所以他们帮我付了账单。
They said, "You can pay less."
他们说：“你可以少付点钱。”
And then I now switched to like a open source
然后我现在转 而喜欢开源
kind of map platform.
一种地图平台。
So it's a very expensive product
所以这是一个非常昂贵的产品
and never made any dollar money.
并且从未赚过一美元钱。
But it's very fun.
但这很有趣。
But it's very expensive.
但它非常昂贵。
- What do you learn from that?
- 你从中学到了什么？
So like from that experience,
所以就像那次经历一样，
'cause when you leverage somebody else's through the API.
因为当你通过 API 利用别人的 API 时。
- Yeah, I mean I don't think a map hosting service
- 是的，我的意思是 我不认为地图托管服务
should cost this much.
应该花这么多钱。
But I could host it myself,
但我可以自己主持，
but that would be...
但那将是...
I dunno how to do that,
我不知道该怎么做，
but I could do that.
但我可以做到。
- Yeah, it's super complicated.
- 是的，这非常复杂。
- I think that the thing is more about like,
- 我认为事情更 多的是，
you can't make money with this project.
你无法通过这个项目赚钱。
I tried to do many things to make money with it
我尝试用它做很多 事情来赚钱
and it hasn't worked.
但它没有起作用。
You talked about like possibly doing
你谈到可能会做
advertisements on it or some somehow.
其上的广告或某种方式。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Or people sponsoring it, yeah.
- 或者有人赞助它，是的。
It's really surprising to me
这真的让我很惊讶
that people don't want to advertise on it.
人们不想在上面做广告。
- I think map apps are very hard to like monetize.
- 我认为地图应用 程序很难盈利。
Google Maps also doesn't really make money.
谷歌地图也并没有 真正赚钱。
Sometimes you see these ads,
有时你看到这些广告，
but I don't think there's a lot of money there.
但我不认为那里 有很多钱。
You could put like a banner ad but it's kind of ugly,
你可以像横幅广告一样放置 ，但它有点难看，
and the product is kind of like, it's kind of cool.
这个产品有点像 ，有点酷。
So it's kinda fun to like subsidize it.
所以喜欢补贴它有点有趣。
And it's kinda a little bit part of Nomad List.
它是 Nomad List 的一部分。
I put it on Nomad List in the cities as well.
我也把它列入城市 的游牧名单。
But I also realized,
但我也意识到，
you don't need to monetize everything.
你不需要把一切都货币化。
Some products are just cool
有些产品很酷
and it's cool to have Hoodmaps exist.
Hoodmaps 的存在真是太酷了。
I want this to exist, right?
我希望这个存在，对吗？
- Yeah, there's a bunch of stuff you've created
- 是的，你创造 了很多东西
that I'm just glad exists in this world.
我很高兴存在于这个世界上。
That's true.
这是真的。
And it's a whole nother puzzle.
这完全是另一个难题。
And I'm surprised to figure out how to make money off of it.
我很惊讶地发现如何 从中赚钱。
I'm surprised maps don't make money,
我很惊讶地图不赚钱
but you're right, it's hard.
但你是对的，这很难。
It's hard to make money. - Yeah.
赚钱很难。 - 是 的。
- 'Cause there's a lot of compute required
- 因为需要大量计算
to actually bring it to life.
真正将其变为现实。
- Also, where do you put the ad, right?
- 另外，你把广告放在哪里了，对吧？
If you have a website, you can put an ad box
如果你有网站，可以 放置广告框
or you can do a product placement or something.
或者你可以做植入式 广告什么的。
But you're talking about a map app
但你说的是地图应用程序
that where 90% of the interface is a map.
界面的 90% 都是地图。
So what are you gonna do?
那你要做什么？
It's hard to figure out where is this?
很难弄清楚这是哪里？
- Yeah, and people don't wanna pay for it.
- 是的，人们不想为此付费。
- No, exactly, because if you make people pay for it,
- 不，确切地说，因为如果 你让人们为此付费，
you lose 99% of the user base
你失去了 99% 的用户群
and you lose the crowdsource data.
并且您会丢失众包数据。
So it's not fun anymore.
所以不再好玩了。
It stops being accurate, right?
它不再准确了，对吧？
They pay for it by crowdsourcing the data,
他们通过众包数据来支付费用，
but then, yeah, it's fine.
但然后，是的，没关系。
It doesn't make money, but it's cool.
虽然不赚钱，但是很酷。
- But that said, Nomad List makes money.
- 但话虽如此，Nomad List 也能赚钱。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- So what was the story behind Nomad List?
- 那么 Nomad List 背后的故事是什么？
So Nomad List started
于是Nomad List开始了
because I was in Chiang Mai in Thailand,
因为我在泰国清迈，
which is now like the second city here.
现在就像这里的第二个城市。
And I was working on my laptop.
我正在用我的笔记本电脑工作。
I met like other nomads there,
我和那里的其他游牧民族一样，
and I was like, okay, this seems like a cool thing to do,
我当时想，好吧，这看 起来是一件很酷的事情，
like working on your laptop in a different country,
就像在不同的国家使用笔记本 电脑工作一样，
kinda travel around.
有点到处旅行。
But back then the internet everywhere was very slow.
但当时各地的互联网 速度都非常慢。
So the internet was fast in,
所以互联网很快，
for example, Holland or United States,
例如荷兰或美国，
but in a lot of parts in South America
但在南美洲的很多地方
or Asia was very slow, like 0.5 megabits.
或者亚洲非常慢，大约0.5兆比特。
So you couldn't watch a YouTube video.
所以您无法观看 YouTube 视频。
Thailand weirdly had like quite fast internet.
奇怪的是，泰国的 互联网速度非常快。
But I wanted to find like other cities where I could go
但我想找到像其他城市 一样我可以去的地方
to like work on my laptop, whatever, and travel.
喜欢在笔记本电脑上工作 等等，还有旅行。
But we needed like fast internet.
但我们需要快速的互联网。
So I was like, let's crowdsource
所以我想，让我们众包吧
this information with a spreadsheet.
将此信息与电子表格一起使用。
And I also needed to know the cost of living,
我还需要了解 生活费用
'cause I didn't have a lot of money.
因为我没有很多钱。
I had $500 a month.
我每个月有 500 美元。
So I had to find a place where the rent was $200 per month
所以我必须找一个每月 租金200美元的地方
or something where I had some money
或者我有钱的东西
that I could actually rent something
我可以租一些东西
and there was Nomad List.
还有游牧者名单。
And it still runs.
它仍然运行。
I think it's now almost 10 years.
我想现在已经快10年了。
- So it's just to describe how it works.
- 所以这只是为了描述它是如何工作的。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- I'm looking at Chiang Mai here.
- 我正在看这里的清迈。
There's a total score, rank number two.
总分排名第二。
- Yeah, that's a number score.
- 是的，这是一个数字分数。
- 4.82 like by members.
- 4.82 会员点赞。
But it's looking at the internet.
但它正在看互联网。
In this case, it's fast. - Yeah.
在这种情况下，速度很快。 - 是的。
- Fun, temperature, humidity, air quality,
- 乐趣、温度、湿度、空气质量、
safety, food safety, crime, racism
安全、食品安全、犯罪、种族主义
or lack of crime, lack of racism, educational level,
或没有犯罪、没有种族主义 、教育水平，
power grid, vulnerability, to climate change, income level.
电网、脆弱性、气候 变化、收入水平。
- It's a little much. - English.
- 有点多了。 - 英语 。
It's awesome.
太棒了。
Walkability. - Keep getting stuff.
步行性。 - 继续拿东西。
- Because for certain groups of people,
- 因为对于某些人群来说，
certain things really matter.
某些事情确实很重要。
And this is really cool.
这真的很酷。
- Yeah. - Happiness.
- 是的。 - 幸福。
I'd love to ask you about that.
我很想问你这个问题。
Nightlife, free Wi-Fi, AC,
夜生活、免费无线网络、空调、
female friendly, freedom of speech.
女性友善，言论自由。
- Yeah, not so good in Thailand.
- 是的，在泰国不太好。
- Values derived from national statistics.
- 来自国家统计数据的值。
(laughs) I like how that one.
（笑）我喜欢那个。
- I need to do that
- 我需要这样做
because the data sets are usually national.
因为数据集通常 是全国性的。
They're not on city level,
他们不在城市层面，
right? - Yes.
正确的？ - 是的。
- So I dunno about the freedom of speech
- 所以我不知道言论自由
between Bangkok or Chiang Mai.
曼谷或清迈之间。
I know them in Thailand.
我在泰国认识他们。
- I mean this is really fascinating.
- 我的意思是这真的很有趣。
So this is for city?
那么这是针对城市的吗？
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Is basically rating all the different things
- 基本上是对所有不同 的事物进行评级
that matter to you and internet.
这对您和互联网都很重要。
And this is all crowdsourced.
而这一切都是众包的。
- Well, so started crowdsourced,
- 嗯，所以开始众包，
but then I realized that you can download more
但后来我意识到你 可以下载更多
accurate data sets from like public source,
来自类似公共来源的 准确数据集，
like World Bank.
像世界银行。
They have a lot of public data sets, United Nations,
他们有很多公共数据 集，联合国，
and you can download a lot of data there,
你可以在那里下载很多数据，
which you can freely use.
您可以自由使用。
I started getting frauds crowdsource data where,
我开始获取欺诈众包 数据，
for example, people from India,
例如，来自印度的人，
they really love India,
他们真的很爱印度，
and they would submit the best scores
他们会提交最好的成绩
for everything in India.
对于印度的一切。
And not just like one person,
而且不只是像一个人，
but like a lot of people,
但和很多人一样，
they would love to pump India.
他们很乐意为印度注入动力。
And I'm like, I love India too,
我想，我也喜欢印度，
but that's not valid data.
但这不是有效数据。
So you started getting discrepancies in the data
所以你开始发现 数据存在差异
between where people where from and stuff.
人来自哪里和东西之间。
So I started switching to data sets,
所以我开始转向数据集，
and now it's mostly data sets,
现在主要是数据集，
but one thing that's still crowdsourced is,
但仍然众包的 一件事是，
so people add where they are,
所以人们添加他们在哪里，
they add their travels to their profile
他们将旅行添加到个人资料中
and use that data to see which places are upcoming
并使用该数据来查看 即将到来的地点
and which places are popular now.
以及现在哪些地方很受欢迎。
So about half the ranking you see here is based on
所以你在这里看到的排名 大约有一半是基于
actual digital nomads who are there.
那里有真正的数字游牧民。
You can click on the city, you can click on people,
你可以点击城市，你 可以点击人物，
and you can see the people,
你可以看到人们，
the users that are actually there.
实际存在的用户。
And it's like 30,000, 45,000 members.
大约有 30,000、45,000 名会员。
So these people are in Austin now.
所以这些人现在在奥斯汀。
- 1,800 remote workers in Austin now.
- 奥斯汀目前有 1,800 名远程工作者。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Of which 8+ members checked in.
- 其中8名以上会员签到。
Members who will be here soon and go.
很快就到的成员就走吧。
- Yeah, so we have meetups. - It's amazing.
- 是的，所以我们有聚会。 - 太棒了。
- So people organize their own meetups
- 所以人们组织自己的聚会
and we have about, I think like 30 per month.
我想我们每个月 大约有 30 个。
So it's like one meetup a day.
所以这就像一天一次聚会。
And I don't do anything.
而我什么也不做。
They organize themselves.
他们自己组织起来。
It's a whole black box.
这是一个完整的黑盒子。
It just runs and I don't do a lot on it.
它只是运行，我没有做太多事情。
It pulls data from everywhere and it just works.
它从各处提取数据 并且可以正常工作。
- Cons of Austin.
- 奥斯汀的缺点。
It's too expensive, very sweaty, and humid now.
现在太贵了，出汗 多，而且潮湿。
Difficult to make friends. - Difficult to make friends.
很难交朋友。 - 很难交朋友。
Interesting, right?
有趣，对吧？
I didn't know that.
我不知道。
- Difficult to make friends- - In Austin.
- 很难交朋友- - 在奥斯汀 。
- But its all crowdsource,
- 但这都是众包的，
but mostly it's pros.
但主要是它的优点。
- Yeah, Austin's very- - Pretty safe, fast internet.
- 是的，奥斯汀非常- - 非常安全、快速的互联网。
- I understand why it says not safe for women
- 我明白为什么它 说对女性不安全
to check the dataset.
检查数据集。
It feels safe.
感觉很安全。
The problem with a lot of places like United States
很多地方都存在这个 问题，比如美国
is that it depends per area, right?
这取决于每个地区，对吗？
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- So if you get like city level data
- 所以如果你得到像城市级别的数据
or nation level data,
或国家级数据，
it's like Brazil is the worst
好像巴西是最糟糕的
because the range in like safe and wealthy
因为范围就像安全和富裕
and not safe is like huge.
不安全就像巨大的。
So you can't say many things about Brazil.
所以关于巴西你不能说太多。
- So once they actually show up to the city,
- 所以一旦他们真正 出现在这座城市
how do you figure out what area?
你怎么知道哪个区域？
Like where to get fast Internet.
比如哪里可以快速上网。
For example, for me, it's consistently a struggle
例如，对我来说，这 始终是一场斗争
to figure out like- - Still.
弄清楚像- -仍然 。
- Hotels with fast Wi-Fi, for example, like a place.
- 拥有快速 Wi-Fi 的酒店 ，例如某个地方。
Okay, okay, I show up to a city.
好吧，好吧，我出现在一个城市。
There's a lot of fascinating puzzles,
这里有很多令人着迷的谜题
and I haven't figured out a way
我还没想出办法
to actually solve this puzzle.
才能真正解决这个难题。
When I show up to a city,
当我出现在一座城市的时候，
figuring out where I can get fast internet connection
弄清楚在哪里可以获得 快速的互联网连接
and for podcasting purposes
以及用于播客目的
where I can find a place with a table that's quiet.
我可以找到一个有桌子 且安静的地方。
- Right, yeah, yeah.
- 是的，是的，是的。
- That's not easy. - Construction sounds.
- 这并不容易。 - 施工声音。
- All kinds of sounds.
- 各种声音。
You get to learn about all the sources
您可以了解所有来源
of sounds in the world,
世界上的声音，
and also the quality of the room
还有房间的质量
because the emptier the room
因为房间越空
and if it's just walls without any curtains
如果只是墙壁而 没有任何窗帘
or any of this kind of stuff,
或任何此类的东西，
then there's echoes in the room anyway.
无论如何，房间里都会有回声。
But you figure out that a lot of hotels don't have tables.
但你发现很多酒店 都没有桌子。
They don't have like normal.
他们没有像平常那样的。
- They have this weird desk, right?
- 他们有这张奇怪的桌子，对吧？
- Yeah, they have- - But it's not a center table.
- 是的，他们有- - 但这不是中间的桌子。
- Yep, and if you want get a nicer hotel
- 是的，如果你想住一家更好的酒店
where it is more spacious and so on.
哪里更宽敞等等。
They usually have these like boutique,
他们通常有这些像精品店，
fancy looking, modernist- - Annoying tables.
外观奇特，现代主义- - 烦人的桌子。
- Tables, that don't- - Yeah, it's too designy.
- 桌子，那不- - 是的 ，它太有设计感了。
- It's too designy. - Yeah.
- 太有设计感了- 是 的。
- They're not really real tables.
- 它们并不是真正的桌子。
- What if you get Ikea?
- 如果你买了宜家怎么办？
- Buy Ikea?
- 买宜家？
- Yeah, before you arrive you order an Ikea.
- 是的，在你到达 之前你订购了宜家。
- Yeah. - Nomads do this.
- 是的。 - 游牧 民族就是这样做的。
They get desks.
他们有桌子。
- I feel like you should be able to show up to a place
- 我觉得你应该能够 出现在一个地方
and have the desk.
并有书桌。
Unless you stay in there for a long time.
除非你长期呆在那里。
Just the entire assembly, all that.
只是整个装配，所有这些。
Airbnb is so unreliable.
Airbnb 太不靠谱了。
The range in quality that you get-
您获得的质量范围-
- Yeah. - Is huge.
- 是的。 - 很大。
Hotels have a lot of problems, pros and cons.
酒店有很多问题， 有优点也有缺点。
Hotels have the problem that the pictures,
酒店图片有问题，
somehow never have good representative pictures
不知怎么的，从来没有 好的代表性图片
of what's actually going to be in the room.
房间里实际 有什么。
- And that's the problem.
- 这就是问题所在。
Fake photos, man.
假照片，伙计。
- If I could have the kind of data you have
- 如果我能得到你所 拥有的那种数据
on Nomad List for hotels. - Yeah, yeah, man.
列入酒店游牧名单。 - 是的 ，是的，伙计。
- And I feel like you can make a lot of money on that too.
- 我觉得你也可以 赚很多钱。
- Yeah, the booking fees affiliate, right?
- 是的，预订费附属机构，对吗？
I thought about this idea,
我想到了这个想法，
'cause we have the same problem.
因为我们有同样的问题。
I go to hotels,
我去酒店，
and there's specific ones that are very good
有一些特别 好的
and I know now the chains and stuff,
我现在知道了链条之类的东西，
but even if you go to some chains are very bad
但即使你去一些 连锁店也很糟糕
in a specific city and very good in other cities.
在特定城市，在 其他城市非常好。
- And each individual hotel has a lot of kinds of rooms.
- 每个酒店都有 很多种房间。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Some are more expensive, some are cheaper, and so on.
- 有些更贵，有些 更便宜，等等。
But you can get the details of what's in the room.
但您可以获取房间内物品 的详细信息。
What's the actual layout of the room,
房间的实际布局是怎样的
what is the view of the room. - You scan it.
房间的景色如何。 - 你 扫描它。
- I feel like as a hotel you can win a lot.
- 我觉得作为一家 酒店你可以赢得很多。
So first, you create a service
首先，您创建一个服务
that allows you to have high resolution data about a hotel,
让您能够获得有关酒店 的高分辨率数据，
then one hotel signs up for that.
然后一家酒店就签约了。
I would 100% use that website to look for a hotel
我 100% 会使用 该网站寻找酒店
instead of the crappy alternatives
而不是糟糕的替代品
that don't give any information.
不提供任何信息。
And I feel like there'll be this pressure
我感觉会有这样的压力
for all the hotels to join that site
让所有酒店加入该网站
and you could make a ton of money,
你可以赚很多钱，
'cause hotels make a lot of money.
因为酒店能赚很多钱。
- I think it's true.
- 我认为这是真的。
But the problem is with these hotels,
但问题是这些酒店，
like it's same with airline industry.
就像航空业一样。
Why does every airline website suck
为什么每个航空公司的网站都很糟糕
when you try book a flights?
当您尝试预订航班时？
- Yeah. - It's very strange.
- 是的 。 - 这很奇怪。
Why does it have to suck?
为什么一定要吸？
Obviously, there's competition here.
显然，这里存在竞争。
Why doesn't the best website win?
为什么最好的网站没有获胜？
- What's the explanation of that?
- 对此有何解释？
- Man, I thought about this for years.
- 伙计，我想这个问题很多年了。
So I think it's like I have to book the flight anyway.
所以我认为无论如何我 都必须预订航班。
I know there's a route that they take
我知道他们有一条路线
and I need to book, for example, Qatar Airlines,
我需要预订，例如 卡塔尔航空，
and I need to get through this process.
我需要完成这个过程。
And with a hotel similar, you need a hotel anyway.
有了类似的酒店，无论如何 你都需要一家酒店。
So do you have time to like figure out the best one?
那么您有时间找出 最好的一个吗？
Not really.
并不真地。
You kind of just need to get the place booked
您只需要 预订位置
and you need to get the flight
你需要赶上航班
and you'll go through the pain of this process.
你会经历这个 过程的痛苦。
And that's why this process always sucks so much
这就是为什么这个过程 总是那么糟糕
for hotels and airline websites and stuff.
用于酒店和航空公司网站等。
Because they don't have an incentive to improve it,
因为他们没有动力 去改进它
because generally only for
因为一般只针对
a super upper segment of the market,
市场的超级高端，
I think super high luxury,
我觉得超高奢华，
it affects the actual booking, right?
这会影响实际预订，对吗？
- I don't know.
- 我不知道。
I think that's an interesting theory.
我认为这是一个有趣的理论。
I think that must be a different theory.
我认为这一定是一个不同的理论。
My theory would be that great engineers,
我的理论是伟大的工程师，
great software engineers are not allowed to make changes.
伟大的软件工程师不 被允许做出改变。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Basically, there's some kind of bureaucracy,
- 基本上，存在 某种官僚主义，
there's way too many managers.
经理太多了。
There's a lot of bureaucracy.
有很多官僚主义。
And great engineers show up,
伟大的工程师出现了，
they try to work there
他们尝试在那里工作
and they're not allowed
他们不被允许
to really make any contributions
真正做出任何贡献
and then they leave.
然后他们就离开了。
And so you have a lot of mediocre software engineers,
所以你有很多平庸 的软件工程师，
they're not really interested in improving any other thing.
他们对改进任何其他事情 并不真正感兴趣。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And literally, they would like to improve the stuff,
- 从字面上看，他们想要 改进这些东西，
but the bureaucracy of the place,
但这个地方的官僚主义，
plus all the bosses,
再加上所有的老板，
all the high up people are not technical people probably.
所有的高层人士可能 都不是技术人员。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- They don't know much about web dev.
- 他们对网络开发了解不多。
They don't know much about programming.
他们对编程了解不多。
So they just don't give any respect.
所以他们根本不给予任何尊重。
- Yeah. - You have to give the freedom
- 是的 。 - 你必须给予自由
and the respect to great engineers
以及对伟大工程师的尊重
as they try to do great things.
当他们尝试做伟大的事情时。
That feels like an explanation.
感觉像是一个解释。
If you were a great programmer,
如果你是一个优秀的程序员，
would you wanna work at America Airlines or?
你想在美国航空 工作吗？
- No, no.
- 不，不。
- I'm torn on that
- 我对此很伤心
'cause I actually as somebody who loves program,
因为我其实作为 一个热爱节目的人，
would love to work at America Airlines
很想在美国航空工作
so I can make the thing better.
这样我就能让事情变得更好。
- Yeah, I would work there just to fix it for myself.
- 是的，我会在那里工作 只是为了自己修复它。
- Yeah, for yourself.
- 是的，为了你自己。
And then you just know how much suffering you're alleviated.
然后你就会知道你减轻 了多少痛苦。
- [Pieter] Yeah, yeah, for the world, for society.
- [彼得] 是的，是的，为了 世界，为了社会。
- Just imagine all the thousands,
- 想象一下成千上万的人，
maybe millions of people that go to that website.
也许有数百万人 访问该网站。
- Yeah. - And have to click
- 是的。 - 并且必须点击
like a million times.
就像一百万次。
It often doesn't work.
它经常不起作用。
It's clunky, all that kind of stuff.
它很笨重，诸如此类。
You're making their life just so much better.
您正在让他们的生活 变得更加美好。
- Much better, yeah. - Yeah.
- 好多了，是的。 - 是 的。
There must be an explanation
必须有一个解释
that has to do with managers and bureaucracies.
这与管理者和 官僚机构有关。
- I think it's money.
- 我认为是钱。
Do you know booking.com?
你知道booking.com吗？
- Sure. - So it's a booking.
- 当然。 - 所以这是一个预订。
It's the biggest booking website in the world.
它是世界上最大 的预订网站。
- Yeah. - It's Dutch actually.
- 是的。 - 实际上是荷兰语。
And they have teams
而且他们有团队
because my friend worked there.
因为我朋友在那里工作。
They have teams for a specific part of the website,
他们为网站的特定 部分设有团队，
like a 10 by 10 pixels area where they run tests on this.
就像一个 10 x 10 像素的区域 ，他们在其中运行测试。
So they run tests like,
所以他们运行这样的测试，
and they're famous for this stuff.
他们因这些东西而闻名。
Oh, there's only one room left, right?
哦，只剩一间房间了，对吧？
Which is red letters.
也就是红色字母。
One room left book now.
还剩一间房，现在就预订。
And they got a fine
他们收到了罚款
from the European Union about this,
欧盟关于此事，
kind of interesting.
有点有趣。
So they have all these teams
所以他们拥有所有这些团队
and they run the test for 24 hours.
他们进行 24 小时的测试。
They go to sleep.
他们去睡觉了。
They wake up next day they come to the office,
他们第二天醒来 来到办公室，
and they see, okay, this performed better.
他们发现，好吧，这表现更好。
This website has become a monster,
这个网站已经变成了一个怪物，
but it's the most revenue generating
但这是创收最多的
hotel booking website in the world.
全球酒店预订网站。
It's number one.
这是第一名。
So that shows that it's not about user experience,
这表明这与用户 体验无关
it's about like,
这大约是，
I don't know about making more money,
不知道怎样才能赚更多的钱
not every company.
不是每家公司。
It's a public company,
这是一家上市公司，
if they're optimizing for money.
如果他们为了钱而优化。
- But you can optimize for money by disrupting,
- 但你可以通过破坏 来优化资金，
like making it way better.
喜欢让它变得更好。
- Yeah, but it's always start,
- 是啊，但一切总是要开始的
they start with disrupting.
他们从破坏开始。
Booking all started as a startup 1997.
Booking all 始于 1997 年。
And then they become like the old shit again.
然后他们又变得 像以前一样了。
Uber now starts to become a taxi again, right?
Uber 现在又开始变成出租车 了，对吗？
It was very good in the beginning.
一开始情况非常好。
Now it's kind of like taxis now in many places are better.
现在很多地方的出租车 都更好了。
They're nicer than Ubers, right?
他们比 Uber 更好，对吧？
So it's like this circle.
所以就像这个圈子一样。
- I think some of it is also just,
- 我认为其中一些也只是，
it's hard to have ultra competent engineers.
拥有超能力的工程师 是很困难的。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Stripe seems like a trivial thing,
- 条纹看起来是一件微不足道的事情，
but it's hard to pull off. - Yeah.
但这很难实现。 - 是 的。
- Why was it so hard for Amazon
- 为什么亚马逊这么难
to have buy with one click?
一键购买？
Which I think is a genius idea.
我认为这是一个天才的想法。
- Yeah. - Make buying easier.
- 是的。 - 让购买变得更容易。
Make it as frictionless as possible.
使其尽可能无摩擦。
Just click a button once thing you bought the thing.
一旦你买了东西， 只需点击一个按钮。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- As opposed to most of the web was a lot of clicking,
- 与大多数网络相反 的是大量的点击，
and it often doesn't work.
但它常常不起作用。
- Yeah. - Like with the Airlines.
- 是的。 - 就像航空公司一样。
- Remember the forms would delete,
- 请记住表格将被删除，
you could click Next, Submit,
您可以单击下一步，提交，
and 404 or something where your internet would go down.
以及 404 或其他导致 互联网瘫痪的情况。
- Yeah. - Your modem.
- 是的。 - 你 的调制解调器。
- That, man.
- 是的。 - 那个，伙计。
- And I would have an existential crisis.
- 我会遇到生存危机。
The frustration would take over my whole body.
挫败感会占据我 的整个身体。
- [Pieter] Yes.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And I would just wanted to quit life
- 我只想放弃生活
for a brief moment there.
在那里呆了一会儿。
- Yeah.
- 是的。 - 是的。
- I'm so happy to form stays in Google Chrome
- 我很高兴能在 Google Chrome 中留下来
now when something goes wrong.
现在当出现问题时。
So Google, somebody at Google
所以谷歌，谷歌的某人
improve society with that, right?
以此来改善社会，对吗？
- Yeah, and one of the challenges of Google
- 是的，这也是谷歌 面临的挑战之一
is to have the freedom to do that.
就是有这样做的自由。
- They don't anymore.
- 他们不再这样了
- There's a bunch of bureaucracy, yeah.
- 有很多官僚主义，是的。
- Yeah, at Google.
- 是的，在谷歌。
- There's so many brilliant, brilliant people there.
- 那里有很多才华横溢、 才华横溢的人。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- But it just moves slowly.
- 但它只是缓慢移动。 - 是 的。
- And I wonder why that is,
- 我想知道为什么会这样
and maybe that's the natural way of a company,
也许这就是公司 的自然方式，
but you have people like Elon who rolls in
但你有像埃隆这样的人加入
and just fires most of the folks
并解雇了大多数人
and always operate,
并始终运行，
like push the company to operate as a startup,
就像推动公司以初创 公司的形式运营，
even what's already big.
即使已经很大了。
- Yeah, I mean, Apple does this.
- 是的，我的意思是，苹果就是这样的。
I like I started in business school,
我喜欢我从商学院开始的，
Apple does competing product teams that operate as startups.
苹果有作为初创公司运作 的竞争产品团队。
So three to five people, they make something,
所以三到五个人，他们 做了一些东西，
they have multiple teams do make the same thing.
他们有多个团队做 同样的事情。
The best team wins.
最好的球队获胜。
I think you need to emulate
我认为你需要效仿
like a free market inside a company
就像公司内部的自由市场
to make it entrepreneurial.
使其具有创业精神。
- Yeah. - And you need
- 是的。 - 而你需要
entrepreneurial mentality in a company
公司的创业心态
to come up with new ideas and do it better.
提出新的想法并 做得更​​好。
- So one of the things you do really, really well is learn.
- 所以你做得非常非常好 的事情之一就是学习。
And you think like you're trying to...
而你认为你正试图...
You have an idea, you try to build it,
你有一个想法，你尝试去实现它，
and then you learn everything
然后你就学会了一切
you need to in order to build it.
你需要这样才能构建它。
You have your current skills,
你有你目前的技能，
but you need learn just the minimal amount of stuff.
但你只需要学习最 少量的东西。
So you're a good person to ask like,
所以你是一个很好的人，可以问这样的问题，
how do you learn?
你怎么学习？
How do you learn quickly and effectively
如何快速有效地学习
and just the stuff you need?
以及您需要的东西？
Just by way of example,
举例来说，
you did a 30 days learning session on 3D.
您参加了为期 30 天的 3D 学习课程。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Where you documented yourself,
- 你在哪里记录自己，
giving yourself only 30 days
只给自己30天的时间
to learn everything you can about 3D.
学习有关 3D 的一切知识。
- Yeah, I tried to learn virtuality
- 是的，我尝试学习虚拟技术
'cause I was like...
因为我就像...
This was same as AI,
这和AI一样，
it came up suddenly like 2016, 2017,
突然想到2016年、2017年，
with I think HTC VIVE,
我认为 HTC VIVE，
this big VR glasses before Apple Vision Pro.
Apple Vision Pro 之前 的这款大型 VR 眼镜。
I was like, oh, this is gonna be big,
我当时想，哦，这会很大，
so I need to learn this.
所以我需要学习这个。
I know nothing about 3D.
我对3D一无所知。
I installed like, I think Unity,
我安装了，我想Unity，
and Blender and stuff.
和搅拌机之类的东西。
And I started learning all this stuff
我开始学习所有这些东西
because I thought this was like a new
因为我觉得这就像一个新的
nascent technology that was gonna be big.
即将发展壮大的新兴技术。
And if I had the skills for it,
如果我有这方面的技能
I could use this to build stuff.
我可以用它来构建东西。
And so I think with learning for me,
所以我认为通过学习对我来说
I think learning is so funny
我觉得学习很有趣
'cause people always ask me,
因为人们总是问我，
"How do you learn to code?"
“你是如何学习编码的？”
Should I learn to code?"
我应该学习编码吗？”
And I'm like, "I don't know."
我说：“我不知道。”
Every day I'm learning.
我每天都在学习。
It's kind of cliche,
这有点陈词滥调
but every day I'm learning new stuff.
但每天我都在学习新东西。
So every day I'm searching on Google
所以我每天都在谷歌上搜索
or asking out ChatGPT,
或询问 ChatGPT，
how to do this thing, how to do this thing.
这件事怎么办， 这件事怎么办。
Every day, I'm getting better at my skill.
每一天，我的技能都在进步。
So you never stop learning.
所以你永远不会停止学习。
So the whole concept of like how do you learn?
那么整个概念就像 你如何学习？
Well, you never ends.
好吧，你永远不会结束。
So where do you want to be?
那么你想去哪里？
Do you wanna know a little bit?
你想知道一点吗？
Or do you wanna know a lot?
或者你想了解很多？
Do you wanna do it for your whole life?
你想一辈子这样吗？
So I think taking action is the best step to learn.
所以我认为采取行动 是学习的最佳步骤。
So making things like, you know nothing,
所以说，你什么都不知道，
just start making things.
开始做东西吧。
Okay, so like how to make a website?
好的，那么如何制作一个网站呢？
Search how to make a website.
搜索如何制作网站。
Or nowadays you ask ChatGPT,
或者现在你问 ChatGPT，
how do I make a website?
我如何制作一个网站？
Where do I start?
我从哪里开始？
It generates codes for you, right?
它会为您生成代码，对吗？
Copy the code, put it in a file, save it,
复制代码，将其放入文件中，保存，
open it in Google Chrome or whatever.
在 Google Chrome 或其他什么工具中打开它。
You have a website and then you start tweaking with it,
你有一个网站，然后 你开始调整它，
and you start, okay, how do I add a button?
然后你开始，好吧，我 如何添加一个按钮？
How do I add AI features, right, nowadays.
现在我该如何添加人工智能功能呢？
So it's like by taking action,
所以就像采取行动一样
you can learn stuff much faster than I'm reading books,
你学东西比 我看书快得多
or tutorials.
或教程。
- Actually, I'm curious, let me ask perplexity.
——其实我很好奇， 请问一下困惑。
How do I make a website?
如何创建网站？
I'm just curious what it would say.
我只是好奇它会说什么。
I hope it goes with like really basic vanilla solutions.
我希望它能与真正基本 的香草解决方案相匹配。
Define your website's purpose.
定义您网站的目的。
Choose a domain name.
选择一个域名。
Select a web hosting provider.
选择网络托管提供商。
Choose a website or builder or CMS,
选择网站、构建器或 CMS，
website build a platform Wix.
网站搭建平台Wix。
- Tells that Wix or Squarespace is what I said.
- 告诉我 Wix 或 Squarespace 就是我所说的。
- Yeah. - The landing page.
- 是的 。 - 登陆页面。
- How do I say if I wanna program it myself?
- 如果我想自己 编程，该怎么说？
Design your website, create essential pages.
设计您的网站， 创建必要的页面。
- Yeah, even tells you to launch it, right?
- 是的，甚至告诉你 启动它，对吧？
Start promoting it.
开始推广它。
- Launch your website. - Cool.
- 启动您的网站。 - 凉爽 的。
- Well, I mean you could do that.
- 嗯，我的意思是你可以做到。
- Yeah, but this is literally it.
- 是的，但这就是字面上的意思。
- [Lex] If you wanna make a website.
- [Lex] 如果你想制作一个网站。
- This is the basic like Google Analytics,
- 这是像Google Analytics这样的基本功能，
- Well, you can't make Nomad List with this way.
- 嗯，你不能用这种 方式制作Nomad List。
- You can. - With Wix.
- 你可以。 - 与维克斯。
- No, you can get pretty far, I think.
- 不，我认为你可以走得很远。
- You get pretty far. - These website builders
- 你已经走得很远了 。 - 这些网站建设者
are pretty advanced.
都相当先进。
All you need is a grid of images, right?
您所需要的只是图像网格，对吧？
- Yeah. - That are clickable.
- 是的 。 - 可点击的。
That open like another page.
就像打开另一页一样。
- Yeah. - You can get quite far.
- 是的。 - 你可以走得很远。
- How do I learn to program?
- 我如何学习编程？
Choose a programming language to start with.
选择一种编程语言 作为开始。
- Yeah, FreeCodeCamp is good.
- 是的，FreeCodeCamp 很好。
- Work through resources systematically,
- 系统地利用资源，
practice coding regularly for 30, 60 minutes a day.
每天定期练习编码 30、60 分钟。
Consistency is key.
一致性是关键。
Join programming communities like Reddit's.
加入 Reddit 等编程社区。
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
Yeah, it is pretty good.
是的，非常好。
- Yeah. - It's pretty good.
- 是的 。 - 非常好。
- So I think it's a very good starting ground,
- 所以我认为这是一个 非常好的起点，
'cause imagine you know nothing
因为想象你什么都不知道
and you wanna make a website,
你想建立一个网站，
you wanna make a startup.
你想创业。
This is like, that's why, man,
这就像，这就是为什么，伙计，
the power of AI for education is gonna be insane.
人工智能对教育 的力量将是疯狂的。
People anywhere can ask this question
任何地方的人都可以问这个问题
and start building stuff.
并开始构建东西。
- Yeah, it clarifies it for sure,
- 是的，它确实澄清了这一点，
and just start building.
并开始构建。
Like keep- - Yeah.
就像保持- - 是的。
- Build, build.
- 建造，建造。
Like actually apply the thing,
就像实际应用一样，
whether it's AI,
无论是人工智能，
or any of the programming for web development.
或任何用于网络开发 的编程。
- Yeah. - Just have a project in mind,
- 是的。 - 只要心中有一个项目，
which I love the idea of like 12 startups in 12 months
我喜欢在 12 个月内创办 12 家初创公司的想法
or like build a project almost every day.
或者几乎每天都构建一个项目。
- Yeah. - Just build a thing.
- 是的。 - 只是建造一个东西。
- And get it to work,
- 让它发挥作用，
and finish it every single day.
并每天完成它。
That's a cool experiment.
这是一个很酷的实验。
- I think that was the inspiration.
- 我认为这就是灵感。
There was a girl who did 160 websites
有一个女孩做了160个网站
and 160 days or something.
还有160天什么的。
Literally mini websites. - Yeah.
字面意思是迷你网站。 - 是 的。
- And she learned to code that way.
- 她学会了用这种方式编码。
So I think it's good to set yourself challenges.
所以我认为给自己设定 挑战是件好事。
You can go to some coding bootcamp,
你可以去一些编码训练营，
but I don't think they actually work.
但我认为它们实际上不起作用。
I think it's better to do,
我认为最好这样做
for me, how to deduct like self-learning
对于我来说，如何演绎就像自学一样
and setting yourself like challenges
并给自己设定挑战
and just getting in,
并且刚进去，
but you need discipline.
但你需要纪律。
You need to discipline to keep doing it.
你需要自律才能继续这样做。
And coding is very,
编码非常，
it's a steep learning curve to get in.
这是一个陡峭的学习曲线。
It's very annoying.
这很烦人。
Working with computers is very annoying.
使用计算机工作非常烦人。
So it can be hard for people to keep doing it.
因此，人们很难 继续这样做。
- Yeah, that thing of just keep doing it and don't quit,
- 是的，就是继续 做而不放弃，
that urgency that's required to finish a thing.
完成某件事 所需的紧迫感。
That's why it's really powerful when you documented this,
这就是为什么当你记录下来 时它真的很强大，
the creation of Hoodmaps
Hoodmaps的创建
or like a working prototype that there is
或者就像有一个工作原型
just a constant frustration I guess.
我想只是持续的挫败感。
It's like oh, okay, how do I do this?
就像哦，好吧，我该怎么做？
And then you look it up,
然后你查一下，
and you're like, okay,
你就像，好吧，
you have to interpret the different options you have.
你必须解释你所拥有 的不同选择。
- Yeah, man. - And then just try it,
- 是的，伙计 。 - 然后就试试吧
and then there's a dopamine rush of like,
然后多巴胺激增，
"Ooh, it works cool." - Man, it's amazing.
“噢，这很酷。” - 伙计，太棒了。
I live streamed it.
我现场直播了。
It's on YouTube and stuff.
它在 YouTube 等网站上。
People can watch it,
人们可以观看，
and it's amazing when things work.
当一切顺利时，真是太神奇了。
Look, it's just like a main that you,
看，这就像你的主菜一样，
I look very not...
我看起来很不...
I don't look far ahead.
我不看长远。
So I only look, okay, what's the next problem to solve,
所以我只是看看，好吧，下一 个要解决的问题是什么，
and then the next problem?
然后下一个问题是什么？
And at the end, you have a whole app
最后，你就有了一个完整的应用程序
or website or thing.
或网站或事物。
But I think most people look way too far ahead.
但我认为大多数人 都看得太远了。
It's like this poster again.
又像这张海报了。
You don't know hard it's gonna be,
你不知道这会很困难
so you should only look like
所以你应该看起来像
for the next thing,
对于接下来的事情，
the next little challenge, the next step.
下一个小挑战，下一步。
And then see where you end up.
然后看看你最终会在哪里。
- And as assume it's gonna be easy. (laughs)
- 假设这会很 容易。 （笑）
- Yeah, exactly.
- 是的，完全正确。
Be naive about it.
对此要天真。
Because you're gonna have very difficult problems.
因为你会遇到非常 困难的问题。
A lot of the big problems won't be even tech,
很多大问题甚至都 不是技术问题
will be like public, right?
会像公众一样，对吧？
Maybe people don't like your website.
也许人们不喜欢您的网站。
You will get canceled for a website, for example.
例如，您将被某个 网站取消。
A lot of things can happen.
很多事情都可能发生。
- What's it like building in public, like you do?
- 像你一样在公共场所建造 建筑是什么感觉？
Openly, where you're just iterating quickly
公开地，你只是 快速迭代
and you getting people feedback.
你会得到人们的反馈。
So there's the power of the crowdsourcing,
所以这就是众包的力量，
but there's also the negative aspects
但也有消极的方面
of people being able to criticize.
人们能够批评。
- So man, I think haters are actually good,
-所以，我认为仇恨者 实际上是好的，
'cause I think a lot of haters have good points.
因为我认为很多仇恨者 都有好的观点。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And it takes like stepping away from the emotion of like,
- 这需要远离 类似的情感，
ah, your website sucks because blah, blah, blah.
啊，你的网站很糟糕， 因为废话，废话，废话。
And you're like, okay, just remove this.
你会想，好吧，把它删除吧。
Your website sucks 'cause it's personal.
你的网站很糟糕，因为它是个人的。
What did he say?
他说什么？
Why did he didn't not like it?
为什么他不喜欢呢？
And you figure out, okay, he didn't like it
然后你就会发现， 好吧，他不喜欢这样
'cause the signup was difficult or something,
因为注册很 困难什么的
or it wasn't the data.
或者不是数据。
They say, no, this data is not accurate or something, right?
他们说，不，这个数据不准确 或者什么的，对吧？
Okay, I need to improve the quality of data.
好的，我需要提高 数据质量。
This hater has a point,
这位仇家说得有道理
because it's dumb to completely ignore your haters.
因为完全忽视你 的仇恨者是愚蠢的。
And also, man, I think I've been there
而且，伙计，我想我也去过那里
when I was like 10 years old or something.
当我10岁左右的时候。
You're on the internet just shouting crazy stuff
你在网上只 是大喊大叫
that's like most of Twitter,
就像 Twitter 上的大多数内容一样，
or the half Twitter.
或者半个推特。
So you have to take it with grain of salt.
所以你必须持保留态度。
Yeah, man, you need to grow a very thick skin
是的，伙计，你 的脸皮需要很厚
on Twitter, on X.
在 Twitter 上、在 X 上。
But I'm mute a lot of people.
但我却对很多人保持沉默。
I found out I muted already 15,000 people
我发现我已经将 15,000 人静音
recently, I checked.
最近，我查了一下。
So in 10 years, I muted 15,000 people.
所以在 10 年里，我让 15,000 人静音。
So that's like- - That's one by one manual.
这就像——这 是一本一本的手册。
- Yeah. - Oh, wow.
- 是的。 - 哦，哇。
- So 1,500 people per year.
- 所以每年有 1,500 人。
And I don't like to block, 'cause then they get angry,
我不喜欢阻止，因为 那样他们就会生气，
they make a screenshot and they say, ah, ah, you block me.
他们截图后说，啊 啊，你屏蔽我了。
So I just mute and it disappear
所以我只是静音然后它就消失了
and it's amazing.
这太棒了。
- So you mentioned Reddit.
- 所以你提到了Reddit。
So Hoodmaps, did that make it to the front page of Reddit?
那么 Hoodmaps 是否登上 了 Reddit 的首页？
- Yeah, yeah it did, yeah, yeah, yeah it did.
- 是的，是的，是的 ，是的，是的，是的。
It was amazing.
太棒了。
And my server almost went down,
我的服务器差点就瘫痪了
and I was checking like Google Analytics
我正在检查谷歌分析
was like 5,000 people on the website or something crazy.
网站上大概有 5,000 人，或者 有些疯狂的事情。
And it was at night and it was amazing.
那是在晚上，真是太棒了。
Man, I think nowadays, honestly, TikTok,
伙计，我认为现在，老实说，TikTok，
YouTube reels, Instagram reels.
YouTube 视频、Instagram 视频。
A lot of apps get very big from people
许多应用程序因人而变得非常大
making TikTok videos about it.
制作有关它的 TikTok 视频。
So let's say you make your own app,
假设您制作自己的应用程序，
you can make a video for yourself.
你可以为自己制作一个视频。
Oh, I made this app.
哦，我做了这个应用程序。
This is how it works, blah, blah, blah.
这就是它的工作原理，等等，等等。
And this is why I made it, for example.
例如，这就是我成功的原因。
And this is why you should use it.
这就是你应该使用它的原因。
And if it's a good video, we'll take off,
如果这是一个好视频，我们就会起飞，
and you will get, man, I got like $20,000 extra per month
你会得到，伙计，我每个月 额外得到大约 20,000 美元
or something from a TikTok from one TikTok video.
或者某个 TikTok 视频中 的 TikTok 内容。
It made a Photo AI.
它制作了照片人工智能。
- By you or somebody else? - By some random guy.
- 由你还是其他人？ - 某个随机的人。
So there's all these AI influencers that they write about.
所以他们写了所有 这些人工智能影响者。
They show AI apps and then they ask money later,
他们展示人工智能应用 程序，然后他们要钱，
like when a video goes viral.
就像视频疯传一样。
I can do it again, and send me $4,000 or something.
我可以再做一次，然后寄给 我 4,000 美元什么的。
I'm like, okay, I did that, for example.
我想，好吧，我就是这么做的，例如。
But it works.
但它有效。
TikTok is a very big platform for user acquisition, yeah.
是的，TikTok 是一个非常 大的用户获取平台。
And Organic, like the best user acquisition
和有机一样，最 好的用户获取
I think is Organic.
我认为是有机的。
You don't need to buy ads.
您不需要购买广告。
You probably don't have money when you start to buy ads.
当你开始购买广告时 ，你可能没有钱。
So use Organic or write a banger, tweet, right?
所以使用 Organic 或写一条 恶作剧、推文，对吧？
That's can make an app take off as well.
这也可以让应用程序起飞。
- Well, I mean yeah, fundamentally create cool stuff
- 嗯，我的意思是， 从根本上创造很酷的东西
and have just a little bit of a following
并且有一点点追随者
enough to like for the cool thing to be noticed.
足够喜欢让酷的 事情被注意到。
And then it becomes viral if it's cool enough.
如果它足够酷的话，它就会像 病毒一样传播开来。
- Yeah, and you don't need a lot of followers anymore
- 是的，你不再需要 很多追随者了
on X and a lot of platforms
在 X 和很多平台上
'cause TikTok X, I think in reels also,
因为 TikTok X，我认为也是在卷轴中，
they have the same algorithm now.
他们现在有相同的算法。
It's not about followers anymore,
这不再是追随者的问题
it's about they test your content on a small subset,
他们会在一小部分内容 上测试您的内容，
like 300 people.
大约300人。
If they like it,
如果他们喜欢的话，
it will gets tested to a thousand people and on and on.
它将接受一千人 的测试，等等。
So if the thing is good, it will rise anyway.
所以如果东西好的话，无论如何 它都会上涨。
It doesn't matter if you have half a million followers
即使你有五十万 粉丝也没关系
or a thousand followers or hundred.
或一千名追随者或一百名追随者。
- What's your philosophy of monetizing
- 您的盈利理念是什么
how to make money from the thing you build?
如何从你建造的 东西中赚钱？
- Yeah, so a lot of starters,
- 是的，有很多首发，
they do like free users.
他们确实喜欢免费用户。
So you could sign up
这样你就可以注册了
and could use an app for free, which is...
并且可以免费使用一个应用程序，这是......
It never worked for me well,
它对我来说从来没有效果，
because I think free users generally don't convert.
因为我认为免费用户 通常不会转化。
And I think if you have VC funding,
我认为如果你有风险投资资金
it makes sense to get free users,
获得免费用户是有意义的，
because you can spend your funding on ads
因为您可以将资金花在广告上
and you can get like millions of people come in predictably
你会发现数百万 人如期涌入
how much they convert
他们转化了多少
and give them like a free trial, whatever,
并给他们免费试用，无论如何，
and then they sign up.
然后他们就报名了。
But you need to have that flow worked out so well
但你需要很好地 解决这个流程
for you to make it work, that you need like...
为了让它发挥作用 ，你需要像......
It's very difficult.
这是非常困难的。
I think it's best to start
我认为最好开始
and just start asking people
然后开始询问人们
for money in the beginning.
一开始是为了钱。
So show your app,
所以展示你的应用程序，
what are you doing on your landing page?
您在目标网页上做什么？
Make a demo or whatever video.
制作演示或任何视频。
And then if you wanna use it, pay me money,
然后如果你想使用 它，请付钱给我，
pay $10, $20, $40.
支付 10 美元、20 美元、40 美元。
I would ask more than $10 per month.
我每月要价10美元以上。
Netflix, like $10 per month.
Netflix，每月 10 美元左右。
But Netflix is a giant company,
但 Netflix 是一家大公司，
they can afford to make it so cheap, relatively cheap.
他们有能力把它做得如此 便宜，相对便宜。
If you're an individual, like an indie hacker,
如果你是个人，比如 独立黑客，
you are making your own app.
你正在制作自己的应用程序。
You need to make like at least $30
你需要至少赚 30 美元
or more on a user to make it worthy for you.
或更多关于用户的信息 ，使其对您有价值。
You need to make money.
你需要赚钱。
- And it builds a community of people
- 它建立了一个人们的社区
that actually really care about the product.
实际上真正 关心产品。
- Also, yeah.
- 还有，是的。
Making a community, making a discord very normal now.
建立一个社区，让不和谐 现在变得很正常。
Every AI app has a discord and you have the developers
每个人工智能应用程序都有不 和谐之处，而且还有开发人员
and the users together in a discord,
和用户在一起不和谐，
and they talk about,
他们谈论，
they ask for features they build together.
他们要求提供共同构建的功能。
It is very normal now.
现在很正常。
And you need to imagine like if you're starting out,
你需要想象一下 ，如果你刚开始，
getting a thousand users is quite difficult,
获得一千个用户是 相当困难的，
getting a thousand pages is quite difficult.
获得一千页是相当 困难的。
And if you charge them like $30,
如果你向他们收费 30 美元
you have 30K a month,
你一个月有3万，
and it's a lot of money.
这是很多钱。
- That's enough to like- - Live a good life.
- 喜欢就够了- - 过上 美好的生活。
- Yeah, live a pretty good life.
- 是的，过着美好的生活。
I mean that could be a lot of costs associated with hosting.
我的意思是，这可能会产生 大量与托管相关的成本。
- Yeah, so that's another thing.
- 是的，那是另一回事了。
I make sure my profit margin are very high.
我确保我的利润率 非常高。
So I try to keep the cost very low.
所以我尽量将成本保持在很低的水平。
I don't hire people.
我不雇人。
I try to negotiate with AI vendors now,
我现在尝试和AI厂商谈判，
can you make it cheaper?
你能便宜点吗？
I discovered this, you can just email companies
我发现了这一点，你可以 只给公司发电子邮件
and say, "Can you give me discount?
并说：“你能给我折扣吗？
It's too expensive."
太贵了。”
And they say, "Sure, 50%."
他们说：“当然，50%。”
I'm like, "Wow, very good." (Lex laughs)
我说：“哇，非常好。” （ 莱克斯笑）
And I didn't know this, you can just ask.
而且这个我也不知道，你可以问一下。
And especially in like now it's kind of recession,
尤其是在现在这样 的经济衰退中，
you can ask companies like, I need a discount
你可以询问公司， 例如，我需要折扣
or I kind of need to like,
或者我需要喜欢，
you don't need to be asshole about it.
你不需要为此表现得混蛋。
Say, "I kind of need a discount
说：“我需要折扣
or I need to go maybe to another company,
或者我可能需要去另一家公司，
maybe discount here and there."
也许到处都有折扣。”
And they say, "Sure."
他们说：“当然。”
A lot of them will say yes.
他们中的很多人都会说是的。
Like 25% discount, 50% discounts,
比如25%折扣，50%折扣，
'cause you think the price on the website
因为你认为网站上的价格
is the price of the API or something.
是API的价格什么的。
It's not.
它不是。
- And also you're a public facing person.
- 而且你也是一个面向公众的人。
- Oh, that helps also.
- 哦，这也有帮助。
- And there's love and good vibes
- 还有爱和良好的氛围
that you put out into the world.
你向世界展示的东西。
You're actually legitimately
你实际上是合法的
trying to build cool stuff.
尝试构建很酷的东西。
So a lot of companies probably wanna associate with you
所以很多公司可能 想与你合作
because you're trying to do.
因为你正在努力做。
- Yeah, it's like a secret hack,
- 是的，这就像一个秘密黑客，
but I think even without- - Secret hack.
但我认为即使没有- - 秘密 黑客。
Be a good person.
做一个好人。
- It depends how much discount they will give.
- 这取决于他们 会给多少折扣。
They'll maybe give more,
他们也许会付出更多，
but you know that's why you should post on Twitter
但你知道这就是你应该 在 Twitter 上发帖的原因
so you get discounts maybe.
所以你也许会得到折扣。
(Lex and Pieter laughs)
（莱克斯和彼得笑了）
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是啊是啊。
And also when it's crowdsourced,
而且当它是众包的时候，
I mean paying does prevent spam
我的意思是付费确实可以防止垃圾邮件
or help prevent spam. - Also, yeah.
或帮助防止垃圾邮件。 - 还有，是的。
Yeah, it gives you high quality users.
是的，它给你带来了高质量的用户。
- High quality users. - Free users are sure,
- 高质量用户。 - 免费 用户可以放心，
but they're horrible.
但它们很可怕。
It's just like millions of people,
就像千百万人一样，
especially with AI startups, you get a lot of abuse.
尤其是对于人工智能初创公司来 说，你会受到很多谩骂。
So you get millions of people from anywhere
这样你就可以从任何 地方吸引数百万人
just abusing your app,
只是滥用你的应用程序，
just hacking it and whatever.
只是破解它等等。
- There's something on the internet.
- 互联网上有一些东西。
You mentioned like 4chan discovered Hoodmaps.
你提到 4chan 发现 了 Hoodmaps。
- Yeah, but I love 4chan.
- 是的，但我喜欢 4chan。
I don't love 4chan,
我不喜欢4chan
but you know what I mean, like they're so crazy,
但你知道我的意思 他们太疯狂了
especially back then.
尤其是那时候。
It's kind of funny what they do.
他们所做的事情有点有趣。
- I actually, what is it?
- 其实我，这是什么？
This new documentary on Netflix "Antisocial Network"
Netflix 的这部新纪录片 “反社交网络”
or something like that that was really-
或者类似的东西，那真的是-
- Interesting. - Was fascinating.
- 有趣的。 - 很迷人。
Just 4chan,
只要4chan，
the spirit of the thing, 4chan.
事物的精神，4chan。
- And people just understand 4chan.
- 人们只了解 4chan。
- It's so much about freedom
- 这非常关乎自由
and also like the humor involved
也喜欢其中的幽默
and fucking with the system and fucking, man.
他妈的系统和 他妈的，伙计。
- That's it.
- 就是这样。
It's just anti-system for fun.
这只是为了好玩而反系统。
- The dark aspect of it is you're having fun,
- 它的阴暗面是你 玩得很开心，
you're doing anti-system stuff,
你在做反系统的事情
but like the Nazis always show up
但就像纳粹总是出现一样
and it somehow- - Really bad shit
不知何故-- 真的很糟糕
started happening. - It drifting somehow, yeah.
开始发生。 - 它以 某种方式漂移，是的。
- It like school shootings and stuff.
- 就像校园枪击事件之类的。
So it's a very difficult topic,
所以这是一个非常困难的话题
but I do know, especially early on,
但我确实知道，尤其是在早期，
I think 2010, I would go to 4chan for fun,
我想2010年我会去4chan玩，
and they would post crazy offensive stuff.
他们会发布疯狂的攻击性内容。
And this was just to scare off people.
而这只是为了吓唬人。
So we show to other people say,
所以我们向其他人展示说，
"Hey, do you know this internet website 4chan?
“嘿，你知道这个互联网 网站 4chan 吗？
Just check it out." - Yeah. (laughs)
看看吧。” - 是 的。（笑）
- And they'd be, "Dude, what the fuck is that?"
- 他们会说，“伙计 ，那是什么鬼？”
I'm like, no, no, you don't understand.
我说，不，不，你不明白。
- Yeah. - That's to scare you away.
- 是的 。 - 那是为了吓跑你。
But actually when you go through scroll,
但实际上当你浏览滚动条时，
there's like deep conversations.
有类似深入的对话。
- Yes. - And they would already be,
- 是的 。 - 他们已经是，
this was like a normie filter,
这就像一个标准过滤器，
like to stop. - Yeah.
喜欢停下来。 - 是的。
- So kind of cool.
- 太酷了。
But yeah- - It goes dark.
但是，是的 ——天黑了。
- It goes dark, yeah.
-天黑了，是的。
- And if you have those people show up,
- 如果你让那些人出现，
for the fun of it, do a bunch of racist things
为了好玩，做一些 种族主义的事情
and all that kind of stuff you were saying.
以及你所说的所有 这些东西。
- Yeah, but everything is,
- 是的，但一切都是，
I think it was never,
我想从来没有，
man, I'm not at 4chan,
伙计，我不在 4chan，
but it was always about provoking.
但它总是与挑衅有关。
It's just provocateur.
这只是挑衅者。
- But the provoking in the case of Hoodmaps
- 但 Hoodmaps 的情况 却令人恼火
or something like this can- - Oh, man.
或者类似的东西可以--哦， 伙计。
- Can damage
- 会损坏
a good thing like (laughs)
像这样的好事（笑）
a little poison in a town is always good.
小镇里有一点毒总是好的。
It's like the Tom Waits thing,
就像汤姆·威茨的事一样
but you don't want too much
但你不想要太多
otherwise it destroys the town.
否则就会毁掉这座城镇。
It destroys the thing.
它毁掉了东西。
- Yeah, they're kind like pen testers,
- 是的，他们就像笔测试员一样友善，
like penetration testers,
就像渗透测试仪一样，
hackers. - Yeah.
黑客。 - 是 的。
- They just test your app for you
- 他们只是为您测试您的应用程序
and then you add some stuff,
然后你添加一些东西，
like I add like a NSFW word list.
就像我添加 NSFW 单词列表一样。
They would say like bad words.
他们会说脏话。
So when they would write like a bad words,
所以当他们写出类似脏话的时候，
they would get forwarded to YouTube,
他们会被转发到 YouTube，
which was like a video.
就像一个视频。
It was like a very relaxing video that like kind of ASMR
这就像一个非常轻松 的视频，有点像 ASMR
with like glowing jelly streaming like this to relax them,
像这样发光的果冻流 让他们放松，
or cheese melting on the toast.
或奶酪融化在面包上。
- Cheese melting, nice.
- 奶酪融化了，很好吃。
- And to chill them out. - Yeah, yeah.
- 让他们冷静下来。 - 是 啊是啊。
- I like it. - Yeah.
- 我喜欢它。 - 是的。
- But actually a lot of stuff I didn't realize
- 但实际上很多东西 我没有意识到
how much originated in 4chan in terms of memes.
就模因而言，有多少 起源于 4chan。
Rickroll, I didn't understand.
里克罗尔，我没听懂。
I did not know that Rickroll originated 4chan.
我不知道 4chan 是 Rickroll 创立的。
- Really? - There's so many memes,
- 真的吗 ？ - 有很多模因，
like most of the memes that you think-
就像你认为的大多数模因一样——
- The word roll I think comes from 4chan,
- 我认为roll这个词来自4chan，
like not the word roll, but in this case,
不像“卷”这个词，但在这种情况下，
in the meme use. - Yeah.
在模因使用中。 - 是的。
- You would get like roll doubles,
- 你会得到双打，
'cause there was like post IDs on 4chan.
因为 4chan 上有类似的帖子 ID。
So they were kinda like random.
所以它们有点像随机的。
So if I get doubles, this happens or something.
所以如果我得到双打，就会发生 这种情况或其他事情。
So you'd get like two, two.
所以你会得到两个，两个。
Anyway, it's like a betting market kind of on these doubles,
无论如何，这就像这些 双打的投注市场，
on these post IDs, this so much funny stuff.
在这些帖子 ID 上，有 很多有趣的东西。
- Yeah, I mean that's the internet, that's purist.
- 是的，我的意思是这就是 互联网，那是纯粹的。
But yeah, again, the dark stuff kind of seeps in.
但是，是的，黑暗的东西 又渗透进来了。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- It's nice to keep the dark stuff to some low amount.
- 将深色物质保持在较 低水平是件好事。
It's nice to have a bit of noise of the darkness,
能有一点黑暗的 噪音真是太好了
but not too much. - Yeah.
但也不过分。 - 是 的。
- But again, you have to pay attention to that with,
- 但同样，你必须 注意这一点，
I mean I guess spam in general.
我的意思是我猜一般都是垃圾邮件。
You have to fight that with Nomad List.
你必须用 Nomad List 来对抗这个问题。
How do you fight spam?
您如何对抗垃圾邮件？
- Man, I use GPT-4 now.
- 伙计，我现在使用 GPT-4。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
(laughs) So I have like user input have reviews,
（笑）所以我喜欢 用户输入的评论，
people can review cities.
人们可以评论城市。
And I don't need to actually sign up.
而且我不需要真正注册。
It's anonymous reviews.
都是匿名评论。
And they write whole books about cities
他们写了整本关于城市的书
and what's good and bad.
以及什么是好什么是坏。
So I run into GPT-4 now,
所以我现在遇到了 GPT-4，
and I ask like, "Is this a good review?
我会问，“这是一篇好的评论吗？
Is this offensive?
这是冒犯吗？
Is this race is this or some stuff?"
这场比赛是这个还是什么？”
And then send me message on Telegram
然后在 Telegram 上给我发消息
when it rejects reviews and I check it,
当它拒绝评论并且我检查它时，
and man, it's so on point.
伙计，这很重要。
It's so- - Automated.
它是如此 ——自动化。
- Yes, and it's so accurate.
- 是的，而且非常准确。
It understands double meanings.
它理解双重含义。
I have GPT-4 running on the chat community.
我在聊天社区 上运行 GPT-4。
It's a chat community of 10,000 people,
这是一个拥有10,000人的聊天社区，
and they're chatting,
他们正在聊天，
and they start fighting with each other.
他们开始互相争斗。
And I used to have human moderators was very good,
我曾经有人类 版主非常好，
but they would start fighting the human moderator.
但他们会开始与 人类主持人对抗。
This guy's biased or something.
这家伙有偏见什么的。
I have GPT-4.
我有 GPT-4。
And it's really, really, really, really good.
这真的非常非常 非常好。
It understands humor.
它懂得幽默。
It understands like you could say something bad,
它理解你可能会 说一些坏话，
but it's kinda a joke,
但这有点像玩笑
and it's kind of not offensive so much,
而且这并没有那么令人反感，
so it shouldn't be deleted, right?
所以应该不会被删除吧？
It understands that.
它明白这一点。
- I would love to have a GPT-4 based filter
- 我想要一个基于 GPT-4 的过滤器
of different kinds for like X.
像X这样的不同种类。
- Yeah, I thought this week like,
- 是的，我想这周就像，
I tweeted like a fact check.
我发推文就像进行事实核查一样。
You can click Fact Check and then GPT-4.
您可以单击“事实检查”，然后单击“GPT-4”。
Look, GPT-4 is not always right about stuff, right?
看，GPT-4 并不总是 正确的，对吧？
But it can give you a general fact check on a tweet.
但它可以让你对推文进行 一般事实检查。
Usually, what I do now when I write something like
通常，当我写类似的 东西时我现在会做什么
difficult about economics or something about AI.
经济学或人工智能 方面的困难。
I put in GPT-4 say, "Can you fact check it?"
我在 GPT-4 中输入“ 你能检查一下吗？”
'Cause I might have said something stupid.
因为我可能说了一些蠢话。
And the stupid stuff always gets taken out by the replies.
而且愚蠢的东西总是 会被回复删除。
Oh, you said this wrong.
噢，你说错了。
And then the whole tweet
然后是整条推文
kind of doesn't make sense anymore.
有点没有意义了。
So I ask GPT-4 the fact check a lot of stuff.
所以我要求 GPT-4 事实 检查很多东西。
- So fact check is a tough one.
- 所以事实核查是一项艰难的工作。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- But it would be interesting to sort of
- 但这会很有趣
rate a thing based on how well-thought out it is
根据一件事的深思熟虑 程度来评价它
and how well-argued it is.
以及它的论证有多么充分。
- Yeah. - That seems more doable.
- 是的 。 - 这似乎更可行。
That seems like more doable.
这似乎更可行。
It seems like a GPT thing
看起来像是 GPT 的东西
because that that's less about the truth
因为这与事实无关
and it's more about the rigor of the thing.
更重要的是事情 的严谨性。
- Exactly, and you can ask that,
- 确实如此，你可以问，
you can ask in the prompt like,
您可以在提示中询问，例如
I don't know, for example, do you think...
我不知道，例如，你认为...
Create like a ranking score for X Twitter applies
创建类似 X Twitter 的排名分数适用
where I should dispose be, if we rank on like,
如果我们排名相似， 我应该在哪里处置，
I dunno, integrity, reality,
我不知道，诚实，现实，
like fundamental deepness or something,
比如基础深度什么的，
interestingness.
趣味性。
And it will give you with a pretty good score probably.
它可能会给你一个 相当不错的分数。
I mean Elon can do this with Grok, right?
我的意思是 Elon 可以用 Grok 做到这一点，对吗？
He can start using that to check replies,
他可以开始用它来检查回复，
because the reply section is like chaos.
因为回复部分一片混乱。
- Yeah, and actually the ranking
- 是的，实际上是排名
and the replies is not great.
而且回复也不是很好。
- Doesn't make any sense. - Doesn't make sense.
- 没有任何意义。 - 没有道理。
- No. - And I would like to sort
- 不 。 - 我想排序
in different kinds of ways.
以不同的方式。
- Yeah, and you get too many replies now,
- 是的，你现在收到太多回复了，
if you have a lot of followers.
如果你有很多追随者。
I get too many replies.
我收到太多回复。
I don't see everything
我没有看到一切
and a lot of stuff I just miss
还有很多我想念的东西
and I wanna see the good stuff.
我想看到好东西。
- And also the notifications or whatever,
- 还有通知或其他什么，
is just complete chaos. - Yeah.
完全是一片混乱。 - 是 的。
- It'd be nice to be able to filter that
- 如果能够过滤的话那就太好了
in interesting ways,
以有趣的方式，
sorted in interesting ways.
以有趣的方式排序。
'Cause I feel like I miss a lot
因为我感觉我错过了很多
and what's surfaced for me is just a random comment
对我来说，这只是 一条随机评论
by a person with no followers.
由一个没有追随者的人。
- Yeah, yeah. - That's positive or negative.
- 是啊是啊。 - 这是积极的还是消极的。
It's like, okay,
就好像，好吧，
- If it's a very good comment, it should happen,
- 如果这是一个非常好 的评论，那就应该发生，
but it should probably look a little bit more,
但它可能看起来 应该多一点，
do these people have followers,
这些人有追随者吗
'cause they're probably more engaged in the platform, right?
因为他们可能更热衷于 这个平台，对吧？
- Oh, no.
- 哦，不。
I don't even care about how many followers.
我什至不在乎有 多少粉丝。
If you're ranking by the quality of the comment, great.
如果您按照评论的质量 进行排名，那就太好了。
- Yeah. - But not just randomly,
- 是的。 - 但不仅仅是随机的，
like chronological, just a sea of comments.
就像按时间顺序排列一样 ，只是大量的评论。
- Yeah, yeah, yeah, it does make sense.
- 是啊是啊，确实有道理。
- Yeah.
- 是的。 - 是的。
X could be very proof of that, I think.
我认为 X 可以很好地证明这一点。
- One thing you espouse a lot,
- 你非常拥护的一件事，
which I love is the automation step.
我喜欢的是自动化步骤。
So once you have a thing...
所以一旦你有事情...
Once you have an idea and you build it,
一旦你有了一个想法并付诸实践，
and it actually starts making money.
它实际上开始赚钱了。
And it's making people happy,
也让人们感到幸福，
there's a community of people using it.
有一个使用它的社区。
You want to take the automation step
您想要采取自动化步骤
of automating the things you have to do as little work
让你只需做很少的工作就 能完成的事情自动化
as possible for it to keep running indefinitely.
尽可能让它无限期 地运行。
- Yeah. - Can you explain
- 是的。 - 你能解释一下吗
your philosophy there?
你的哲学在那里？
What do you mean by automate?
你所说的自动化是什么意思？
- Yeah, so the general theory of starters would be
- 是的，所以初学者 的一般理论是
that when it starts, you start making money,
当它开始时，你 就开始赚钱，
you start hiring people to do stuff, right?
你开始雇人来做 事，对吗？
Do stuff that you, like marketing, for example.
做一些你喜欢的事情 ，例如营销。
Do stuff that you would do in the beginning yourself,
做你自己一开始 会做的事情，
and whatever community management
以及任何社区管理
and organizing meetups for Nomad List, for example,
并为 Nomad List 组织 聚会，例如，
that would be a job, for example.
例如，那将是一份工作。
And I felt like I don't have the money for that
我觉得我没有 钱这么做
and I don't really wanna run a big company
我真的不想经营一家大公司
with a lot of people,
和很多人一起，
'cause there's a lot of work managing these people.
因为管理这些人 有很多工作要做。
So I've always tried to automate these things
所以我一直尝试让 这些事情自动化
as much as possible.
尽量。
And this can literally be like for Nomad List,
这实际上就像 Nomad List 一样，
it's literally like a...
从字面上看，它就像一个...
It's not a different other sources.
这与其他来源没有什么不同。
It was like a webpage
就像一个网页
where you can organize your own meetup,
您可以在这里组织自己的聚会，
set a schedule, a date, whatever.
设定一个时间表，一个日期，等等。
You could see how many nomads will be there at that date.
你可以看到那天会 有多少游牧民。
So there will be actually enough nomads to meet up, right?
所以实际上会有足够 的游牧民见面，对吗？
And then when it's done,
然后当它完成后，
it sends a tweet out on the Nomad List account.
它在 Nomad List 帐户 上发送一条推文。
There's a meetup here.
这里有一个聚会。
It sends a direct message to everybody in the city
它向城市中的每个 人发送直接信息
who are there, who are gonna be there.
谁在那里，谁将在那里。
And then people show up on a bar and there's a meetup
然后人们出现在 酒吧，举行聚会
and that's fully automated.
这是完全自动化的。
And for me, it's so obvious to make this automatic,
对我来说，让这个自动化 是显而易见的，
why would you have somebody organize this?
你为什么要让人组织这个？
It makes more sense to automate it.
将其自动化更有意义。
And with most of my things,
我的大部分东西，
like I figure out how to do it with codes.
就像我弄清楚如何用代码来做一样。
And I think especially now with AI,
我认为尤其是现在有了人工智能，
you can automate so much more stuff than before.
你可以比以前自动化 更多的东西。
'Cause AI understands things so well.
因为人工智能非常了解事物。
Like before I would use if statements, right?
就像之前我会使用 if 语句 一样，对吗？
Now you ask GPT, you put something on GPT-4,
现在你问GPT，你在GPT-4 上放了一些东西，
and in the API and it sends back like,
在 API 中，它会发回如下内容：
this is good, this is bad.
这是好的，这是坏的。
- Yeah, so you basically can now even
- 是的，所以你现在基本上可以
automate sort of subjective type of things.
自动化一些 主观类型的事情。
This is the difference now. - Yeah.
这就是现在的区别。 - 是 的。
- And that's very recent, right?
- 那是最近的事，对吧？
- But it's still difficult to,
- 但还是很难，
I mean that's step of automation is difficult
我的意思是自动化 这一步很困难
to figure out how to...
弄清楚如何...
Is you're basically delegating everything to code.
您基本上是将所有 事情委托给代码。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And it's not trivial to take
- 这并不是一件小事
that step for a lot of people.
对于很多人来说这一步。
So when you say automate,
所以当你说自动化时
are you talking about like CronJob?
你是在谈论 CronJob 吗？
- Yes, man, a lot of CronJob.
- 是的，伙计，很多 CronJob。
- A lot of CronJobs. - Yeah.
- 很多 CronJobs。 - 是 的。
- I literally, I log into the server
- 我真的，我登录到服务器
and I do like sudo crontab-e,
我确实喜欢 sudo crontab-e,
and then I go into editor
然后我进入编辑器
and I write like hourly
我每小时写一次
and then I write PHP,
然后我写 PHP，
dothisthing.php, and that's a script.
dothisthing.php，这是一个脚本。
And that script does a thing and it does it then hourly.
该脚本会执行一件事，然后 每小时执行一次。
That's it.
就是这样。
And that's how all my websites work.
这就是我所有网站的运作方式。
- Do you have a thing where it like
- 你有喜欢的东西吗
emails you or something like this?
给你发电子邮件或类似的东西？
Or emails somebody managing the thing,
或者给管理此事的人发电子邮件，
if something goes wrong?
如果出了什么问题？
- I have these webpage that make,
- 我有这些网页，
they're called like healthchecks.
它们被称为健康检查。
It's like healthcheck.php,
就像healthcheck.php，
and then it has emojis,
然后它有表情符号，
it has a green check mark if it's good,
如果它是好的，它有一个绿色的复选标记，
and a read one if it's bad.
如果不好的话就读一读。
And then it does like database cures, for example.
例如，它确实像 数据库疗法一样。
Like what's the internet speed in, for example, Amsterdam.
例如，阿姆斯特丹的互联网 速度是多少。
Okay, it's a number.
好吧，这是一个数字。
It's like 27 point megabits.
相当于 27 点兆位。
So it's accurate number.
所以这是准确的数字。
Okay, check, good.
好的，检查一下，好的。
And it goes to the next,
然后它进入下一个，
and it goes on all the data points.
它适用于所有数据点。
Did people sign up in it last 24 hours?
过去 24 小时内有人注册吗？
It's important 'cause maybe the sign up broke.
这很重要，因为 注册可能会失败。
Okay, check, somebody sign up.
好的，检查一下，有人报名了。
Then I have uptimerobot.com,
然后我有 uptimerobot.com，
which is like for Uptime,
就像正常运行时间一样，
but it can also check keywords.
但它也可以检查关键字。
It checks for an emoji,
它检查表情符号，
which is like the red X,
就像红色的X，
which is if something is bad.
也就是说，如果有什么事情是坏的。
And so it opens that health check page every minute
所以它每分钟都会打开 健康检查页面
to check if something's bad.
检查是否有问题。
Then if it's bad,
那么如果情况不好的话
it sends a message to me on Telegram
它在 Telegram 上向我发送消息
saying, "Hey, what's up?"
说：“嘿，怎么了？”
Or it doesn't say, "Hey, what's up?"
或者它不会说：“嘿，怎么了？”
It sends me like alert. (Lex laughs)
它让我警觉起来。 （莱克斯 笑）
- Hey, hey, sweetie.
- 嘿，嘿，亲爱的。
- This thing is down and then I check.
- 这东西坏了，然后我检查一下。
So within a minute of something breaking,
所以在东西坏掉的一分钟之内
I know it and then I can open my laptop and fix it.
我知道了，然后我就可以打开 我的笔记本电脑并修复它。
- Yeah. - But the good thing is
- 是的 。 - 但好处是
like the last few years, things don't break anymore.
就像过去几年一样 ，事情不再破裂。
And definitely 10 years ago, when I started,
绝对是 10 年前， 当我开始时，
everything was breaking all the time.
一切都在不断地破裂。
And now it's like almost,
现在几乎就这样了
last week was like a 100.000% Uptime.
上周的正常运行时间约为 100.000%。
And these health checks are part of the Uptime percentage.
这些健康检查是正常运行 时间百分比的一部分。
So it's like everything works.
所以就好像一切正​​常。
- You're actually making me realize
- 你实际上让我意识到
I should have a page for myself.
我应该为自己设立一个页面。
Like one page that has all the healthchecks,
就像包含所有健康检查 的一页一样，
just so I can go to it
这样我就可以去
and see all the green check marks.
并看到所有绿色复选标记。
- It feels good to look at, you know.
- 看起来感觉很好，你知道。
- It just be like, okay. - Yeah.
- 就这样，好吧。 - 是 的。
- All right, we're okay.
- 好吧，我们没事。
Everything's okay. - Yeah.
一切都好。 - 是 的。
- And like you can see like,
- 就像你可以看到的那样，
when was the last time something wasn't okay,
上次出现问题 是什么时候
and it'll say like never. - Yeah.
它会说永远不会。 - 是 的。
- Or meaning like you've checked
- 或者就像你已经检查过的意思
since you've last cared to check, it's all been okay.
自从你上次关心检查 以来，一切都很好。
- For sure.
- 一定。
It used to send me the good healthchecks.
它曾经给我发送良好的健康检查。
- Yeah. - It all works, it all works.
- 是的。 - 一切都有效，一切都有效。
- But it's been- - It all works.
- 但它已经- - 一切 正常。
- [Lex] So often. (laughs)
- [莱克斯] 经常这样。 （笑）
- And I'm like, this feels so good.
- 我想，这感觉真好。
But then I'm like, okay, obviously, it's not gonna,
但后来我想，好吧 ，显然，这不会，
we need to hide the good ones and show only the bad ones,
我们需要隐藏好的 ，只显示坏的，
and now that's the case.
现在就是这样。
- I need to integrate everything into one place.
- 我需要将所有内容 整合到一个地方。
I automate like everything. - Yeah, yeah.
我喜欢一切自动化。 - 是 啊是啊。
- Also just a large set of CronJob.
- 也只是一大套 CronJob。
A lot of the publication of this podcast is done all,
这个播客的很多发布 都完成了，
everything's just on automatically,
一切都自动开启，
it's all clipped up.
一切都被剪掉了。
All this kind of stuff. - Wow, yeah.
所有这些东西。 - 哇 ，是的。
- But it would be nice to automate even more.
- 但如果能实现更多 自动化就更好了。
- Yeah. - Like translation,
- 是的。 - 就像翻译一样，
all this kind of stuff would be nice to automate.
所有这些东西如果能 实现自动化就好了。
- Yeah, every JavaScript,
- 是的，每个 JavaScript，
every PHP error gets sent to my Telegram as well.
每个 PHP 错误也会发送 到我的 Telegram。
So every user, whatever user it is,
所以每个用户，无论是什么用户，
doesn't have to be page user.
不必是页面用户。
If they run into a error,
如果他们遇到错误，
the JavaScript sends the JavaScript error to the server
JavaScript 将 JavaScript 错误发送到服务器
and then it sends to my Telegram, from all my websites.
然后它从我所有的 网站发送到我的电报。
- So you get like a message.
- 所以你会收到一条消息。
- So I get like a uncut, variable error,
- 所以我得到了一个未切割的、可变的错误，
whatever, blah, blah, blah.
无论如何，巴拉，巴拉，巴拉。
And then I'm like, "Okay, interesting."
然后我说，“好吧，有趣。”
And then I go check it out.
然后我就去看看。
And that's like a way to get to zero errors,
这就像一种实现 零错误的方法，
'cause you get flooded with errors in the beginning,
因为一开始你就会 被错误淹没，
and now it's like nothing almost.
现在几乎什么都没有了。
- So that's really cool.
- 所以这真的很酷。
That's really cool.
这真的很酷。
- But this is the same stuff people,
- 但这是同样的东西，人们，
they pay like very big SaaS companies.
他们像大型 SaaS 公司一样付费。
New Relic for right?
新遗迹对吗？
To manage this stuff.
来管理这些东西。
So you can do that too.
所以你也可以这样做。
You can use off the shelf.
您可以使用现成的。
I like to build myself.
我喜欢打造自己。
It's easier. - Yeah, it's nice.
更容易了。 - 是的，这很好。
It's nice to do that kind of automation.
进行这种自动化真是太好了。
I'm starting to think of like,
我开始想，
what are the things in my life
我的生活中有哪些事情
I'm doing myself that could be automated
我正在做自己可以自动化的事情
in addition.
此外。
- You can ask GPT, give your daily your day
- 你可以问GPT，给你的 每一天你的一天
and then ask you what parts you to automate.
然后问你要自动化 哪些部分。
- Well, one of the things I would love to automate more
- 嗯，我希望自动化程度 更高的事情之一
is my consumption and social media.
是我的消费和社交媒体。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Both the output and the input.
- 输出和输入。
- Man, I think there's some startups that do that.
- 伙计，我认为有一些 初创公司这样做。
They summarize the cool shit happening on Twitter,
他们总结了 Twitter 上 发生的很酷的事情，
with AI, I think the guy called SWYX or something,
对于人工智能，我认为 那个叫 SWYX 之类的人，
he does like a newsletter that's completely AI generated.
他确实喜欢完全由人工 智能生成的时事通讯。
We have the cool new stuff in AI.
我们在人工智能领域拥有很酷的新东西。
- Yeah, I mean I would love to do that.
- 是的，我的意思是我很乐意这样做。
But also like across Instagram, Facebook-
但也像 Instagram、Facebook 一样 -
- Yeah. - LinkedIn.
- 是的。 - 领英。
- All this kind of stuff.
- 是的 。 - 所有这些东西。
Just like, okay,
就像，好吧，
can you summarize the internet for me
你能为我总结一下互联网吗
(Pieter chuckles) For today?
（彼得笑了） 今天？
- Summarize internet.com. - Yeah, dot com.
- 总结 internet.com。 - 是 的，.com。
- Yeah. - Because I feel like
- 是的 。 - 因为我觉得
it pulls into way too much time,
它花费了太多的时间，
but also like, I don't like the effect it has
但也喜欢，我不 喜欢它的效果
some days on my psyche.
有些天在我的心灵上。
- Because of like haters
- 因为同样的仇恨者
or just general content and politics?
或者只是一般内容和政治？
- Just general.
- 只是一般。
No, no, just general.
不不不，只是一般。
Like for example, TikTok is a good example of that for me.
对我来说，TikTok 就是 一个很好的例子。
I sometimes just feel dumber after I use TikTok.
使用 TikTok 后，我有时 会觉得自己更蠢了。
I just feel like-
我只是觉得——
- [Pieter] Yeah, I don't use it anymore.
- [Pieter] 是的，我不再使用它了。
- Empty somehow and I'm like uninspired.
- 不知怎的，我很空虚，就像没有灵感一样。
- Yeah. - It's funny
- 是的。 - 很有趣
in the moment I'm like,
此刻我就像
ha-ha, look at that cat doing a funny thing.
哈哈，看那只猫在做一 件有趣的事情。
And then you're like,
然后你就像，
oh, look at that person dancing
哦，看看那个人跳舞
in a funny way to that music.
以一种有趣的方式配合音乐。
And then you're like,
然后你就像，
10 minutes later you're like, I feel way dumber
10分钟后，你会 觉得我变笨了
and I don't really wanna do much.
我真的不想做太多事。
- Yeah. - For the rest of the day.
- 是的。 - 今天剩下的时间。
- My girlfriend said,
- 我女朋友说，
she saw me like watching some dumb video.
她看到我就像在看一些愚蠢的视频。
She's like, "Dude, your face looks so dumb as well."
她说：“伙计，你的 脸看起来也很蠢。”
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
Your whole face starts going like, oh, interesting.
你的整个脸开始 变得，哦，有趣。
- I mean with social media,
- 我的意思是通过社交媒体，
with X sometimes for me too,
有时我也和X一起，
I think I'm probably naturally
我想我可能是天生的
gravitating towards the drama.
偏向戏剧。
- Yeah, hard wheel.
- 是的，硬轮。
- Yeah, and so with following AI people,
- 是的，下面的人工智能人也是如此，
especially AI people that only post technical content
尤其是只发布技术 内容的AI人
and it's been really good,
而且这真的很好，
'cause then I just look at them,
因为那时我只是看着他们，
and then I go on down rabbit holes
然后我继续往兔子洞里走
of like learning new papers that have been published
就像学习已发表 的新论文
or- - Yeah.
或者 - - 是的。
- Git repos,
- Git 存储库，
or just any kind of cool demonstration of stuff
或者只是任何很 酷的东西演示
and the kind of things that they retweet.
以及他们转发的内容。
And that's the rabbit hole I go and I'm learning
这就是我去的兔子洞 ，我正在学习
and I'm inspired, all that kind of stuff.
我受到了诸如此类的启发。
But it's been tough.
但这很艰难。
It's been tough to control that.
很难控制它。
- It's difficult.
- 它很难。
You need to like manage your platforms.
您需要喜欢管理您的平台。
I have a mute board list as well,
我也有一个静音板列表，
so I mute like politics stuff,
所以我对政治之类的事情保持沉默，
'cause I don't really want it on my feed.
因为我真的不想让它出现在我的饲料中。
And I think I've muted so much that now my feed is good.
我想我已经静音了很多 ，所以现在我的提要很好。
I see interesting stuff, (Lex laughs)
我看到了有趣的东西，（ 莱克斯笑）
but the fact that you need to modify,
但事实上你需要修改，
you need to like mod your app,
你需要喜欢修改你的应用程序，
your social media platform- - Yeah.
你的社交媒体平台- - 是 的。
- Just to function and not be toxic for you,
- 只是为了发挥作用 而不是对你有毒，
for your mental health, right?
为了你的心理健康，对吗？
That's like a problem.
这就像一个问题。
It should be doing that for you.
它应该为您做到这一点。
- It's some level of automation
- 这是一定程度的自动化
that would be interesting.
那会很有趣。
I wish I could access X and Instagram through API easier.
我希望我可以通过 API 更 轻松地访问 X 和 Instagram。
- You need to spend $42,000 a month,
- 你每月需要花费42,000美元，
which my friends do.
我的朋友们就是这么做的。
Yeah, you can do that.
是的，你可以这样做。
- But still, even if you do that,
- 但即使你这么做了
that you're not getting,
你没有得到的，
I mean there's limitations
我的意思是有限制
that don't make it easy to do like-
这并不容易做到-
- Yeah. - Automate.
- 是的。 - 自动化。
The thing that they're trying to limit,
他们试图限制的事情，
like abuse or for you to steal all the data
例如滥用或让您 窃取所有数据
from the app to then train an LLM,
从应用程序中培训法学硕士，
or something like this. - Yeah.
或类似的东西。 - 是 的。
- But if I just wanna figure out ways
- 但如果我只是想找出办法
to automate my interaction with the X system,
自动化我与 X 系统 的交互，
or with Instagram, they don't make that easy.
或者使用 Instagram，他们不 会让这一切变得容易。
But I would love to sort of automate that
但我很想自动化
and explore different ways to how to leverage LLMs
并探索如何利用法学 硕士的不同方法
to control the content I consume,
控制我消费的内容，
and maybe publish that
也许会发布那个
and maybe they themselves can see how
也许他们自己能明白如何
that could be used to improve their system.
可以用来改进 他们的系统。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- But there's not enough access.
- 但没有足够的访问权限。
- Yes, if you could screen cap your phone, right?
- 是的，如果你可以屏蔽 你的手机，对吗？
It could be an app that watches your screen with you.
它可能是一个可以与您 一起观看屏幕的应用程序。
- You could, yeah.
- 你可以，是的。
- But I don't even know like what it would do.
- 但我什至不知道 它会做什么。
Maybe it's can hide stuff before you see it.
也许它可以在你看到 之前隐藏一些东西。
Scroll down. - I have that,
向下滚动。 - 我有那个，
I have Chrome extensions.
我有 Chrome 扩展程序。
I write a lot of Chrome extensions
我写了很多 Chrome 扩展
that hide parts of different pages and so on.
隐藏不同页面 的部分等等。
- Yeah. - For example,
- 是的 。 - 例如，
on my main computer, I hide all views and likes
在我的主计算机上，我 隐藏了所有视图和喜欢
and all that on YouTube content that I create.
以及我创建的 YouTube 内容 中的所有内容。
So that I don't- - Smart, doesn't affect you.
这样我就不会 - - 聪明，不会影响你。
- It doesn't, yeah.
- 不是的，是的。
So you don't pay attention to it.
所以你不去关注它。
- Yeah. - I also hide parts there.
- 是的。 - 我也把零件藏在那里。
I have a mode for X where I hide most of everything.
我有一个 X 模式，可以 隐藏大部分内容。
So there's no, it's same with YouTube.
所以没有，YouTube 也一样。
- I have the same, I have this extension.
- 我有同样的，我有这个扩展。
- Well, I wrote my own 'cause it's easier.
- 嗯，我自己写的，因为它更容易。
- Yeah. - 'Cause it keeps changing.
- 是的。 - 因为它一直在变化。
It's not easy to keep it dynamically changing,
保持动态变化 并不容易，
but they're really good at like getting you to be distracted
但他们真的很擅长 让你分心
and like starting to- - Related accounts,
并且喜欢开始- - 相关帐户，
related post. - Related stuff.
相关帖子。 - 相关的东西。
- I'm like, I don't want related.
- 我想，我不想有关系。
- And like 10 minutes later you're like,
- 大概 10 分钟后你就会想，
or something that's trending.
或者一些流行的东西。
I have a weird amount of friends addicted to YouTube,
我有很多朋友 沉迷于 YouTube，
and I'm not addicted.
我没有上瘾。
I think 'cause my attention span is too short for YouTube.
我想是因为我对 YouTube 的 注意力持续时间太短了。
(Lex and Pieter laughs)
（莱克斯和彼得笑了）
But I have this extension to like YouTube Unhook,
但我有这个扩展来喜欢 YouTube Unhook，
which it hides all the related stuff.
它隐藏了所有相关的东西。
I can just see the video and it's amazing.
我只能看视频，这太棒了。
But sometimes I need to like,
但有时我需要喜欢，
I need to search a video how to do something.
我需要搜索视频如何 做某事。
And then I go to YouTube
然后我就去 YouTube
and then I had these YouTube shorts.
然后我就有了这些 YouTube 短片。
These YouTube shorts are like,
这些 YouTube 短片就像，
they're algorithmically designed
它们是通过算法设计的
to just make you tap them.
只是让你点击它们。
And I tap and I then I'm like five minutes later,
然后我点击， 五分钟后，
with this face,
有了这张脸，
and you're just stuck.
而你就被困住了。
And it's like, what happened?
就像，发生了什么事？
I was gonna open,
我正要打开，
I was gonna play like the coffee mix,
我本来想像混合咖啡一样演奏
the music mix for drinking coffee together
一起喝咖啡的音乐组合
in the morning, like jazz,
早晨，像爵士乐一样，
I didn't wanna go to shorts.
我不想穿短裤。
So it's very difficult.
所以这是非常困难的。
- I love how we're actually highlighting
- 我喜欢我们实际强调的方式
all kinds of interesting problems
各种有趣的问题
that all could be solved at a startup.
这一切都可以在启动时解决。
Okay, so what about the exit?
好吧，那么出口呢？
When and how to exit?
何时以及如何退出？
- Man, you shouldn't ask me
- 伙计，你不应该问我
'cause I never sold my company,
因为我从未卖掉过我的公司
and I've- - So you've never...
而且我- - 所以你从来没有...
All the successful stuff you've done,
你所做的所有成功的事情，
you've never sold it.
你从来没有卖过它。
- Yeah, it's kind of sad, right?
- 是的，这有点悲伤，对吧？
So I've been in a lot of acquisition like deals and stuff,
所以我参与了很多 收购，比如交易之类的，
and I learned a lot about finance people as well there,
我在那里也学到了很多 关于财务人员的知识，
like manipulation and due diligence
比如操纵和尽职调查
and then changing the valuation.
然后改变估值。
People change the valuation after.
人们在之后改变了估值。
A lot of people string you on to acquire you
很多人都拉着 你来获取你
and then it takes six months.
然后需要六个月的时间。
It's a classic.
这是一个经典。
It takes six to 12 months.
需要六到十二个月的时间。
They wanna see everything.
他们想看到一切。
They wanna see your Stripe and your code and whatever.
他们想看到你的 Stripe 和你的代码等等。
And then in the end, they'll change the price to lower,
最后，他们会将 价格降低，
'cause you're already so invested.
因为你已经如此投入了。
So it's a negotiation tactic, right?
所以这是一种谈判策略，对吗？
I'm like, no, then I don't want to sell, right?
我想，不，那我 不想卖，对吧？
And the problem with my companies is like,
我的公司面临的问题是，
they make 90% profit margin.
他们的利润率为 90%。
So the multiple,
所以多重，
companies get sold with multiples,
公司以倍数出售，
kind of multiples of profit or revenue.
利润或收入的倍数。
And often the multiple is like three times,
通常倍数是 三倍，
three times or four times
三四次
or five times revenue or profit.
或收入或利润的五倍。
So in my case, they're all automated.
所以就我而言，它们都是自动化的。
So I might as as well wait three years
所以我还不如等三年
and I get the same money as when I sell
我得到的钱和我卖的钱一样
and then I can still sell the same company.
然后我仍然可以出售 同一家公司。
You know what I mean?
你知道我的意思？
I can still sell for three, five times.
我还能卖三五倍。
So financially, it doesn't really make sense to sell.
所以从经济角度来说， 出售并没有什么意义。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Unless the price high enough.
- 除非价格足够高。
If the price gets to six or seven or eight,
如果价格达到 六、七、八，
I don't wanna wait six years for the money.
我不想等六年 才拿到钱。
But if you give me three,
但如果你给我三个
like three years is nothing.
三年好像没什么。
I can wait.
我可以等。
- So that means they're really valuable stuff
- 所以这意味着它们是 非常有价值的东西
about the companies you created
关于您创建的公司
is not just the interface
不仅仅是界面
and the crowdsource content,
和众包内容，
but the people themselves, like the user base.
而是人们本身，比如 用户群。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
So Nomad List, it's a community, yeah.
所以Nomad List，它是一个社区，是的。
- So I could see that being extremely valuable.
- 所以我可以看到 这是非常有价值的。
- Yeah. - I'm surprised that has not.
- 是的。 - 我很惊讶事实并非如此。
- But Nomad List,
- 但是游牧名单，
it's like my baby.
这就像我的孩子。
It's like my first project I took off,
这就像我开始的第一个项目
and I don't really know if I wanna sell it.
我真的不知道我是否 想卖掉它。
It's like something you- - Yeah.
这就像你--是的 。
- Would be nice when you're old
- 当你老了的时候会很好
to just still work on this.
仍然致力于此。
It has like a mission,
它就像一个使命，
which is like people should travel anywhere
这就像人们应该 去任何地方旅行
and they can work from anywhere
他们可以在任何地方工作
and they can meet different cultures.
他们可以遇到不同的文化。
And that's a good way to make the world get better.
这是让世界变得 更好的好方法。
If you go to China and live in China,
如果你去中国并且住在中国，
you'll learn that they're nice people.
你会发现他们都是好人。
And a lot of stuff you hear about China's propaganda,
你听到很多关于中国 宣传的东西，
a lot of stuff is true as well.
很多事情也是真的。
But it's more, you know, you learn a lot from traveling.
但更重要的是，你知道，你可以 从旅行中学到很多东西。
And I think that's why it's a cool product to not sell.
我认为这就是为什么它是一个 很酷的产品但不卖的原因。
AI products, I have less emotional feeling
AI产品，我的情感感受较少
with AI products like photo AI, which I could sell, yeah.
像照片人工智能这样的人工智能 产品，我可以出售，是的。
- Yeah, the thing you also mentioned is you have to
- 是的，你也提到 了你必须这样做
price in the fact that you're going to miss.
价格是你会错过 的事实。
- Yeah. - The company you created.
- 是的 。 - 你创建的公司。
- And the meaning it gives you, right?
- 它给你带来的意义，对吗？
There's a very famous depression
有一种非常著名的抑郁症
after start finding a solar company.
之后开始寻找一家太阳能公司。
They're like, this was me.
他们就像，这就是我。
Like who am I?
比如我是谁？
And they immediately start building another one.
他们立即开始建造 另一座。
(Lex laughs) They never can stop.
（莱克斯笑） 他们永远都停不下来。
So I think it's good to keep working until you die.
所以我认为继续工作 直到死是件好事。
Just keep working on cool stuff
继续做很酷的事情
and you shouldn't retire.
你不应该退休。
I think retirement's bad probably.
我认为退休可能很糟糕。
- So you usually build this stuff solo and mostly work solo.
- 所以你通常会单独构建这些东西 ，并且大部分时间都是单独工作。
What's the thinking behind that?
这背后的想法是什么？
- I think I'm not so good working with other people.
- 我认为我不太擅长 与其他人合作。
Not like I'm crazy, but I don't trust other people.
不是我疯了，而是 我不相信别人。
- To clarify,
- 澄清一下，
you don't trust other people to do a great job.
你不相信其他人 能把工作做好。
- Yeah, and I don't wanna have this consensus meeting
- 是的，我不想召开 这个共识会议
where we all like,
我们都喜欢的地方，
you have a meeting of three people
你有一个三人会议
and then you kind of get this compromise results,
然后你就会得到这个 妥协的结果，
which is very European.
这是非常欧洲的。
In Holland, we call pull them whatever.
在荷兰，我们称它们为“拉扯”。
You put people the room and you only let 'em out
你把人安排在房间里 ，然后只让他们出去
when they agree on the compromise, right?
当他们就妥协达成一致时，对吗？
In politics.
在政治上。
I think it breeds like averageness,
我认为它就像平均水平一样，
you get an average idea, average company, average culture,
你会得到一个普通的想法、普通 的公司、普通的文化，
you need to have a leader or you need to be solo
你需要有一个领导者，或者 你需要独自一人
and just do it, do it yourself, I think.
我想，就去做吧，你自己做吧。
And I trust some people,
我相信一些人，
now with my best friend Andre,
现在和我最好的朋友安德烈，
I'm making a new AI startup.
我正在创办一家新的人工智能初创公司。
But it's because we know each other very long
但那是因为我们 认识很久了
and he's one of the few people I would build something with
他是少数几个我愿意 与之合作的人之一
but almost never, yeah.
但几乎从来没有，是的。
- So what does it take to be successful
- 那么怎样才能成功呢
when you have more than one?
当你有不止一个的时候？
How do you build together with Andre?
你如何与安德烈一起建设？
How do you build together with other people?
你如何与其他人 一起建设？
- So he codes, I should post on Twitter.
- 所以他编码，我应该在 Twitter 上发布。
Literally, I promoted on Twitter.
从字面上看，我在 Twitter 上进行了宣传。
We set product strategy.
我们制定产品策略。
I said, this should be better, this should be better.
我说，这个应该更 好，这个应该更好。
But I think you need to have one person coding it.
但我认为你需要 一个人来编码。
He codes in Ruby so was like cannot do Ruby,
他用 Ruby 编写代码，所以 好像无法使用 Ruby，
I'm in PHP.
我是用PHP的。
- So have you ever coded with another person
- 那么你有没有和另一 个人一起编码过
for prolonged periods of time?
长时间？
- Never in my life.
- 从来没有在我的生活中。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
- What do you think is behind that?
- 你认为这背后的原因是什么？
- I know it was always just me sitting on my laptop,
- 我知道一直只有我坐 在笔记本电脑上，
like coding.
就像编码一样。
- No, like you've never had another developer
- 不，就像你从未有过 其他开发人员一样
who like rolls in and like?
谁喜欢滚进来并喜欢？
- I've had once with Photo AI,
- 我曾经用过Photo AI，
there's an AI developer, Philip,
有一位人工智能开发者 Philip，
I hired him to do the...
我雇他来做...
'Cause I can't write Python.
因为我不会写Python。
- Yeah. - And AI stuff is Python.
- 是的。 - 人工智能的东西就是Python。
And I needed to get models to work and replicate and stuff.
我需要让模型发挥作用 并进行复制等等。
And I needed to improve Photo AI.
我需要改进照片人工智能。
And he helped me a lot for 10 months he worked,
他工作的10个月里 给了我很多帮助，
and man, I was trying Python working with NumPy,
我正在尝试将 Python 与 NumPy 一起使用，
and package manager and it was too difficult for me
和包管理器，这对 我来说太难了
to figure this shit out.
来解决这个问题。
And I didn't have time.
我没有时间。
I think 10 years ago I would've time to sit,
我想十年前我会 有时间坐下来
go do all-nighters to figure this stuff out with Python.
通宵达旦地用 Python 来 解决这个问题。
I don't have the...
我没有那个...
It's not my thing,
这不是我的事
- But it's not your thing.
- 但这不关你的事。
It's another programming language, I get it.
这是另一种编程语言 ，我明白了。
AI, new thing, got it.
人工智能，新事物，明白了。
But you never had a developer roll in,
但你从来没有开发人员介入，
look at your PHP, jQuery code and yes,
看看你的 PHP、jQuery 代码，是的，
like in conversation or improv-
就像在谈话或即兴表演中
- Yeah. - They talk about yes,
- 是的。 - 他们谈论的是，
and, like basically, alright.
基本上，好吧。
- I had for one week. - Understand.
- 我用了一个星期。 - 理解。
- And that ended.
- 就这样结束了。
- What happened?
- 发生了什么？
- Because he wanted to rewrite everything in the-
- 因为他想重写 里面的一切-
- No, that's the wrong guy.
- 不，那是错误的人。
- I know. - He wanted to rewrite
- 我知道 。 - 他想重写
and what?
还有什么？
- He wanted to rewrite,
- 他想重写，
he said this jQuery, we cannot do this.
他说这个jQuery，我们不能这样做。
I'm like, okay.
我想，好吧。
He's we need to rewrite a thing in Vue, vue.js
他是我们需要在Vue中重 写一个东西，vue.js
I'm like, "Are you sure?
我说：“你确定吗？
Can we just like, you know, keep jQuery?"
我们可以保留 jQuery 吗？”
He's like, "No, man."
他说：“不，伙计。”
And we need to change a lot of stuff.
我们需要改变很多东西。
And I'm like, "Okay."
我说：“好吧。”
And I was kinda feeling it like this,
我有点像这样的感觉，
you know, we're gonna clean up shit.
你知道，我们要清理垃圾。
But then after week,
但一周后，
this is gonna take way too much time.
这会花费太多时间。
- I think I like working with people
- 我想我喜欢与人一起工作
where when I approach them,
当我接近他们时，
I pretend in my head
我在心里假装
that they're the smartest person who has ever existed.
他们是有史以来 最聪明的人。
- Wow. - So I look at their code
- 哇。 - 所以我看看他们的代码
or I look at the stuff they've created
或者我看看他们创造的东西
and try to see the genius of their way.
并尝试看看他们的方式的天才之处。
You really have to understand people,
你真的要理解人，
like really notice them.
喜欢真正注意到他们。
And then from that place have a conversation
然后从那个地方 进行对话
about what is the better approach.
关于什么是更好的方法。
- Yeah, but those are the top tier developers.
- 是的，但那些 是顶级开发商。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- Those are the ones that are tech ambiguous.
- 这些是技术上 含糊不清的。
So they can work with,
所以他们可以与，
they can learn any tech stack
他们可以学习任何技术堆栈
and they can- - Yeah.
他们可以--是 的。
- And that's like really few,
- 这真的很少，
it's like- - Really?
就像--真的 吗？
- Top 5%. - Damn.
- 前 5%。 - 该死。
- Because if you try higher devs,
- 因为如果你尝试更高的开发，
no offense to devs, but most devs are not.
无意冒犯开发者，但大多数开发者并非如此。
Man, most people in general jobs are not so good at the job,
伙计，大多数从事一般工作 的人都不太擅长这项工作，
even doctors and stuff. - That's too sad.
甚至医生之类的。 => - 这太悲伤了。
- When you realize this,
- 当你意识到这一点时，
people are very average at the job.
人们的工作表现很一般。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Especially with dev with coding, I think.
- 我认为尤其是对于 编码开发人员。
So sorry for-
非常抱歉-
- I think that's a really important skill
- 我认为这是一项非常重要的技能
for a developer to roll in
让开发人员加入
and understand the musicality, the style.
并了解音乐性和风格。
- That's it, man.
- 就是这样，伙计。
Empathy, it's like code empathy, right?
同理心，就像代码同理心，对吧？
- It's code empathy.
—— 这是代码同理心。
- Yeah, it's new word, but that's it.
- 是的，这是新词，但就是这样。
You need to understand,
你需要明白，
go over the code, get a holistic view of it
仔细检查代码 ，全面了解它
and man, you can suggest we change stuff, for sure.
伙计，你当然可以建议 我们改变一些东西。
And look, jQuery is crazy.
你看，jQuery 太疯狂了。
It's crazy, I'm using jQuery.
太疯狂了，我正在使用 jQuery。
We can change that.
我们可以改变这一点。
- It's not crazy at all.
- 这一点也不疯狂。
jQuery is also beautiful- - Yeah.
jQuery 也很漂亮- - 是 的。
- And powerful,
- 而且强大，
and PHP is beautiful and powerful.
PHP 既美观又强大。
Especially as you said recently,
尤其是你最近说的，
as the versions evolved,
随着版本的演变，
it's much more serious programming language now.
现在它是一种更加 严肃的编程语言。
It's super fast. - For sure.
速度超级快。 - 一定。
- Like PHP is really fast now.
- PHP 现在真的很快。
- Yeah, yeah, yeah. - It's crazy JavaScripts-
- 是啊，是啊，是啊 。 - 这是疯狂的 JavaScript -
- Much faster than Ruby, yeah.
- 比 Ruby 快得多，是的。
- Really fast now. - Yeah.
- 现在真的很快。 - 是 的。
- So if speed is something you care about,
- 所以如果你关心速度，
it's super fast. - Yeah.
速度超级快。 - 是 的。
- And there's gigantic communities of people-
- 还有巨大的 人群社区 -
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Using those program languages,
- 使用这些程序语言，
and there's frameworks if you like the framework.
如果你喜欢框架的话 ，还有框架。
So whatever, it doesn't really matter what you use,
所以无论如何，你 用什么并不重要，
but also you, if I was like a developer working with you,
还有你，如果我像一个与 你一起工作的开发人员，
like you are extremely successful.
就像你非常成功一样。
You've shipped a lot. - Yeah.
你已经发货很多了- 是 的。
- So like if I roll in, I'm gonna be like,
- 所以如果我加入，我会说，
I don't assume you know nothing.
我不认为你什么都不知道。
Assume Pieter is a genius,
假设彼得是个天才，
like the smartest developer ever.
就像有史以来最聪明的开发人员一样。
And like learn, learn from it.
就像学习一样，从中学习。
- Yeah. - And yes and.
- 是的。 - 是的，还有。
Notice parts in the code where like, okay, okay, okay.
请注意代码中类似“好 吧，好吧，好吧”的部分。
I got it. - Yeah.
我得到了它。 - 是的。
- Here's how he's thinking.
- 这就是他的想法。
And now if I want to add another,
现在如果我想添加另一个，
like a little feature,
就像一个小功能，
definitely needs to have emoji. (laughs)
肯定需要有表情符号。 （笑）
- Yeah, man. - In front of it.
- 是的，伙计 。 - 在它前面。
And then like just follow the same style and add it.
然后就像遵循相同的 风格并添加它一样。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And my goal is to make you happy,
- 我的目标是让你快乐
to make you smile,
为了让你微笑，
to make you, ha-ha, fuck, I get it.
让你，哈哈，他妈的，我明白了。
And now you're going to start respecting me.
现在你要开始 尊重我了。
- Yeah. - And like trusting me,
- 是的。 - 就像信任我一样，
and you start working together in this way.
你们就以这种方式 开始一起工作。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I don't know how hard it's to find developers.
不知道找开发商 有多难。
- No, I think they exist.
- 不，我认为它们存在。
I think I need to hire more people.
我想我需要雇用更多的人。
I need to try more people. - Try people, yeah.
我需要尝试更多的人。 - 尝试 别人，是的。
- But that costs a lot of my energy and time.
- 但这花费了我很多 精力和时间。
- Yeah. - But it's 100% possible.
- 是的。 - 但这是100%可能的。
- But do I want it?
- 但我想要它吗？
I don't know, things kind of run fine for now.
我不知道，目前 一切进展顺利。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
And I mean like, okay.
我的意思是，好吧。
You could say like, okay,
你可以说，好吧，
Nomad List looks kind of clunky.
Nomad List 看起来有点笨重。
People say the design's gonna clunky.
人们说这个设计会很笨重。
Okay, I'll improve the design.
好的，我会改进设计。
It's like next to my to-do list, for example.
例如，它就像在我的 待办事项列表旁边。
I'll get there eventually.
我最终会到达那里。
- But it's true.
- 但这是真的。
I mean you're also extremely good at what you do.
我的意思是你也非常擅长 你所做的事情。
I'm just looking at the interfaces of Photo AI.
我只是在看 Photo AI 的界面。
You with jQuery, right?
你用过 jQuery，对吧？
How amazing is jQuery?
jQuery 有多神奇？
These cowboys are getting, these are...
这些牛仔正在变得，这些是......
There's these cowboys.
有这些牛仔。
This is a lot, this is a lot.
这很多，这很多。
But I'm glad they're all wearing shirts.
但我很高兴他们都穿着衬衫。
Anyway, the interface here is just really, really nice.
不管怎样，这里的界面 真的非常非常好。
I could tell you know what you're doing
我可以告诉你知道你在做什么
and with Nomad List extremely nice, the interface.
Nomad List 的界面 非常好。
- Thank you, man.
- 谢谢你，伙计。
- And that's all you.
- 这就是你。
- [Pieter] Yeah, that's everything is me.
- [Pieter] 是的，这就是我的一切。
- So all of this and every little feature.
- 所有这一切以及每一个小功能。
All of this. - People say
所有这一切 。 - 人们说
it looks kind of ADHD or ADD,
看起来有点ADHD或ADD，
like it's so much because it has so many things
喜欢它是因为它 有很多东西
and designs these days is minimalist.
如今的设计都是极简主义的。
Right? - Right, right, I hear you.
正确的 ？ - 对，对，我听到了。
But this is a lot of information
但这是很多信息
and it's useful information,
这是有用的信息，
and it's delivered in a clean way
并且以干净的方式交付
while still stylish and fun to look at.
同时看起来仍然时尚有趣。
So like minimalist design is about
就像极简主义设计的意义一样
when you want to convey no information whatsoever-
当你不想传达 任何信息时-
- Yeah. - And look cool.
- 是的。 - 而且看起来很酷。
- Yeah, it's very cool.
- 是的，这非常酷。
It's pretentious, right?
这很装腔作势吧？
- Pretentious or not, the function is useless.
- 不管是不是自命不凡 ，这个功能都没啥用。
This is about a lot of information
这涉及到很多信息
delivered to you in a clean,
以干净的方式交付给您，
and when it's clean you can't be too sexy.
当它干净的时候，你就不能太性感。
So it's sexy enough.
所以它足够性感。
- Yeah, this is I think how my brain looks.
- 是的，这就是我认为我 的大脑的样子。
It's a lot of shit going on.
发生了很多糟糕的事情。
It's like drawing bass music.
这就像绘制低音音乐。
It's like very (imitates bass music)
很像（模仿贝斯音乐）
- Yeah, but it's this still...
- 是啊，但还是这样……
The spacing of everything is nice.
一切的间距都很好。
The fonts are really nice.
字体真的很好看。
Like very readable, very small.
就像非常可读，非常小。
- Yeah, I like it, you know,
- 是的，我喜欢它，你知道，
but I made it so I don't trust my own judgment.
但我做到了，所以我不 相信自己的判断。
- No, this is really nice. - Thank you, man.
- 不，这真的很好。 - 谢谢 你，伙计。
- Emojis are somehow,
- 表情符号在某种程度上是，
like this is a style, it's a thing.
就像这是一种风格，这是一种东西。
- I need to pick the emoji.
- 我需要选择表情符号。
It takes a while to pick them.
挑选它们需要一段时间。
- Something about the emoji is a really nice memorable,
- 表情符号确实 令人难忘，
like placeholder for the idea.
就像这个想法的占位符。
- Yeah. - If it was just text,
- 是的。 - 如果只是文字的话
it would actually be overwhelming if you was just text.
如果你只是文字，那实际上会 让人不知所措。
The emoji really helps.
表情符号真的很有帮助。
That's a brilliant addition.
这是一个绝妙的补充。
Some people might look at it,
有的人可能看了一眼，
why do you have emojis everywhere?
为什么到处都有表情符号？
It's actually really, for me, it's really-
事实上，对我来说，这真的是——
- People tell me to remove the emojis.
- 人们告诉我删除表情符号。
- Yeah, well, people don't know what they're talking about.
- 是的，人们不知道 他们在说什么。
- Makes it immature.
- 使其不成熟。
- I'm sure people will tell you a lot of things.
- 我相信人们会告诉 你很多事情。
This is really nice.
这真的很好。
And then using color is nice.
然后使用颜色就很好了。
Small font but not too small.
字体虽小，但也不能太小。
And obviously, you have to show maps,
显然，你必须展示地图，
which is really tricky.
这确实很棘手。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- This is nice.
- 这很好。
- No, this is really, really, really nice.
- 不，这真的、真的、真的很好。
I mean, okay, how this looks
我的意思是，好吧，这看起来怎么样
when you hover over it?
当你将鼠标悬停在它上面时？
- Yeah, it's easy as transitions.
- 是的，过渡很简单。
- No, I understand that.
- 不，我明白。
I'm sure there's like,
我确信有这样的，
how long does that take you to figure
你需要多长时间才能弄清楚
out how you want it to look?
你想要它是什么样子？
Do you ever go down a rabbit hole
你曾经掉进过兔子洞吗
where you spent like two weeks?
你在哪里度过了大约两周？
- No, it's all iterative.
- 不，这都是迭代的。
It's like 10 years of, you know,
这就像10年，你知道，
added C transition here or do this or.
在这里添加 C 转换或执行此操作或。
- Well, let's say like,
- 好吧，比方说，
see these are rounded now. - Yeah.
看到这些现在是圆形的。 - 是 的。
- If you wanted to like round is probably the better way.
- 如果您喜欢圆形，那 可能是更好的方法。
But if you want it to be rectangular,
但如果你想要它是矩形的，
like sharp corners, what would you do?
比如尖角，你会怎么做？
You just? - So go to the index at CSS.
你刚刚？ - 因此请转到 CSS 索引。
- Yeah. - And I do Command + F.
- 是的。 - 我按 Command + F。
and I search border radius 12 px.
我搜索边框半径 12 px。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- And then I replace with border radius zero.
- 然后我用边界 半径零替换。
And then I do Command + Enter-
然后我执行 Command + Enter-
- Yeah. - And it's get deploys,
- 是的。 - 而且它已经得到部署，
it pushes to the git hub
它推送到 git hub
and then sends a WebBook and then deploys to my server,
然后发送一个WebBook，然后 部署到我的服务器，
and it's live in five seconds.
五秒后即可上线。
- Oh, you often deployed to production.
- 哦，你经常部署到生产环境。
You don't have like a testing ground?
你们没有试验场之类的吗？
- No. (Lex laughs)
- 不。（ 莱克斯笑）
So I'm like famous for this,
所以我因此而出名
'cause I'm too lazy to set up
因为我懒得去设置
a staging server on my laptop every time.
每次我的笔记本电脑上都有一个临时服务器。
So nowadays I just deploy to production.
所以现在我只是部署到生产中。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- Man, I'm gonna be canceled for this.
- 伙计，我会因此被取消。
But it works very well for me,
但对我来说效果很好，
'cause I have a lot of...
因为我有很多...
I have PHP Lint and djLint
我有 PHP Lint 和 djLint
so it tells me when there's error.
所以它会告诉我何时出现错误。
So I don't deploy. - Yeah.
所以我不部署。 - 是 的。
- But literally,
- 但从字面上看，
I have like 37,000 git commits
我有大约 37,000 次 git 提交
in the last 12 months or something.
在过去 12 个月或其他时间。
So I make small fix
所以我做了一些小修改
and then Command + Enter,
然后命令+输入，
and sends to GitHub.
并发送到 GitHub。
GitHub sends a web to server,
GitHub 将网络发送到服务器，
web server pulls it, deploys the production,
Web 服务器拉取 它，部署生产，
and is there.
就在那里。
- What's the latency of that
- 延迟是多少
from you pressing Command + Enter?
你按 Command + Enter 吗？
- One second, can be one two seconds.
- 一秒，可以是一两秒。
- So you just make a change and then you-
- 所以你只要做出改变然后你-
- That's right. - Getting really good at like
- 这是正确的 。 - 变得非常擅长喜欢
not making mistakes basically.
基本不会犯错误。
- Man, 100%, you're right.
- 伙计，100%，你是对的。
People are like, how can you do this?
人们会说，你怎么能这样做呢？
Well, you get good at not
好吧，你擅长不
taking the server down. - Yeah.
关闭服务器。 - 是 的。
- 'Cause you need to code more carefully.
- 因为你需要更仔细地编码。
Look, it's idiotic in any big company.
瞧，这在任何大公司都是愚蠢的。
But for me, it works 'cause it makes me so fast.
但对我来说，它很有效 ，因为它让我跑得很快。
Somebody will report a bug on Twitter
有人会在 Twitter 上报告错误
and I kind of did do a stopwatch.
我确实做了一个秒表。
How fast can I fix this bug?
我能多快修复这个错误？
And then two minutes later, for example, it's fixed.
然后，例如，两分钟后 ，问题就解决了。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- And it's fun 'cause it's annoying
- 这很有趣，因为它很烦人
for me to work with companies where you report a bug
让我能够与您报告错误 的公司合作
and it takes like six months. - Yeah.
大约需要六个月的时间。 - 是 的。
- It's like horrible.
- 这太可怕了。
And it makes people really happy
这让人们真的很开心
when you can really quickly solve their problems.
当你能够真正快速地解决 他们的问题时。
But it's crazy, I admit.
但这很疯狂，我承认。
- I don't think it's crazy.
- 我不认为这很疯狂。
I mean, I'm sure there's a middle ground,
我的意思是，我确信有一个中间立场，
but I think that whole thing
但我认为整件事
where there's a phase of like testing
其中有一个类似测试的阶段
and there's the staging,
还有舞台表演，
and there's a development
并且有一个发展
and then there's like multiple tables
然后有很多张桌子
and databases that you use for the stage.
以及您在舞台上使用的数据库。
Like it's- - Filing.
就像它- - 归档。
- It's a mess. - Yeah.
- 真是一团糟。 - 是的。
- And there's different teams involved.
- 并且涉及不同的团队。
It's not good.
这不好。
- I'm like a good funny extreme on the other side.
- 我就像另一边的 一个有趣的极端。
- But just a little bit safer but not too much.
- 但只是稍微安全一点 ，但也不是太多。
It would be great. - Yeah, yeah.
那就太好了。 - 是 啊是啊。
- And I'm sure that's actually like how X now,
- 我确信这实际上 就像 X 现在一样，
how they're doing rapid improvement.
他们如何快速改进。
It's exactly. - No, they do
正是如此。 - 不 ，他们这样做
because there's more bugs. - Yeah.
因为还有更多的bug。 - 是 的。
- And people complain about like,
- 人们抱怨说，
oh look, he bought this Twitter.
哦，看，他买了这个 Twitter。
Now it's full of bugs.
现在它充满了错误。
Dude, these shipping stuff-
老兄，这些运输的东西-
- Yeah. - Things are happening now
- 是的 。 - 事情正在发生
and it's a dynamic app now.
现在它是一个动态应用程序。
- Yeah, the bugs is actually
- 是的，这些错误实际上是
a sign of a good thing happening.
好事发生的征兆。
- Yes. - The bugs of the feature
- 是的 。 - 功能的错误
because it shows- - Yes.
因为它表明——是 的。
- That the team is actually building shit.
- 该团队实际上正在构建垃圾。
- 100%, yeah.
- 100%，是的。
- Well, one of the problems is like
- 嗯，问题之一是
I see with YouTube there's so much potential
我看到 YouTube 有巨大的潜力
to build features, but I just see how long it takes.
构建功能，但我只是 看看需要多长时间。
So I've gotten a chance to interact with many other teams.
所以我有机会与许多 其他团队互动。
But one of the teams is MLA, multi-language audio.
但其中一个团队是 MLA（ 多语言音频）。
- Yeah. - I dunno if you know this,
- 是的。 - 我不知道你是否知道这一点
but in YouTube you can have
但在 YouTube 上您可以
audio tracks in different languages.
不同语言的音轨。
- Yeah. - For over dubbing.
- 是的 。 - 用于配音。
And there's a team,
还有一个团队，
and not many people are using it,
而且用的人不多，
but like every single feature,
但就像每一个功能一样，
they have to meet and agree,
他们必须会面并达成一致，
and there's allocate resources.
还有分配资源。
Engineers have to work on it.
工程师必须为此努力。
But I'm sure it's a pain in the ass
但我确信这很痛苦
for the engineers to get approval to like,
为了让工程师们获得认可，
- [Pieter] I know.
- [彼得]我知道。
- Because it has to not break the rest of the site,
- 因为它不能破坏 网站的其余部分，
whatever they do.
无论他们做什么。
But if you don't have enough dictatorial,
但如果你没有足够的独裁能力
like top down, like we need this now,
就像自上而下一样，就像我们现在需要这个一样，
it's gonna take forever
这将需要永远
to do anything multi-language audio.
做任何事情都需要多语言音频。
But multi-language audio is a good example of a thing
但多语言音频就是 一个很好的例子
that seems niche right now,
现在看来是小众的，
but it quite possibly could change the entire world.
但它很可能会改变 整个世界。
When I upload this conversation right here,
当我在这里上传 这段对话时，
if instantaneously, it dubs it into 40 languages.
如果即时的话，它会 将其配音成 40 种语言。
- [Pieter] Yeah, man.
- [彼得] 是的，伙计。
- And everybody consume every single video
- 每个人都会观看每一个视频
can be watched and listened to
可以观看和收听
in those different, it changes everything.
在那些不同的地方，它改变了一切。
And YouTube is extremely well-positioned
YouTube 的定位非常有利
to be the leader in this. - Yeah.
成为这方面的领导者。 - 是 的。
- They got the compute,
- 他们得到了计算，
they got the user base,
他们获得了用户群，
they have the experience of how to do this.
他们有如何做到这 一点的经验。
So like multi-language audio should be-
所以多语言音频应该是-
- High priority feature, right?
- 高优先级功能，对吧？
- Yeah, that's high priority. - Yeah, yeah.
- 是的，这是高优先级。 - 是 啊是啊。
- And it's a way,
- 这是一种方式，
Google is obsessed with AI right now.
谷歌现在对人工智能非常着迷。
They wanna show off that they could be dominant in AI.
他们想炫耀自己可以在人工 智能领域占据主导地位。
That's a way for Google to say like, we used AI.
这是谷歌的一种说法， 我们使用了人工智能。
This is a way to break down the walls
这是打破墙壁的方法
that language creates.
该语言创造。
- The preferred outcome
- 首选结果
for them is probably their career
对他们来说可能就是他们的职业
and not the overall result of the cool product.
而不是酷产品的 整体结果。
- I think they're not like selfish or whatever,
- 我认为他们并不 自私或其他什么的
they wanna do good.
他们想做好事。
There's something about the machine-
这台机器有一些东西——
- The organization, yeah.
- 组织，是的。
- The organizational stuff that's just so I happens.
- 组织上的事情正 是我所经历的。
- I have this when I report bugs
- 当我报告错误时我有这个
on like big companies I work with.
像我合作过的大公司一样。
I talk to a lot of different people in DM
我在 DM 中与很多不同的人交谈
and they're all really trying hard to do something.
他们都非常努力 地去做某事。
They're all really nice.
他们都非常好。
And I'm the one being kind of asshole-
而我就是那个混蛋——
- Yeah. - 'Cause I'm like,
- 是的。 - 因为我就像，
guys, I'm talking to 20 people about this
伙计们，我正在和 20 个人谈论这个
for six months and nothing's happening.
六个月了，什么也没发生。
I say, "Man, I know but I'm trying my best."
我说：“伙计，我知道， 但我正在尽力。”
Yeah, so it's systemic.
是的，所以它是系统性的。
- Yeah, it requires, again,
- 是的，这再次需要，
I don't know if there must be a nicer word,
不知道还有没有 更好听的词
but like dictatorial type of top down the CEO rolls in
但就像自上而下的独裁类型 一样，首席执行官介入
and just says like, for you two, it's like MLA.
只是说，对于你们两个 来说，这就像 MLA。
- Yeah. - Get this done now.
- 是的。 - 现在就完成这件事。
This is the highest priority.
这是最高优先级。
- I think big companies, especially in America,
- 我认为大公司， 尤其是在美国，
a lot of it's legal, right?
很多都是合法的，对吧？
They need to pass everything through legal.
他们需要通过法律 途径解决一切问题。
- Yeah. - And you can't like,
- 是的 。 - 你不能喜欢，
man, the things I do,
伙计，我所做的事情，
I could never do that in a big corporation,
在大公司我 永远做不到
'cause it's everything has to be probably
因为一切都可能是这样
Git deploy has to go through legal.
Git部署必须经过合法程序。
- Well, again, dictatorial,
- 好吧，再说一遍，独裁者，
you basically say Steve Jobs did this quite a lot.
你基本上可以说史蒂夫· 乔布斯做了很多这样的事。
I've seen a lot of leaders do this.
我见过很多领导这样做。
Ignore the lawyers.
无视律师。
Ignore comms. - Exactly, yeah.
忽略通讯。 - 确实如此。
- Ignore PR, ignore everybody.
- 忽略公关，忽略所有人。
Give power to the engineers.
把权力交给工程师。
Listen to the people on the ground, get this shit done,
听听当地人民的意见 ，把这件事做好，
and get it done by Friday.
并在周五之前完成。
- Yeah. - That's it.
- 是的。 - 就是这样。
- And the law can change.
- 法律可以改变。
For example, let's say you launch this AI dubbing
例如，假设您启动 了这个人工智能配音
and there's some legal problems with lawsuits.
并且诉讼中存在 一些法律问题。
Okay, so the law changes, there will be appeals,
好吧，所以法律改变 了，会有上诉，
there will be some Supreme Court thing, whatever.
无论如何，最高法院都 会有一些事情。
And the law changes.
法律也发生了变化。
So just by shipping it you change society,
因此，只要运送它，你就可以改变社会，
you change the legal framework.
你改变了法律框架。
And by not shipping,
并且通过不发货，
being scared of the legal framework all the time.
一直害怕法律 框架。
You're not changing things.
你没有改变事情。
- Just outta curiosity, what ID do you use?
- 出于好奇，你使用 什么ID？
Let's talk about like your whole setup.
让我们谈谈你的整个设置。
Given how ultra productive you are
考虑到你的生产力有多高
and that you often program in your underwear
你经常在 内裤里编程
slouching on the couch.
无精打采地靠在沙发上。
Does it matter to you in general?
总体来说这对你来说重要吗？
Is there like a specific ID you use you use VS Code?
您使用 VS Code 时是否 有一个特定的 ID？
- Yeah, VS Code.
- 是的，VS Code。
Before I used Sublime Text,
在我使用 Sublime Text 之前，
I don't think it matters a lot.
我认为这并不重要。
I think I'm very skeptical
我想我很怀疑
of like tools when people think it...
当人们认为类似的工具时...
They say it matters, right?
他们说这很重要，对吗？
I don't think it matters.
我认为这并不重要。
I think whatever tool you know very well,
我认为无论你熟悉什么工具，
you go very, very fast and the shortcuts,
你走得非常非常快，还有捷径，
for example, IDE.
例如，IDE。
I love Sublime Text 'cause I could use multi-cursor,
我喜欢 Sublime Text 因为 我可以使用多光标，
you search something and I could just like make mass
你搜索一些东西， 我就可以做大众
replaces in a foul- - Yeah.
犯规时换人- - 是 的。
- With the cursor thing,
- 有了光标的东西，
and VS Code doesn't really have that as well.
而 VS Code 也确实 没有这样的功能。
- It's actually interesting.
- 其实很有趣。
Sublime is the first editor where I've learned that.
Sublime 是我学到的第一 个编辑器。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And I think they just make that super easy.
- 我认为他们让这 变得超级简单。
So what would that be called?
那么这会被称为什么呢？
Multi-edit, multi-cursors edit-
多重编辑、多光标编辑-
- Yeah. - Thing whatever.
- 是的。 - 无论如何。
- [Pieter] That's so good.
- [彼得] 那太好了。
- I'm sure like almost every editor can do that.
- 我确信几乎每个编辑 都能做到这一点。
It is just probably hard to set up.
只是可能很难设置。
- Yeah. - And why so why need it?
- 是的 。 - 为什么需要它？
- VS Code is not so good, I think,
- 我认为 VS Code 不太好，
Or at least I try it.
或者至少我尝试一下。
But I would use that to like process data.
但我会用它来处理数据。
Data sets, for example, from World Bank.
例如，来自世界银行的数据集。
I would just multi-cursor mass change everything,
我只想用多光标大 规模改变一切，
but yeah, VS Codes.
但是，是的，VS Code。
Man, I was bullied into using VS Code,
伙计，我被胁迫才使用 VS Code，
'cause Twitter would always see my screenshots
因为 Twitter 总会 看到我的屏幕截图
of Sublime Text and say,
Sublime Text 并说，
"Why are you still using Sublime Text?"
“你为什么还在使用 Sublime Text？”
Boomer, you need to use VS codes.
Boomer，你需要使用VS代码。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And I'm like, yeah, I'll try it.
- 我想，是的，我会尝试一下。
I got a new MacBook
我有一台新 MacBook
and then I never installed,
然后我就再也没有安装过
I never copied the old MacBook.
我从来没有抄袭旧MacBook。
I just make it fresh, you know,
我只是让它变得新鲜，你知道，
like a clean, like format C Windows.
就像干净的、格式为C的Windows一样。
Clean starts and I'm like, 'Okay, I'll try VS Code."
干净地开始，我想，‘好吧 ，我会尝试 VS Code。’
And it stuck, you know, but I don't really care.
你知道，它卡住了， 但我真的不在乎。
It's not so important for me.
这对我来说并不那么重要。
- Wow, you know the format C reference, huh?
- 哇，你知道 C 格式参考吗？
- Dude, it was so good.
=> - 伙计，太棒了。
You would install Windows
你会安装Windows
and then after three or six months it would start breaking
然后三六个月后 它就会开始破裂
and everything was like get slow.
一切都变得缓慢起来。
Then you would restart, go to Dos,
然后你会重新启动，进入Dos，
format C, you would delete your hard drive
格式化C，你会删除你的硬盘
and then install the Windows 95 again,
然后再次安装Windows 95，
that was so good times.
那真是美好的时光。
And you would design everything.
你会设计一切。
Now I'm gonna install it properly.
现在我要正确安装它。
now I'm gonna design my desktop properly.
现在我要正确设计我的桌面。
- Yeah, I don't know if it's peer pressure,
- 是的，我不知道这 是否是同辈压力，
but like I used E-MAX for many, many years
但就像我使用 E-MAX 很多很多年一样
and I know, you know, I love Lisp.
我知道，你知道，我喜欢 Lisp。
So a lot of the customization is done in Lisp.
所以很多定制都是用 Lisp 完成的。
It's a programming language.
它是一种编程语言。
And partially, it was peer pressure.
部分原因是同侪压力。
But part of it's realizing like
但其中一部分是意识到
you need to keep learning stuff.
你需要不断学习东西。
The same issue with jQuery.
jQuery 也有同样的问题。
I still think I need to learn Node.js, for example.
例如，我仍然认为 我需要学习 Node.js。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Even though that's not my main thing
- 尽管这不是我的主要事情
or even close to the main thing.
甚至接近主要的事情。
But I feel like you need to keep learning this stuff.
但我觉得你需要继续 学习这些东西。
And even if you don't choose to use it long term,
即使您不选择 长期使用它，
you need to give it a chance.
你需要给它一个机会。
So your understanding of the world expands.
所以你对世界的 理解会扩展。
- Yeah, you wanna understand
- 是的，你想明白
the new technological concepts
新技术概念
and see if they can benefit you.
看看它们是否能让你受益。
It would be stupid not to even try it.
不尝试一下就太愚蠢了。
- It's more about the concepts
- 更多的是关于概念
I would say than the actual tools.
我想说的是比实际的工具。
Like expanding, and that could be a challenging thing.
就像扩张一样，这可能 是一件具有挑战性的事情。
So going to VS Code and like really learning it,
所以去 VS Code 并 真正学习它，
like all the shortcuts, all the extensions,
就像所有的快捷方式、 所有的扩展一样，
and actually installing different stuff and playing with it.
并实际安装不同的东西 并使用它。
That was a interesting challenge.
这是一个有趣的挑战。
It was uncomfortable at first.
一开始很不舒服。
- Yeah, for me too, yeah. - Yeah, but you just dive in.
- 是的，对我来说也是，是 的。 - 是的，但你只是潜入。
- It's like neuro flex,
- 这就像神经弯曲，
like you keep your brain fresh,
就像你让你的大脑保持新鲜一样，
like this kind of stuff.
喜欢这种东西。
- I gotta do that more.
- 我必须做得更多。
Have you given React a chance? (laughs)
你给过React机会吗？ （笑）
- No, but I wanna learn
- 不，但我想学习
and I understand the basics, right?
我了解基础知识，对吗？
I don't really know where to start.
我真的不知道从哪里开始。
- But would you like, I guess you gotta use your own model,
- 但是你愿意吗，我想你必须 使用你自己的模型，
which is like build the thing using it.
这就像用它来构建东西一样。
- No, man, so I kind of did that.
- 不，伙计，所以我就这么做了。
- Yeah. - The stuff I do
- 是的 。 - 我做的事
in jQuery is essentially,
在 jQuery 中本质上是，
a lot of it is like,
很多都是这样的，
I start rebuilding whatever tech is already out there.
我开始重建现有 的技术。
Not based on that,
并非基于此，
but just on accident. - Yeah.
但只是偶然。 - 是 的。
- I keep coding long enough that I built the same,
- 我持续编码的时间足够长，以至于 我构建了相同的东西，
I start getting the same problems everybody else has,
我开始遇到和其他 人一样的问题
and you start building the same frameworks kind of.
然后你开始构建 相同的框架。
So essentially, I use my own kind of framework of.
所以本质上，我使用 我自己的框架。
- So you basically build a framework from scratch
- 所以你基本上是从头 开始构建一个框架
that's your own, that you understand it?
那是你自己的，你明白吗？
- Kinda yeah.
- 有点是的。
With HX calls, but essentially it's the same thing.
虽然有 HX 调用，但本质 上是一样的。
Look, I don't have the time.
你看，我没有时间。
I think saying you don't have the time
我想说你没有时间
is like always a lie,
就像总是一个谎言，
'cause you just don't prioritize it enough.
因为你没有足够 优先考虑它。
My priority is still like the running the businesses
我的首要任务仍然 是经营企业
and improving that and AI.
并改进它和人工智能。
I think learning AI is much more valuable now
我认为现在学习人工 智能更有价值
than learning a front end framework.
比学习前端框架更重要。
Yeah, It's just more impact.
是的，只是影响更大。
- I guess you should be just learning
- 我想你应该只是在学习
every single day a thing.
每一天都是一件事。
- Yeah, you can learn a little bit every day.
- 是的，你每天都 可以学到一点。
- Yeah. - Like a little bit of React,
- 是的 。 - 就像一点点 React，
or I think now, like Next very big.
或者我认为现在，像Next非常大。
So learn a little bit of Next.
所以学习一点Next。
But I call them the military industrial complex.
但我称它们 为军工联合体。
But you need to know,
但你需要知道，
you need to know it anyway.
无论如何你都需要知道它。
- You gotta learn how to use the weapons of war
- 你必须学习如何 使用战争武器
and then you can be peacenik.
然后你就可以成为和平主义者了。
- Yeah, yeah. - Yeah, I mean,
- 是啊是啊。 - 是 的，我的意思是，
but you gotta learn it in the same exact way
但你必须以同样 的方式学习它
as we were talking about,
正如我们所说，
which is learning by trying to build something with it
这是通过尝试用它构建 一些东西来学习
and actually deploy it.
并实际部署它。
- The frameworks are so complicated
- 框架太复杂了
and it changes so fast.
而且变化如此之快。
So it's like, where do I start?
所以这就像是，我从哪里开始？
And I guess it's the same thing
我想这是同一件事
when you're starting out making websites.
当您开始制作网站时。
Where do you start?
你从哪里开始？
Ask GPT-4, I guess.
我想，问问 GPT-4。
Yeah, it's just so dynamic.
是的，它就是这么动态。
It changes so fast that,
它变化如此之快，以至于
and I dunno if it would be a good idea for me to learn it.
我不知道学习它对我来说 是否是一个好主意。
Maybe some combination of like,
也许像这样的某种组合，
few Next with PHP Laravel.
接下来使用 PHP Laravel。
Laravel is like a framework for PHP.
Laravel 就像 PHP 的框架。
I think that would be...
我想那会是...
It could benefit me.
它可以使我受益。
Maybe Tailwind for CSS,
也许 CSS 的 Tailwind，
like a styling engine.
就像造型引擎一样。
That stuff could probably save me time.
那东西可能可以节省我的时间。
- Yeah, but like you won't know
- 是的，但就像你不知道一样
until you really give it a try.
直到你真正尝试一下。
And it feels like you have to build,
感觉就像你必须建造，
if maybe I'm talking to myself,
如果也许我在自言自语
but I should probably recode
但我可能应该重新编码
like my personal one page in Laravel.
就像我在 Laravel 中的个人页面一样。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And even though it might not have almost
- 即使它可能没有几乎
any dynamic elements, maybe have one dynamic element,
任何动态元素，可能 有一个动态元素，
but it has to go end to end in that framework.
但它必须在这个框架 内进行端到端。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Or like end to end build in Node.js.
- 或者像 Node.js 中的端到端构建一样。
Some of it is, I don't...
有一些是，我不...
Figuring out how to even deploy the thing.
弄清楚如何部署这个东西。
- I have no idea. - Full stack.
- 我不知道。 - 全栈。
- All I know is right now I would send it to GitHub
- 我所知道的是现在我 会将其发送到 GitHub
and it sends it to my server.
并将其发送到我的服务器。
I don't know how to get JavaScript running.
我不知道如何让 JavaScript 运行。
I have no clue. - Yeah.
我不知道。 - 是 的。
- So I guess I need like a pass,
- 所以我想我需要一张通行证
like first an array,
就像第一个数组一样，
or Heroku kind of those kind of platforms.
或 Heroku 之类的平台。
- I actually kind of just gave myself the idea of like,
- 实际上我只是给 自己一个想法，
I kind of just wanna build a single webpage.
我只是想建立 一个网页。
Like one webpage that has one dynamic element
就像一个网页有 一个动态元素
and just do it in every single,
并在每一个环节都做到这一点，
in a lot of frameworks.
在很多框架中。
Like just- - Ah, on the same page.
就像- - 啊 ，在同一页上。
- Same exact page. - All the same?
- 完全相同的页面。 - 都一样吗？
- Kinda page. - It's smart.
- 有点页面。 - 这很聪明。
That's a cool project.
这是一个很酷的项目。
You can learn all these frameworks.
您可以学习所有这些框架。
- Yeah. - And you can see
- 是的。 - 你可以看到
the differences.
的差异。
- Yeah. - That's interesting, right?
- 是的 。 - 这很有趣，对吧？
- That how long it takes to do it.
- 完成这件事需要多长时间。
- Yeah, stopwatch, yeah, yeah.
- 是的，秒表，是的，是的。
- I have to figure out actually
-我实际上必须弄清楚
something sufficiently complicated,
足够复杂的东西，
'cause it should probably do,
因为它可能应该做，
it should probably do some kind of thing
它可能应该做一些事情
where it accesses the database
它访问数据库的地方
and dynamically changing stuff.
和动态变化的东西。
- Some AI stuff, some LLM stuff.
- 一些人工智能的东西，一些法学硕士的东西。
- Yeah, maybe some,
- 是的，也许有一些，
it doesn't have to be AI LLM but maybe-
它不一定是人工智能法学硕士，但也许-
- Do an API call. - API call to something.
- 进行 API 调用 。 - API 调用。
- Yeah, to replicate, for example.
- 是的，例如复制。
And then that would be a very cool project.
那将是一个非常 酷的项目。
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是啊是啊。
And like time it and also report on my happiness.
喜欢计时并报告 我的幸福感。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- I'm gonna totally do this
- 我会完全做到这一点
- Because nobody benchmarks this.
- 因为没有人对此进行基准测试。
Nobody's benchmark developer happiness with frameworks.
没有人能够衡量开发人员 对框架的满意度。
- [Lex] Yeah
- [莱克斯] 是的
- Nobody's benchmarked the shipping time.
- 没有人对运输时间进行基准测试。
- Just take like a month and do this.
- 只需一个月的时间就可以做到这一点。
How many frameworks are there?
有多少个框架？
How many?
多少？
There's like five main ways of doing it.
大约有五种主要方法可以做到这一点。
So there's like, this is no...
所以这就像是，这不是...
There's backend, frontend.
有后端，前端。
- And this stuff confused me too.
- 这件事也让我困惑。
Like React now apparently has become backend.
就像 React 现在显然已经 成为后端了。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- Or something used to be on frontend,
- 或者以前在前端的东西，
and you're forced to do now backend also.
而且你现在也被迫做后端。
I don't know.
我不知道。
But there's not really,
但其实并没有，
you're not really forced to do anything.
你并没有真正被迫做任何事情。
So according to the internet,
所以根据网上的说法，
so like there's no...
所以就像没有...
It's actually not trivial
其实这并不是一件小事
to find the canonical way of doing things.
找到做事的规范方式。
So like the standard vanilla- - Yeah.
就像标准的香草一样——是 的。
- You go to the ice cream shop,
- 你去冰淇淋店，
there's like a million flavors.
大约有一百万种口味。
I want vanilla.
我想要香草。
If I've never had ice cream in my life,
如果我这辈子没吃过冰淇淋
can we just like learn about ice cream?
我们可以学习冰淇淋吗？
- Yeah. - I want vanilla.
- 是的。 - 我想要香草。
Nobody actually,
其实没有人，
sometimes they'll literally name it vanilla.
有时他们会直接 将其命名为香草。
But I wanna know what's the basic way,
但我想知道基本的方法是什么
but not like dumb,
但又不像哑巴，
but the standard canonical common.
但标准规范通用。
- Yeah, I know the dominant way-
- 是的，我知道主导方式-
- [Lex] Yeah, the dominant way.
- [Lex] 是的，主导方式。
- 60% of developers do it like this.
- 60% 的开发者这样做。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- It's hard to figure that out,
- 很难弄清楚，
that's the problem.
这就是问题所在。
- Yeah, maybe LLMs can help.
- 是的，也许法学硕士可以提供帮助。
Maybe you should explicitly ask what is the dominant?
也许你应该明确地 问什么是主导？
- Because they usually know the dominant,
- 因为他们通常知道主导，
they give answers- - Yeah.
他们给出答案--是 的。
- That are like the most probable kind of.
- 这就像最有可能的一种。
- So that makes sense
- 是的。 - 所以这是有道理的
to ask LLM.
去问LLM。
I think honestly, maybe what would help is
老实说，我认为也许有帮助的是
if you wanna learn or I would wanna learn a framework.
如果你想学习或者我想 学习一个框架。
Hire somebody that already does it
雇用已经做过这件事的人
and just sit with them
和他们坐在一起
and make something together.
一起做一些事情。
I've never done that, but I've thought about it.
我从来没有这样做 过，但我想过。
So it would be a very fast way to
所以这将是一个非常快速的方法
take their knowledge put them in my brain.
把他们的知识放进我的大脑里。
- I've tried these kinds of things.
- 我已经尝试过这些事情。
What happens is it depends what kind of,
发生什么取决于什么样的，
if they're like a world class developer, yes.
如果他们像世界级的开发 人员一样，是的。
Oftentimes they themselves are used to that thing
很多时候他们自己已经 习惯了那件事
and they have not themselves explored in other options.
他们自己也没有探索 过其他选择。
So they're have this dogmatic talking down to you,
所以他们用这种教条主义 的态度来居高临下地对你说话
- [Pieter] Yeah. (laughs)
- [彼得] 是的。 （笑）
- This is the right way to do it.
- 这是正确的做法。
- Yeah. - It's like, no, no, no.
- 是的。 - 就像，不，不，不。
We're just like exploring together.
我们就像一起探索。
Okay, show me the cool thing you've tried,
好吧，让我看看你尝试过的很酷的事情，
which is like, it has to have open-mindedness to like,
就像，它必须有开放 的心态才能喜欢，
Node.js is not the right way to do web development.
Node.js 不是进行 Web 开发的正确方法。
It's like one way.
这就像一种方式。
And there's nothing wrong with the old lamp, PHP,
而且老灯PHP也没 什么问题，
jQuery, vanilla JavaScript way.
jQuery，普通 JavaScript 方式。
It just has its pros and cons,
只是有它的优点和缺点
and like- - Yeah.
就像- - 是 的。
- You really you need to know what the pros and cons.
- 你真的需要知道 优点和缺点。
- Those people exist.
- 这些人确实存在。
You could find those people probably.
你也许可以找到那些人。
- Yeah. - If you wanna learn AI,
- 是的。 - 如果你想学习人工智能，
imagine you have Karpathy sitting next to you-
想象一下卡帕西 坐在你旁边-
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Teach you, like he does these YouTube videos.
- 教你，就像他教这些 YouTube 视频一样。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
He can teach it to like a five-year-old
他可以教它像一个五岁的孩子一样
about how to make LLM.
关于如何取得LLM。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
Imagine this guy sitting next to you
想象一下这个人坐在你旁边
and just teaching you like,
只是教你，
let's make LLM together.
让我们一起攻读LLM吧。
Holy shit, it would be amazing.
天啊，那真是太棒了。
- Yeah, I mean, well, Karpathy has its own style
- 是的，我的意思是 ，卡帕蒂有自己的风格
and is like, I'm not sure he's for everybody,
就像，我不确定 他适合所有人，
for example, a five-year-old.
例如，一个五岁的孩子。
It depends on the five-year-old.
这取决于五岁的孩子。
- Yeah. - He's like super technical,
- 是的 。 - 他技术精湛，
- But he's amazing,
- 但他很了不起
'cause he's super technical
因为他技术超强
and he's the only one who can explain-
而他是唯一能解释的人——
- Yes. - The stuff in a simple way,
- 是的 。 - 以简单的方式做事，
which shows his complete genius.
这显示了他完全的天才。
- Yes. - 'Cause if you can
- 是的。 - 因为如果你可以
explain without jargon- - No BS.
不用行话解释——没有 废话。
- You're like, wow.
- 你就像，哇。
- And build it from scratch. - Yeah. it's like top tier.
- 从头开始​​构建它。 - 是的。这就像顶级的。
What a guy!
真是个家伙啊！
- But he might be anti-framework
- 但他可能是反框架的
'cause he builds from scratch.
因为他是从头开始构建的。
- Actually, exactly, yeah.
- 事实上，确实如此，是的。
Actually he probably is, yeah.
事实上他可能是，是的。
- He's like you, but for AI.
- 他和你一样，只不过是人工智能。
- Yeah, so maybe learning a framework
- 是的，所以也许学习一个框架
is a very bad idea for us.
对我们来说是一个非常糟糕的主意。
Maybe we should stay in PHP,
也许我们应该留在 PHP，
and like Script kiddie and the-
就像脚本小子和-
- But you have to...
- 但你必须...
Maybe by learning the framework,
也许通过学习框架，
you learn what you want to yourself,
你自己学习你想要的东西，
build from scratch.
从头开始构建。
- Yeah, maybe you learn concepts,
- 是的，也许你学习概念，
but you don't actually
但你实际上并没有
have to start using it for your life, right?
必须开始在你的生活 中使用它，对吗？
Yeah, yeah.
是啊是啊。
- And you're still a Mac guy or was a Mac guy?
- 你现在仍然是 Mac 人还是 曾经是 Mac 人？
- Yeah, yeah, I switched to Mac in 2014,
- 是的，是的，我在 2014 年转向了 Mac，
'cause when I wanted to start traveling
因为当我想开始旅行时
and my brother was like, "Dude, get a MacBook.
我哥哥说：“伙计 ，买台 MacBook。
It's like the standard now."
这就像现在的标准。”
I'm like, wow, I need to switch from Windows.
我想，哇，我需要从 Windows 切换过来。
And I had like three screens, Windows.
我有大约三个屏幕，Windows。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- I had this whole setup for music production.
- 我有音乐制作的 整个设置。
I had to sell everything.
我不得不卖掉所有东西。
And then I had a MacBook,
然后我就有了一台 MacBook，
and I remember opening up this MacBook box,
我记得打开这个 MacBook 盒子，
like aah,
就像啊，
and it was so beautiful.
它是如此美丽。
It was like this aluminum,
就像这个铝，
and then I opened it,
然后我打开它，
I removed the screen protector thing.
我把屏幕保护膜去掉了。
And it's so beautiful.
它是如此美丽。
And I didn't touch it for three days.
而且我已经三天没碰它了。
I was just like, looking at it.
我只是看着它。
- Yeah. - Really.
- 是的。 - 真的。
And I was still on the Windows computer.
而且我还在使用 Windows 计算机。
And then I went traveling with that.
然后我就带着它去旅行了。
And all my great things started when I switched to Mac,
当我切换到 Mac 时，我 所有的伟大事情都开始了，
which sounds very dogmatic, right?
这听起来很教条，对吧？
- What great things are you talking about?
- 你在谈论什么伟大的事情？
- All the business started working out.
- 所有的生意都开始顺利进行。
I started traveling.
我开始旅行。
I started building startups.
我开始创办初创公司。
I started making money.
我开始赚钱了。
It all started when I switched to Mac.
这一切都是从我切换到 Mac 开始的。
- Listen, I kinda...
- 听着，我有点...
You're making me wanna switch to Mac.
你让我想切换到 Mac。
So I either use Linux inside Windows with WSL
所以我要么在 Windows 中 使用 Linux 并使用 WSL
or just- - Yeah.
或者只是- - 是的。
- Ubuntu, Linux.
- Ubuntu、Linux。
But Windows for most stuff,
但对于大多数东西来说，Windows
like editing or any Adobe products.
例如编辑或任何 Adob​​e 产品。
- Adobe stuff, right? - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- Adob​​e 的东西，对吧？ - 是啊，是啊，是啊。
Well you could use,
那么你可以使用，
I guess you could do Mac stuff there.
我想你可以在那里做 Mac 的事情。
- Yeah. - I wonder if I should switch.
- 是的。 - 我想知道我是否应该转换。
What do you miss about Windows?
您怀念 Windows 的什么？
What was the pros and cons?
有什么优点和缺点？
- I think the Finder is horrible in Mac.
- 我认为 Mac 上的 Finder 太糟糕了。
- What is horrible? - The Finder.
- 什么是可怕的？ - 发现者。
Oh, you don't know the Finder?
哦，你不知道Finder吗？
So there's the Windows Explorer.
于是就有了 Windows 资源管理器。
- Yeah. - Windows Explorer is amazing.
- 是的。 - Windows 资源管理器非常棒。
- Thank you for talking down.
- 谢谢你低声说话。
- Finder is strange, man.
- Finder 很奇怪，伙计。
There's like strange things.
好像有一些奇怪的事情。
There's this bug where if you send,
有一个错误，如果你发送，
like, attach a photo in WhatsApp or Telegram,
例如，在 WhatsApp 或 Telegram 中附上照片，
it just selects the whole folder
它只是选择整个文件夹
and you almost accidentally can click Enter
你几乎不小心可以 点击 Enter
and you send all your photos, all your files
然后你发送你所有的 照片，所有的文件
to this chat group, happened to my girlfriend.
这个聊天群，发生 在我女朋友身上。
She starts sending me photo, photo, photo, photo, photo.
她开始给我发照片、照片 、照片、照片、照片。
So Finder is very unusable, but it has Linux.
所以Finder非常不 好用，但是有Linux。
The whole thing is like, it's Unix based, right?
整个事情就像是，它是 基于 Unix 的，对吧？
- So you use the command like?
- 所以你使用这样的命令？
- Yeah, all the time.
- 是的，一直都是。
Like all the time.
就像一直以来一样。
And the cool thing is you can run,
最酷的是你可以跑步
I think it's like Unix, like Debian or whatever.
我认为它就像 Unix、Debian 或者其他什么。
You can run most Linux stuff on macOS,
你可以在 macOS 上运行大多数 Linux 东西，
which makes this very good for developments.
这对于发展 非常有利。
I have my Nginx server,
我有我的 Nginx 服务器，
if I'm not lazy and set up my staging on my laptop,
如果我不懒并在我的笔记本 电脑上设置我的舞台，
it's just the Nginx server.
这只是 Nginx 服务器。
The same as I have on my cloud server, right?
和我云服务器 上的一样吧？
The same way the websites run.
网站的运行方式相同。
And I can use almost everything, the same config files,
我几乎可以使用所有东西， 相同的配置文件，
configuration files, and it just works.
配置文件，然后它就可以工作了。
And that makes Mac a very good platform
这使得 Mac 成为一个非常好的平台
for Linux stuff, I think.
我认为对于 Linux 的东西。
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是啊是啊。
- Real Ubuntu is like better of course.
- 真正的 Ubuntu 当然更好。
- Yeah, I'm in this weird situation where I'm
- 是的，我现在 的处境很奇怪
somewhat of a power user in Windows,
Windows 中的高级用户，
and let's say Android
假设 Android
and all the much smarter friends I have
以及我所有聪明得多的朋友
all using Mac and iPhone.
全部使用 Mac 和 iPhone。
And it's like- - If you don't wanna
这就像- - 如果你不想
go through the peer pressure.
承受同侪压力。
- It's not peer pressure.
- 这不是同侪压力。
It's like one of the reasons I wanna have kids
这就像我想要 孩子的原因之一
is that there's a lot of...
是有很多...
I would love to have kids as a baseline,
我希望有孩子作为底线
but there's like a concern.
但有一个担忧。
Maybe there's gonna be a trade off,
也许会有一个权衡
or all this kind of stuff.
或所有此类的东西。
But you see like these extremely successful smart people
但你会看到这些非常 成功的聪明人
who are friends of mine,
谁是我的朋友，
who have kids and are really happy they have kids.
他们有孩子并且非常 高兴他们有孩子。
So that's not peer pressure,
所以这不是同侪压力
that's just like a strong signal.
这就像一个强烈的信号。
- Yeah, it works for people.
- 是的，它对人们有用。
- That works for people. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 这对人们有用。 - 是啊 ，是啊，是啊。
And the same thing with Mac.
Mac 也是如此。
It's like- - Yeah.
这就像- - 是 的。
(Lex exhales)
（莱克斯呼气）
- I don't see fundamentally,
- 我从根本上看不出来，
I don't like closed systems.
我不喜欢封闭的系统。
So fundamentally, I like Windows more
所以从根本上来说，我更喜欢Windows
because there's much more freedom.
因为有更多的自由。
Same with Android, there's much more freedom.
与 Android 一样 ，自由度更高。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- It's much more customizable.
- 它更加可定制。
But like all the cool kids,
但就像所有酷孩子一样
the smart kids are using Mac and iPhones.
聪明的孩子正在使用 Mac 和 iPhone。
All right, I need to really,
好吧，我真的需要，
I need to give it a real chance.
我需要给它一个真正的机会。
Especially for development,
尤其是对于发展来说，
since more and more stuff is done in the cloud anyway.
因为无论如何，越来越多 的事情是在云中完成的。
- Yeah. - Well, anyway.
- 是的。 - 好吧，无论如何。
But it's funny to hear you say all
但听到你说这一切很有趣
the good stuff started happening.
好事开始发生。
Maybe I'll be like that guy too.
也许我也会像那个人一样。
When I switched to Mac,
当我切换到 Mac 时，
all the good stuff- - Yeah.
所有的好东西--是 的。
- Started happening.
- 开始发生了。
- I think it's just about the hardware.
- 我认为这只是硬件的问题。
It's just much about the software that-
这与软件有关-
- Yeah. - The hardware
- 是的 。 - 硬件
is so well built, right?
建得这么好，对吧？
A keyboard and- - Yeah.
键盘和 - - 是 的。
But look at the keyboard I use.
但看看我使用的键盘。
- Yeah, that's pretty cool.
- 是的，那太酷了。
- That's one word for it.
- 这就是一个词。
What's your favorite place to work?
你最喜欢在哪里工作？
- On the couch.
- 在沙发上。
Does the couch matter?
沙发重要吗？
Is the couch at home or is it any couch?
沙发是家里的还是任何沙发？
- No, like hotel couch also.
- 不，也像酒店的沙发。
In the room, right? - In the room.
在房间里，对吗？ - 在房间里。
- Yeah, but I used to work like very ergonomically
- 是的，但我以前的工作方式 非常符合人体工程学
with like a standing desk.
像站立式办公桌一样。
- Yeah. - And everything like perfect,
- 是的 。 - 一切都那么完美，
like eye height, screen, blah, blah, blah.
比如眼高、屏幕等等。
And I felt like, man, this has to do with lifting too.
我觉得，伙计，这 也与举重有关。
I started getting RSI like repetitive strain injury,
我开始出现重复性 劳损等 RSI，
like tingling stuff.
像刺痛的东西。
And it would go all the way on my back.
它会一直压在我的背上。
And I was sitting in a coworking space like 6:00 AM,
早上 6:00 左右我坐 在联合办公空间里，
sun comes up and I'm working and I'm coding,
太阳升起，我在 工作，在编码，
and I hear like a sound or something.
我听到了某种声音或者什么东西。
So I do like, I look left
所以我喜欢，我向左看
and my neck gets stuck like (imitates cracking)
我的脖子被卡住了（ 模仿破裂的样子）
and I'm like, wow, fuck!
我就想，哇，操！
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
And I'm like, am I dying?
我想，我要死了吗？
And I thought, (Lex laughs)
我想，（莱克斯 笑）
I'm probably dying.
我可能快死了。
- Yeah, probably dying.
- 是的，可能快死了。
- I don't wanna die in a cowork space.
- 我不想死在共享空间里。
I'm gonna go home and die in like-
我要回家然后死掉——
- Yeah. - Peace and honor.
- 是的。 - 和平与荣誉。
- So I closed my laptop,
- 所以我合上了笔记本电脑
and I put it in my backpack.
我把它放进背包里。
- Yeah. - And I walked to the street.
- 是的 。 - 然后我走到街上。
I got on my motorbike, went home.
我骑上摩托车回家了。
- Yeah. - And I lie down
- 是的。 - 然后我躺下
on like a pillow,
像枕头一样放在上面，
with my legs up and stuff,
我的腿抬起来之类的，
to get rid of this like,
摆脱这个，就像
'cause it was my whole back.
因为那是我的整个背部。
And it was because I was working like this all the time.
这是因为我一直 都是这样工作的。
- Yeah. - So I started getting like a,
- 是的 。 - 所以我开始变得像，
a laptop stand, everything.
笔记本电脑支架，应有尽有。
Ergonomically correct.
符合人体工程学。
But then I started lifting and since then,
但后来我开始举重，从那时起，
it seems like everything gets straightened out.
似乎一切都变得 理顺了。
Your posture kinda, you're more straight.
你的姿势有点直。
And I never have RSI anymore, repetitive injury.
我再也没有出现重复性 损伤，重复性损伤。
I never have tingling anymore.
我再也没有刺痛过。
No pains and stuff.
没有痛苦之类的东西。
So then I started working on the sofa and it's great.
然后我开始在沙发 上工作，这很棒。
It feels close to the...
感觉很接近...
I sit like this.
我就这样坐着
- Yeah. - Legs together
- 是的。 - 双腿并拢
and then a pillow and then a laptop.
然后是枕头，然后是笔记本电脑。
And then I work.
然后我工作。
- Are you like leaning back?
- 你喜欢向后靠吗？
- I'm kind of like, together like legs,
- 我有点像，像双腿一样，
and then- - Where's the mouse?
然后- - 老鼠在哪里？
- No, so everything is tracked on the macOs, the MacBook.
- 不，所以一切都在 macO、MacBook 上进行跟踪。
I used to have the Logitech MX mouse,
我以前用过罗技MX鼠标，
the perfect ergonomic mouse.
完美的人体工学鼠标。
So you're just doing like this little thing with the thing.
所以你只是用这个 小东西做事。
- Yes. - One screen.
- 是的。 - 一个屏幕。
And I used to have three screens.
我以前有三个屏幕。
I know where people come from. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
我知道人们从哪里来。 - 是啊 ，是啊，是啊。
- I had all the stuff,
- 我拥有所有的东西，
but then I realized that having it all condensed
但后来我意识到把这 一切都浓缩起来
in one laptop, it's a 16 inch MacBook.
一台笔记本电脑是 16 英寸 MacBook。
So it's quite big.
所以它是相当大的。
But having it one there is amazing,
但拥有它真是太神奇了
'cause you're so close to the tools,
因为你离工具很近，
you're so close to what's happening.
你离正在发生的事情如此之近。
It's like working on a car or something.
这就像在汽车或其他东西上工作。
Man, if you have trees, you to look here,
伙计，如果你有树，你就看看这里，
look there, you get also neck injury actually.
看看那里，你的脖子实际上 也受伤了。
- Well, I don't know.
- 嗯，我不知道。
This sounds like you're part of a cult,
听起来你是邪教的一员
and you're just trying to convince me.
而你只是想说服我。
I mean, but it's good to hear
我的意思是，但很高兴听到
that you can be ultra productive on a single screen.
您可以在单个屏幕 上实现超高工作效率。
- Yeah. - I mean that's crazy.
- 是的。 - 我的意思是这太疯狂了。
- Come on tap, you all tap,
- 来吧，大家都点击，
Windows is all up tap, macros Command + Tap,
Windows 全部打开，点击 ，宏 Command + Tap，
you switch very fast. - So you have like one,
你切换得很快。 - 所以 你有一个这样的，
the entire screen is taken out by VS Code.
整个屏幕被VS Code取出来。
Say you look at the code and then-
假设你查看了代码，然后-
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And then if you deploy like a website, you what?
- 然后如果你像网站一样 部署，你会怎样？
Switch screens.
切换屏幕。
- Command + Tap to Chrome.
- Command + 点击以访问 Chrome。
I used to have this swipe screen,
我以前用过这个滑屏
you could do like different screen.
你可以做不同的屏幕。
- Yeah, yeah. - Spaces.
- 是啊是啊。 - 空格。
- Yeah. - I was like,
- 是的。 - 我当时想，
"Ah, it's too difficult."
“啊，太难了。”
Let's just put it all on one screen on the MacBook and then.
让我们将所有内容都放在 MacBook 的一个屏幕上，然后就可以了。
- And you can be productive that way?
- 这样你就能提高工作效率吗？
- Yeah, very productive, yeah.
- 是的，非常有成效，是的。
More productive than before. - Interesting.
比以前更有成效。 - 有趣的。
Because I have three screens,
因为我有三个屏幕，
then two of them are vertical.
然后其中两个是垂直的。
Like on the size? - Yeah, code,
喜欢尺寸吗？ - 是 的，代码，
right, yeah. - For the code,
对，是的。 - 对于代码，
you can see a lot. - Yeah.
你可以看到很多。 - 是的。
No man, I love it.
没有男人，我喜欢它。
I love seeing it with friends.
我喜欢和朋友一起看。
They have amazing like battle stations, right?
他们有令人惊叹的 战斗站，对吧？
- Yeah. - It's called.
- 是的。 - 这就是所谓的。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
I want it but I don't want it, right?
我想要它，但我不想要它，对吗？
- So you like the constraints.
- 所以你喜欢限制。
- [Pieter] That's it.
- [彼得] 就是这样。
- There's some aspect of the constraints,
- 有一些方面的限制，
which like once you get good at it,
就像一旦你擅长了，
you can focus your mind and you can.
你可以集中注意力，你可以的。
- Man, I'm suspicious of like more.
- 伙计，我怀疑更多。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Do you really need all the stuff?
- 你真的需要所有的东西吗？
It might slow me down, actually.
实际上，这可能会减慢我的速度。
- It's a good way to put it.
- 这是一个很好的表达方式。
I'm suspicious of more, me too.
我怀疑更多，我也是。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- I'm suspicious of more in all ways,
- 我在各方面都怀疑更多，
in all walks of life.
各行各业。
- 'Cause you can defend more, right?
- 因为你可以防守更多，对吗？
You can defend.
你可以防守。
Yeah, I'm a developer, I make money.
是的，我是开发商，我赚钱。
I need to get more screens, right?
我需要更多的屏幕，对吗？
I need to be more efficient.
我需要变得更有效率。
And then you read stuff about "Mythical Man-Month,"
然后你读到有关“ 人月神话”的内容，
where like hiring more people
哪里喜欢雇用更多人
slows down a software project that's famous.
减慢了一个著名的 软件项目的速度。
Think you can use a metaphor maybe for tools as well.
我想你也可以用 工具来比喻。
Then I see friends just with gear acquisition syndrome
然后我看到朋友患有 齿轮获取综合症
that buying so much stuff,
买了这么多东西，
but they're not that productive.
但他们的生产力并不高。
They have the best, most beautiful battle stations,
他们拥有最好、最 美丽的战斗站，
desktops, everything.
桌面，一切。
They're not that productive.
他们的生产力并不高。
And it's also like kind of fun.
这也很有趣。
It's all from my laptop in a backpack, right?
这些都来自我背包里的 笔记本电脑，对吗？
- Yeah. - It's kinda nomad minimalist.
- 是的。 - 这有点游牧极简主义。
- Take me through like the perfect
- 带我经历完美
ultra productive day in your life.
您生命中生产力最高的一天。
Say like where you get a lot of shit done.
比如说你在哪里做了很多事情。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And it's all focused on getting shit done.
- 这一切都集中在 完成任务上。
When are you waking up?
你什么时候起床？
Is it a regular time?
是常规时间吗？
Super early, super late?
超级早，超级晚？
- Yes, so I go to sleep like 2:00 AM usually,
- 是的，所以我通常在凌晨 2:00 左右睡觉，
something like that.
类似的事情。
And before 4:00 AM,
凌晨 4:00 之前，
but my girlfriend would go sleep midnight.
但我女朋友会半夜睡觉。
So we did a compromise like 2:00 AM you know,
所以我们做了妥协，比如 凌晨 2:00，你知道，
so I wake up around 10, 11.
所以我在10点、11点左右醒来。
The more like 10,
越多像10个，
shower, make coffee,
淋浴、煮咖啡、
I make coffee, like drip coffee,
我煮咖啡，像滴滤咖啡，
like the V60, you know the filter.
就像 V60 一样，您知道过滤器。
And I'd boil water and then I put the coffee in,
我会把水烧开，然后 把咖啡放进去，
and then chill, live with my girlfriend
然后冷静下来，和我女朋友住在一起
and then open laptops, start coding,
然后打开笔记本电脑，开始编码，
check what's going on, like bugs or whatever.
检查发生了什么，比如 错误或其他什么。
- How long are you, like how stretches of time
- 你有多长，就像 时间有多长
are you able to just sit behind the computer coding?
你能坐在电脑 后面编码吗？
- So I used to need like really long stretches
- 所以我以前需要很 长的伸展运动
where I would do like all nighters
我喜欢在哪里过夜
and stuff to get shit done.
以及完成任务的东西。
But I've gotten trained to like have more interruptions
但我已经习惯了 喜欢更多的打扰
where I can like-
我可以喜欢的地方-
- Because you have to. - This is life.
- 因为你必须这样做。 - 这就是生活。
There's a lot of distractions.
有很多干扰。
Your girlfriend asks stuff,
你女朋友问起事来，
people come over, whatever. - Yeah.
人们过来了，无论如何。 - 是 的。
- So I'm very fast now,
- 所以我现在速度很快
I can lock in and lock out quite fast.
我可以很快地锁定和锁定。
And heard people, developers or entrepreneurs
并听到人们、 开发人员或企业家
with kids have the same thing.
与孩子们也有同样的事情。
Before they're like, ah, I cannot work,
在他们说，啊，我无法工作之前，
but they get used to it,
但他们已经习惯了
and they get really productive in like short time,
他们在很短的时间 内就变得非常高效，
because they only have like 20 minutes
因为他们只有20分钟的时间
and then shit goes crazy again.
然后狗屎又变得疯狂了。
So another constraint, right?
那么另一个限制，对吗？
- Yeah, it's funny.
- 是的，这很有趣。
- So I think that works for me, but yeah.
- 所以我认为这对我有用，但是是的。
And then cook food and stuff,
然后做饭什么的，
like have lunch, steak and chicken and whatever.
比如吃午餐，牛排 和鸡肉等等。
- Do you eat a bunch of times a day?
- 你一天吃很多次吗？
So you said coffee.
所以你说的是咖啡。
- Yeah. - What are you doing?
- 是的 。 - 你在干什么？
- Yeah, so a few hours later cook foods.
- 是的，所以几个小时后做饭。
We get like locally stores like meat and stuff
我们像当地的商店一样 购买肉类和其他东西
and vegetables and cook that,
和蔬菜然后煮，
and then second coffee and then go some more.
然后喝第二杯咖啡 ，然后再喝一杯。
Maybe go outside for lunch.
也许去外面吃午饭。
You can mix fun stuff.
你可以混合有趣的东西。
- How many hours are you saying a perfectly productive day?
- 您所说的一天有多少小时 是完美高效的？
Are you doing programming?
你在做编程吗？
If you were like to kill it?
如果你想杀掉它？
Are you doing like all day basically?
你基本上整天都这样吗？
- You mean like the special days
- 你的意思是像特殊的日子
where like- - Special days.
比如——特殊 的日子。
- Girlfriend leaves to like bears or something,
- 女朋友离开去 喜欢熊什么的，
and you're alone for a week at home.
而你一个人在家待了一个星期。
Which is amazing. - Yes.
这太棒了。 - 是 的。
- You can just code.
- 你可以直接编码。
And you stay up all night and eat chocolate and-
然后你熬夜吃巧克力 然后-
- Yeah, chocolate. - Yeah, you know.
- 是的，巧克力。 - 是的，你知道。
- Yeah, yeah, okay, okay.
- 是啊，是啊，好吧，好吧。
Let's remove girlfriend from picture.
让我们把女朋友从照片中删除吧。
Social life from picture.
从图片中看社会生活。
It's just you.
这只是你。
- Man, then goes shit crazy.
- 伙计，然后就疯了。
- Yeah, because when shit goes crazy.
- 是的，因为当狗屎变得疯狂时。
- Yeah, now shit goes crazy.
- 是的，现在狗屎变得疯狂了。
- Okay, good.
- 好的，很好。
Let's rewind.
让我们回顾一下。
Are you still waking up?
你还醒着吗？
There's coffee, there's no girlfriend to talk to.
有咖啡，却没有女 朋友可以聊天。
There's no- - Now we wake up
没有--现在 我们醒来
(Lex and Pieter laughs)
（莱克斯和彼得笑了）
Like 1:00 PM or 2:00 PM.
例如下午 1:00 或下午 2:00。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
- Because you went to bed at 6:00 AM.
- 因为你早上 6:00 就睡觉了。
- Yeah, because I was coding,
- 是的，因为我正在编码，
I was finding some new AI shit.
我发现了一些新的人工智能狗屎。
- Yeah, yeah. - And I was studying it,
- 是啊是啊。 - 我正在研究它，
and it was amazing.
这太棒了。
And I cannot sleep 'cause it's too important.
我无法入睡，因为 这太重要了。
We need to stay awake. - Yeah, yeah.
我们需要保持清醒。 - 是啊是啊。
- We need to see all of this.
- 我们需要看到这一切。
We need to make something now.
我们现在需要做点什么。
But that's the times I do make new stuff more,
但那是我做更多 新东西的时候，
so I think I have a friend,
所以我想我有一个朋友
he actually books a hotel for like a week to leave his,
他实际上预订了一家酒店大约 一周的时间来离开他的，
and he has a kid too,
而且他还有一个孩子，
and his girlfriend and his kids stay in the house
他的女朋友和孩子们 住在房子里
and he goes to another hotel.
然后他去了另一家旅馆。
Sounds a little suspicious, right?
听起来有点可疑，对吧？
Going to the hotel.
要去酒店了。
But all he does (Lex laughs)
但他所做的一切 （Lex笑）
is like writing or coding. - Yeah.
就像写作或编码一样。 - 是 的。
- He's a writer,
- 他是一位作家，
and he needs like this alone time, this silence.
他需要这样独处的 时间，这样的安静。
And I think for this flow state, it's true.
我认为对于这种心流状态 来说，这是真的。
I'm better maintaining stuff
我更擅长维护东西
when there's a lot of disruptions
当有很多干扰时
then like creating new stuff.
然后喜欢创造新东西。
I need this.
我需要这个。
And it's common, it's close.
这很常见，也很接近。
It's this uninterrupted period of time.
这是一段不间断的时间。
So yeah, I wake up like one, 2:00 PM,
所以是的，我像下午 2:00 一样醒来，
still coffee, shower.
还是咖啡，淋浴。
We still shower, you know,
我们仍然洗澡，你知道，
and then this code like nonstop.
然后这段代码就像不间断的一样。
Maybe my friends comes over anyway.
也许我的朋友们无论如何都会过来。
- Just some distraction.
- 只是分散注意力。
- Yeah, Andre, he codes too.
- 是的，安德烈，他也编码。
So he comes over, we code together,
所以他过来了，我们一起编码，
we listen...
我们听...
It starts going back to like the Bali days,
它开始回到巴厘岛 的日子，
you know, like- - Yeah.
你知道，就像- - 是 的。
- Coworking days.
- 联合办公日。
- You're not really working with him,
- 你并没有真正和他一起工作
but you're just both working.
但你们都只是在工作。
- Because it's nice to have like the vibe
- 因为喜欢这种氛围真是太好了
where you both sit together on the couch
你们一起坐在沙发上
and coding on something and you actually,
并在某些东西上编码，而你实际上，
it's mostly silent or there's music,
大部分时间都很安静或者有音乐，
and sometimes you ask something.
有时你会问一些事情。
But generally, you are really locked in.
但一般来说，你确实被锁定了。
- What music are you listening to?
- 你在听什么音乐？
- I think like techno, like YouTube techno.
- 我觉得就像 techno， 就像 YouTube techno。
There's a channel called HOR with Umlaut,
有一个名为 HOR 的频道，带有 Umlaut，
HO like double dot.
HO 像双点。
It's Berlin techno, whatever.
无论如何，这是柏林科技。
It looks like they film it in like a toilet
看起来他们在厕所 里拍摄的
with like white tiles and stuff.
像白色瓷砖之类的东西。
And it's very cool.
这非常酷。
And they always have like, very good,
他们总是有这样的感觉，非常好，
kind of industrial. - Industrial, so fast phase.
工业的一种。 - 工业化 ，如此快速的阶段。
- Kinda aggressive, like (imitates techno music)
- 有点咄咄逼人，比如 （模仿电子音乐）
- Yeah, yeah.
- 是啊是啊。
That's not distracting to you brain.
这不会分散你的大脑注意力。
- That's amazing. - Okay.
- 太棒了。 - 好 的。
- I think distracting, man, jazz.
- 我认为爵士乐会让人分心。
I listen coffee jazz with my girlfriend when I wake up
当我醒来时，我和女 朋友一起听咖啡爵士乐
and it's kind of like, this piano starts getting annoying.
有点像，这架钢琴 开始变得烦人了。
It's like
就像
(imitates jazz music). (Lex laughs)
（模仿爵士乐）。 （ 莱克斯笑）
It's too many tones.
音调太多了。
It's like, too many things go on.
就像，太多的事情在发生。
- [Lex] Yeah, yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是啊，是啊。
- This industrial techno is like,
- 这种工业技术就像，
you know, these African rain dances.
你知道，这些非洲雨舞。
(imitates techno music)
（模仿电子音乐）
It's this transcendental- - Yeah.
这就是超验的——是 的。
- Trans. - That's interesting,
- 跨。 - 那很有意思，
'cause I actually mostly now listen to brown noise,
因为我现在主要 听棕色噪音
noise. - Yeah, wow.
噪音。 - 是的，哇。
- Pretty loud. - Wow.
- 声音很大。 - 哇。
- And one of the things you learn
- 你学到的东西之一
is your brain gets used to whatever.
你的大脑已经习惯了一切。
So I'm sure to techno,
所以我确信技术，
if I actually give it a real chance.
如果我真的给它一个真正的机会。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- My brain would get used to it.
- 我的大脑会习惯的。
But like with noise,
但就像噪音一样，
what happens is something happens to your brain.
所发生的事情是你的大脑 发生了一些事情。
I think there's a science to it,
我觉得这里面有科学道理
but I don't really care.
但我真的不在乎。
You just have to be a scientist of one.
你只需要成为一名科学家即可。
Study yourself,
研究一下自己，
your own brain. Yeah.
你自己的大脑。是 的。
- For me, it does something.
- 对我来说，它确实有作用。
I discovered it right away
我立刻就发现了
when I tried it for the first time.
当我第一次尝试的时候。
After about like a couple minutes,
大约几分钟后，
every distraction just like disappears.
所有的干扰都消失了。
And it goes like (imitates pressure deflating)
它就像（模仿压力 放气）
You can like hold focus on things like really well.
你可以很好地专注 于事情。
It's weird.
很奇怪。
You can like really focus on a thing.
你可以真正专注于一件事。
It doesn't really matter what that is.
那是什么并不重要。
I think that's what people achieve with like meditation.
我认为这就是人们通过 冥想所达到的目的。
You can like focus on your breath,
你可以喜欢专注于你的呼吸，
for example, for so long.
例如，这么长时间。
- It's just normal brown noise.
- 这只是正常的棕色噪音。
It's not like binaural.
这不像双耳。
- No, it's just normal brown noise.
- 不，这只是正常的棕色噪音。
- It's like shhhh. - Yeah.
- 就像嘘。 - 是 的。
- White noise, I think it's same.
- 白噪音，我认为是一样的。
It's like make noise, white noise.
这就像制造噪音，白噪音。
Brown noise I think is when it's like bassier.
我认为棕色噪音是 指低音的时候。
- Yeah, it's more diffused.
- 是的，它更加分散。
More dampened. - Yeah.
更受挫。 - 是 的。
- Yeah, yeah. - Dampened.
- 是啊是啊。 - 受潮了。
- Yeah, I can see that. - No sharpness.
- 是的，我看得出来。 - 没有清晰度。
- Yeah, sharp brightness. - Yeah, brightness.
- 是的，锐利的亮度。 - 是的，亮度。
- Yeah, I can see that.
- 是的，我看得出来。
And you use a headphones, right?
你还用耳机，对吧？
- Yeah, headphones. - Yeah.
- 是的，耳机。 - 是 的。
- I actually like, walk around in life
- 我其实很喜欢，在生活中走来走去
often with brown noise. - Dude,
经常伴有棕色噪音。 - 伙计 ，
that's like psycho batshit.
这就像精神病一样。
But it's cool. (Lex laughs)
但这很酷。 （ 莱克斯笑）
- Yeah, yeah, yeah.
- 是啊，是啊，是啊。
When I murder people, it helps.
当我杀人时，这会有所帮助。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
It drowns out their screams.
它淹没了他们的尖叫声。
- Jesus Christ. - I'm sorry,
- 耶稣基督。 - 对不起，
I said too much.
我说太多了。
- Man, I'm gonna try brown noise.
- 伙计，我要尝试棕色噪音。
- With a murder or for the coding?
- 谋杀还是编码？
Yeah. - For the coating, yeah.
是的。 - 对于涂层，是的。
- Okay, good.
- 好的，很好。
Try it, try it.
试试吧，试试吧。
But you have to like, with everything else,
但你必须喜欢，和 其他一切一样，
you give it a real chance. - Yeah.
你给它一个真正的机会。 - 是 的。
- I also, like I said,
- 我也，就像我说的，
do techno type stuff.
做技术类型的东西。
Electronic music on top of the brown noise,
棕色噪音之上 的电子音乐，
but then control the speed,
但随后控制速度，
'cause the faster it goes, the more anxiety.
因为进展得越快 ，就越焦虑。
So if I really need to get shit done,
所以如果我真的需要完成一些事情
especially with programming, I'll have a beat.
尤其是编程，我会 很开心。
- Yeah. - And it's great.
- 是的。 - 这太棒了。
It's cool.
这很酷。
Say is cool to play those little tricks
说玩这些小把戏很酷
of your mind to study yourself.
你的思想去研究你自己。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- I usually don't like to have people around,
- 我通常不喜欢 有人在身边
'cause when people,
因为当人们，
even if they're working,
即使他们在工作，
I don't know, I like people too much.
我不知道，我太喜欢别人了。
They're like, interesting.
他们就像，有趣。
- There might be, yeah.
- 可能有，是的。
In coworker space, I would just start talking too much.
在同事空间里，我 会开始说太多话。
- Yeah. - Yeah, yeah.
- 是的。 - 是啊是啊。
- So there's a source of distraction.
- 所以有一个干扰源。
- Yeah, in the cowork space,
- 是的，在共享办公空间，
we would do like a money pot, like a mug.
我们会像一个钱罐，像一个杯子。
So we'd work for 45 minutes
所以我们会工作45分钟
and then if you would say, like pair of words,
然后如果你会说， 就像一对词一样，
you would get a fine, which is like $1.
你会被处以 1 美元左右的罚款。
So you'd put $1 to say, "Hey, what's up?"
所以你会投入 1 美元来问：“嘿，怎么了？”
So $3 you put in the mug,
所以你把 3 美元放进杯子里，
and then 15 minutes free time.
然后是15分钟的自由时间。
We can like party, whatever.
我们可以喜欢派对，无论什么。
And then 45 minutes again working.
然后又工作了 45 分钟。
And that works.
那行得通。
But you need to shut people up or they, you know.
但你需要让人们闭嘴，否则 他们，你知道。
- I think there's an intimacy in being silent together-
-我觉得在一起沉默 有一种亲密感-
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Maybe I'm uncomfortable with.
- 也许我不舒服。
If you need to make yourself vulnerable
如果你需要让自己变得脆弱
and actually do it, like with close friends
并实际去做，就像 和亲密的朋友一样
to just sit there in silence
静静地坐在那里
for long periods of time. - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
很长一段时间。 - 是啊 ，是啊，是啊。
- And like doing a thing.
- 喜欢做一件事。
- Dude, I watched this video of this podcast.
- 伙计，我看了这个 播客的视频。
It was like this Buddhism podcast with people meditating,
就像这个佛教播客 ，人们在冥想，
and they were interviewing each other or whatever,
他们正在互相采访 或者其他什么，
and like a podcast.
就像播客一样。
And suddenly after a question, it's like, yeah, yeah.
突然问完一个问题，就好像 ，是啊，是啊。
And they were just silent for like three minutes.
他们沉默了大约 三分钟。
And then they said it was amazing.
然后他们说这太棒了。
Yeah, it was amazing.
是的，太棒了。
I was like, wow, pretty cool.
我当时想，哇，太酷了。
- Elon is like that.
- 埃隆就是这样。
And I really like that,
我真的很喜欢这样，
he'll ask a question.
他会问一个问题。
I don't know, what's a perfectly productive day for you?
我不知道，对你来说，哪一天 是最高效的一天？
Like I just asked,
就像我刚才问的，
and you just sit there for like 30 seconds thinking.
然后你就坐在那里 思考 30 秒。
- Yeah, he thinks.
- 是的，他想。
- Yeah, I don't know.
- 是的，我不知道。
- That's so cool.
- 太酷了。
I wish I could think more about,
我希望我能多思考一下
but I wanna show you my heart.
但我想向你展示我的心。
I wanna show you...
我想给你看...
go straight from my heart
直接从我的心里走
to my mouth to like saying the real thing.
喜欢说真话。
And the more I think the more I start
我越想就越开始
like filtering myself, right?
就像过滤自己一样，对吧？
And I wanna just throw it out there immediately.
我想立即把 它扔掉。
- I do that more with team.
- 我和团队一起做更多的事情。
I think he has a lot of practice in that.
我认为他在这方面有很多练习。
I do that as well.
我也这样做。
And in team setting, when you're thinking,
在团队环境中，当你思考时，
brainstorming. - Yeah.
集思广益。 - 是 的。
- And you allow yourself to just like, think in silence.
- 你允许自己静静 地思考。
- Yeah. - Just like,
- 是的。 - 就像，
'cause even in meetings, people wanna talk.
因为即使在会议上，人们 也想交谈。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- It's like, no, you think before you speak
- 就像，不，你说话 之前要先思考一下
and just like, it's okay to be silent together.
就像，一起沉默 也没关系。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And if you allow yourself the room to do that,
- 如果你给自己空间 去做这件事，
you can actually come up with really good ideas.
你实际上可以想出 非常好的主意。
- Yeah. - So, okay, this perfect day,
- 是的。 - 所以，好吧，这完美的一天，
(laughs) how much caffeine are you consuming in this day?
（笑）你今天摄入 了多少咖啡因？
- Man, too much, right?
- 伙计，太多了，对吧？
Because normally like two cups of coffee.
因为平时喜欢喝两杯咖啡。
But on this perfect day, we go to four maybe.
但在这个完美的一天，我们 也许会去四个。
So we're starting to hit the anxiety levels.
所以我们开始达到 焦虑水平。
- So four cups is a lot for you?
- 所以四杯对你来说很多了？
- Well, I think my coffees
- 嗯，我想我的咖啡
are quite strong when I make them.
当我制作它们时它们非常坚固。
It's like 20 grams of coffee powder in the V60.
相当于V60中的 20克咖啡粉。
So my friends call 'em like nuclear coffee
所以我的朋友们称它们为核咖啡
'cause it's quite heavy. - Yeah, super strong.
因为它相当重。 - 是 啊，超级强。
- It's quite strong.
- 相当强。
But it's nice to hit that anxiety level
但达到焦虑水平是件好事
where you're like almost panic attack.
你几乎惊恐发作。
- Yeah. - But you're not there yet.
- 是的 。 - 但你还没到那儿。
But that's like, man, it's like super locked in.
但这就像，伙计，这 就像超级锁定一样。
Just like (imitates intense music)
就像（模仿激烈的音乐）
It's amazing.
太棒了。
But I mean there's a space for that in my life.
但我的意思是我的 生活中有一个空间。
But I think it's great for making new stuff.
但我认为这对于创造新 东西来说非常有用。
It's amazing.
太棒了。
- Starting from scratch, creating a new thing.
- 从头开始​​， 创造新事物。
- Yes, I think girlfriends should let their guys
- 是的，我认为女朋友应该 让她们的男人
go away for like two weeks.
离开两周左右。
Every few, no, every year at least.
每隔几次，不，至少每年。
Maybe every quarter, I dunno.
也许每个季度，我不知道。
And just sit and make some shit without,
就坐下来做点什么吧，
they're amazing but like no disturbance.
他们很棒，但就像没有打扰一样。
Just be alone.
就一个人呆着吧。
And then people can make something very, very amazing.
然后人们就可以创造出 非常非常令人惊奇的东西。
- Just wearing cowboy hats in the mountains like we showed.
- 就像我们展示的那样， 在山里戴着牛仔帽。
- Exactly, we can do that.
- 确实，我们可以做到。
- There's a movie about that. - With the laptops.
-有一部电影就是关于这个的。 - 与笔记本电脑。
- They didn't do much programming though.
- 不过他们没有做太多编程。
- Yeah, you can do a little bit of that.
- 是的，你可以做一点。
- Okay.
- 好的。
- And then a little bit of shipping.
- 然后是一点点运输。
You could do both.
你可以两者都做。
- It's a different, "Brokeback Mountain."
- 这是一个不同的，“断背山”。
- They need to allow us to go.
- 他们需要让我们走。
They need like a man cave, right?
他们需要一个男人的洞穴，对吧？
- Yeah, to ship.
- 是的，运送。
(Lex laughs)
- 是的，运送。 （ 莱克斯笑）
- Get shit done, yeah.
- 完成任务，是的。
It's a balance, okay, cool.
这是一个平衡，好吧，很酷。
What about sleep, naps and all that?
睡眠、小睡等等呢？
You not sleeping much?
你睡得不多吗？
- I don't do naps in the day.
- 我白天不小睡。
I think power naps are good,
我觉得小睡一下很好
but I'm never tired anymore in the day.
但白天我再也不会感到疲倦了。
Man, also 'cause of gym, I'm not tired.
伙计，也是因为健身，我不累。
I'm tired when I wanna...
当我想...的时候我很累
When it's night, I need to sleep.
到了晚上，我需要睡觉。
- Yeah, me, I love naps. - I sleep very well.
- 是的，我，我喜欢小睡 。 - 我睡得很好。
- I love naps.
- 我喜欢小睡。
- Yeah. - I don't care.
- 是的。 - 我不在乎。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I don't know why, brain shuts off, turns on.
不知道为什么，大脑突然 关闭，又打开。
I dunno if it's healthy or not.
我不知道它是否健康。
It just works. - Yeah.
它就是有效的。 - 是的。
- I think with anything mental, physical,
- 我认为任何精神上的、身体上的、
you have to be a student of your own body
你必须成为自己身体的学生
and like- - Yeah, yeah, yeah.
就像--是的 ，是的，是的。
- Know what the limits are.
- 知道限制是什么。
You have to be skeptical taking advice
你必须持怀疑态度接受建议
from the internet in general,
一般从互联网上来看，
'cause a lot of the advice is just like a good baseline
因为很多建议就 像一个好的基线
for the general population. - It's not personalized, yeah.
对于一般人群。 - 这 不是个性化的，是的。
- You have to become a student of your own-
-你必须成为 自己的学生-
- Yeah. - Like of your own body,
- 是的。 - 就像你自己的身体一样，
of your own self,
属于你自己，
of how you work, yeah.
你的工作方式，是的。
I've done a lot of and just like,
我已经做了很多，就像，
for me, fasting was an interesting one,
对我来说，禁食是一件有趣的事情，
because I used to eat a bunch of meals a day,
因为我以前一 天吃很多顿饭
especially when I was lifting heavy.
尤其是当我举起重物时。
'Cause everybody says, "You have to eat,"
因为每个人都说“你必须吃饭”
kind of a lot, multiple meals a day.
种类很多，一天吃好几顿饭。
But I realize I can get much stronger,
但我意识到我可以变得更坚强
feel much better if I eat once or twice a day on.
如果我每天吃一到两 次，感觉好多了。
- Yeah, me too, yeah. - It's crazy.
- 是的，我也是，是的。 - 太疯狂了。
- I never understood this small meal thing, yeah.
- 我从来不理解这顿小饭 的事，是的。
It didn't work for me.
这对我不起作用。
- Well, let me just ask you,
- 好吧，让我问你，
it'd interesting if you can comment
如果你能评论的话会很有趣
on some of the other products you've created.
在您创建的一些 其他产品上。
We talked about Nomad List, Interior AI,
我们讨论了 Nomad List、Interior AI、
Photo AI, Therapist AI.
照片人工智能、治疗师人工智能。
What's RemoteOK?
什么是RemoteOK？
- It's a job board for remote jobs.
- 这是远程工作的工作委员会。
Because back then, like 10 years ago there was job boards,
因为那时候，就像 10 年前，有招聘委员会，
but it was not really specifically remote job, job boards.
但这并不是真正专门的远程工作 、工作委员会。
So I made one...
所以我做了一个...
First of all, Nomad List is I made like nomad jobs,
首先，Nomad List是我像 游牧工作一样制作的，
like a page.
就像一页。
And a lot of companies started hiring
很多公司开始招聘
and they pay for job posts.
他们为职位付费。
So I spin it off to RemoteOK.
所以我将其分离到 RemoteOK。
And now it's like this number one
现在就像这个第一
or number two biggest remote job boards.
或排名第二的远程工作委员会。
And it's also fully automated
而且它也是完全自动化的
and people just post a job and people apply.
人们只需发布一份工作 ，然后就可以申请。
It has like profiles as well.
它也有类似的配置文件。
It's kinda like LinkedIn for remotes work.
它有点像用于远程工作的 LinkedIn。
- So's focus on remote only. - Yeah.
- 所以我们只关注远程。 - 是 的。
It's essentially like a simple job board.
它本质上就像一个简单的工作板。
I discover job boards
我发现工作委员会
are way more complicated than you think.
比你想象的要复杂得多。
Yeah, it's a job board for remote jobs.
是的，这是一个远程工作的工作委员会。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
But the nice thing is you can
但好处是你可以
charge a lot of money for job posts.
为招聘职位收取大量费用。
Man, it's good money.
伙计，钱真好赚。
B2B, you can charge like,
B2B，你可以这样收费，
you start with 299.
你从299开始。
But at the peak when the Fed started printing money, 2021.
但在美联储开始印钞 的高峰期是 2021 年。
I was making like 140K a month with RemoteOK,
我通过 RemoteOK 每个 月赚了 14 万左右，
with just job posts.
只有职位信息。
And I started like adding crazy upsells,
我开始喜欢添加疯狂的追加销售，
like rainbow color,
像彩虹一样的颜色，
it's job posts.
这是工作岗位。
You can add your background images.
您可以添加背景图像。
- Yeah. - It's just upsells man.
- 是的。 - 这只是加价，伙计。
And you charge $1,000 for an upsell.
您对追加销售收取 1,000 美元的费用。
It was crazy.
太疯狂了。
And all these companies is up so up.
所有这些公司都上涨了。
So yeah, we want everything.
所以是的，我们想要一切。
Job post would cost 3,000, $4,000.
职位发布费用为 3,000 至 4,000 美元。
And I was like, this is good business.
我当时想，这是一笔好生意。
And then the Fed stopped printing money
然后美联储停止印钞
and it all went down,
一切都结束了，
and it went down to like 10K a month from 140.
每月从 140 降到 10K 左右。
- Yeah. - Now it's back.
- 是的。 - 现在它回来了。
I think it's like 40.
我觉得40左右吧
It was good times.
那是美好的时光。
- I gotta ask you about back to the digital nomad life.
- 我想问你关于回到数字 游牧生活的事情。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- You wrote a blog post on the reset.
- 你写了一篇关于重置的博文。
And in general, just giving away everything,
一般来说，只要 放弃一切，
living a minimalist life.
过着极简主义的生活。
- Yeah. - What did it take to do that,
- 是的。 - 需要什么才能做到这一点，
like to get rid of everything?
想要摆脱一切？
- 10 years ago was like this trend in the blog.
- 10年前博客中就 有这样的趋势。
Back then blogs were so popular.
当时博客非常流行。
It was a blogosphere,
这是一个博客圈，
and it was like 100 things challenge.
这就像 100 件事的挑战。
- What is that?
- 那是什么？
The 100 things challenge. - I mean, it's ridiculous.
100 件事挑战。 - 我的意思 是，这太荒谬了。
But like you write down every object you have in your house
但就像你写下你家 里所有的物品一样
and you count it, you make a spreadsheet
然后你数一下，然后制作一个电子表格
and you're like, "Okay, I have 500 things."
你会说，“好吧，我有 500 件东西。”
You need to get it down to 100.
你需要把它降到100。
Why?
为什么？
This just the trend, so I did it.
这只是趋势，所以我就这么做了。
I started like selling stuff, started throwing away off.
我开始喜欢卖东西 ，开始扔掉。
And I did like MDMA and ecstasy like 2012 kind of.
我确实喜欢摇头丸和摇头丸 ，就像 2012 年那样。
And after that trip, I felt so different,
那次旅行之后我感觉很不一样
and I felt like I had to start throwing shit away.
我觉得我必须开始 扔垃圾了。
I swear. - Yeah.
我发誓。 - 是的。
- And I started throwing shit away.
- 然后我开始扔垃圾。
And I felt that was like,
我觉得就像是，
it was almost the drug sending me to a path of like,
这几乎是毒品让我走上 了一条类似的道路，
you need to throw all your shit away.
你需要把你所有的狗屎都扔掉。
You need to start go on a journey.
你需要开始一段旅程。
You need to get out of here.
你需要离开这里。
And that's what the MDMA did, I think, yeah.
我想这就是摇头丸 所做的，是的。
- How hard is it to get down to 100 items?
- 减少到 100 件有多难？
- Boy, you need to like, sell your PC and stuff.
- 男孩，你需要喜欢，卖掉 你的电脑和东西。
You need to go on eBay
你需要去 eBay
and then, man, going eBay,
然后，伙计，去易趣，
selling all your stuff is balancing,
卖掉你所有的东西是平衡的，
'cause you discover society.
因为你发现了社会。
You meet the craziest people.
你会遇到最疯狂的人。
You meet every range from rich to poor,
你会遇到从富人到穷人的各种阶层，
everybody comes to your house to buy stuff.
每个人都来你家 买东西。
It's so funny, so interesting.
真是太搞笑了，太有趣了。
I recommend everybody do this.
我建议大家都这样做。
- Just to meet people that want your shit.
- 只是为了遇见那些想要你的东西的人。
- Yeah, it was so like, I didn't know,
- 是的，就像，我不知道，
I wasn't living in Amsterdam,
我不住在阿姆斯特丹
and I didn't know,
我不知道，
I have my own subculture or whatever.
我有自己的亚文化或其他什么。
And I discovered the Dutch people,
我发现了荷兰人，
like as they are from eBay.
就像它们来自 eBay 一样。
So I sold everything.
所以我卖掉了所有东西。
- What's the weirdest thing you had to sell
- 你卖过的最奇怪 的东西是什么
and you had to find a buyer for,
你必须找到买家，
not the weirdest, but like, what's memorable?
不是最奇怪的，但是， 什么是令人难忘的？
- So back then I was making music
- 所以那时我正在创作音乐
and we would make music videos
我们会制作音乐视频
with like a Canon 5D camera. - Yeah.
像佳能 5D 相机一样。 - 是 的。
- Back then everybody's making films and musicals.
- 那时每个人都在制作 电影和音乐剧。
And we bought it with my friends and stuff.
我们和我的朋友 一起买了它。
And it was kind of like, I had to sell this thing too,
有点像，我也必须 卖掉这个东西，
'cause it was very expensive.
因为它非常昂贵。
It was like 6K or something.
好像是6K之类的。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- But it meant that selling this,
- 但这意味着卖掉这个，
meant that we wouldn't make music theater anymore.
这意味着我们不会 再制作音乐剧了。
I would leave Holland.
我会离开荷兰。
This kind of stuff we were working on would end.
我们正在做的这 类事情将会结束。
And I was kind of saying this music theater stuff,
我想说的是音乐剧 的东西，
we're not getting famous in this or successful.
我们并没有因此而 出名或成功。
We need to stop doing this.
我们需要停止这样做。
This music production also, it's not really working.
这个音乐制作也没有 真正发挥作用。
And it was kinda like, felt very bad for my friends,
这有点像，为我的朋友们 感到非常难过，
'cause we would work together on this
因为我们会在这方面共同努力
and to sell this camera that we'd make stuff with.
并出售我们用来制作 东西的相机。
- It was a hard goodbye.
- 这是一次艰难的告别。
- It was just a camera, but it was like,
- 这只是一台相机，但它就像，
it felt like, sorry guys,
感觉就像，对不起，伙计们，
it doesn't work and I need to go.
它不起作用，我得走了。
- Who bought it?
- 谁买的？
Do you remember?
你是否记得？
It was some guy who couldn't possibly understand
这是一个不 可能理解的人
the journey. - The emotion of it.
旅程。 - 它的情感。
- Yeah.
- 是的。 - 是的。
- He just showed up,
- 他刚刚出现，
here's the money, thanks.
这是钱，谢谢。
- Yeah, but it was like cutting your life.
- 是的，但这就像切断你的生命。
This shit ends now and now we gonna do new stuff.
这狗屎现在结束了，现在 我们要做新的事情了。
- I think it's beautiful.
- 我觉得很漂亮。
I did that twice in my life.
我一生中做过两次这样的事。
I give away everything, everything, everything.
我放弃一切， 一切，一切。
- Wow. - Like down to just pants,
- 哇。 - 就像只剩下裤子一样，
underwear, backpack. - Yeah.
内衣，背包。 - 是 的。
- I think it's important to do.
- 我认为这很重要。
It shows you what's important.
它向您展示什么是重要的。
- Yeah, I think that's what I learned from it.
- 是的，我想这就是 我从中学到的东西。
You learn that you can live a very little objects
你知道你可以靠 很少的物体生存
very little stuff,
东西很少，
but there's a counter to it.
但有一个反驳的办法。
You lean more on the stuff, on the services, right?
你更依赖于东西、 服务，对吧？
Like for example, you don't need a car,
比如说，你不需要汽车，
you use Uber, right?
你用Uber，对吧？
Or you don't need kitchen stuff
或者你不需要厨房用品
because you go to restaurants when you're traveling.
因为你旅行时会 去餐馆。
So you lean more on other people's services,
所以你更多地依赖 别人的服务，
but spend money on that as well.
但也要为此花钱。
So that's good. - Yeah, but just letting go
所以这样很好 。 - 是的，但只是放手
of material possessions,
物质财富，
which it gives a kind of freedom
它赋予了一种自由
to how you move about the world.
到你如何在这个世界上移动。
- Yeah. - It gives you
- 是的 。 - 它给你
complete freedom to go into another city to-
完全自由地进入另 一个城市——
- Yeah, with your backpack.
- 是的，带着你的背包。
- The backpack. - Yeah.
- 背包。 - 是 的。
- There's a kind of freedom to it.
- 有一种自由。
There's something about material possessions
有一些关于物质 财富的东西
and having a place and all that,
并拥有一个地方以及所有这些，
that ties you down a little bit.
这会让你有点束缚。
- Yeah. - Like spiritually.
- 是的。 - 就像精神上的。
- It's good to take a leap
- 是的 。 - 跳跃是件好事
alternate into the world.
交替进入世界。
Especially when you're younger to like.
尤其是年轻的时候更喜欢。
- Man, I recommend if you're 18,
- 伙计，如果你18岁，我建议你，
you get out of high school,
你从高中毕业，
do this, go travel,
做到这一点，去旅行，
and build some internet stuff, whatever.
并建立一些互联网的东西，无论如何。
Bring your laptop.
带上你的笔记本电脑。
It's amazing experience.
这是一次奇妙的经历。
Five years ago, it's still good in university,
五年前，大学 里还是不错的，
but now I'm thinking like,
但现在我想，
no, maybe skip university.
不，也许跳过大学。
Just go first, like travel around a little bit,
先走吧，喜欢到处 走走，
figure some stuff out.
弄清楚一些事情。
You can go back to university when you're 25.
25岁就可以 重返大学。
You can like, okay, now I learned,
你可以喜欢，好吧，现在我学会了，
I'd be successful in business.
我会在商业上取得成功。
You have money at least.
你至少有钱。
Now you can choose what you really wanna study.
现在你可以选择你真正 想学习的内容。
Because people at 18,
因为18岁的人，
they go study what's probably good
他们去研究什么可能是好的
for the job market, right?
为了就业市场，对吗？
So it probably makes more sense.
所以这可能更有意义。
If you want that, go travel,
如果你想要的话，就去旅行吧
build some businesses,
建立一些企业，
and go back to university if you want.
如果你愿意的话，可以回到大学。
- So one of the biggest uses
- 所以最大的用途之一
of a university is the networking.
大学的本质就是网络。
You gain friends, you gain, like you meet people.
你会收获朋友，你会收获 ，就像你结识了人一样。
It's a forcing function to meet people.
与人见面是一种强迫功能。
But if you can meet people out
但如果你能出去认识人
to the world- - Travel.
走向世界—— 旅行。
- By travel.
- 通过旅行。
- Man, and you meet so many different cultures.
- 伙计，你会遇到 很多不同的文化。
- I mean, the problem for me is like if I traveled
- 我的意思是，对我来说 问题就像我旅行一样
at that young age, I'm attracted
在那个年纪，我就被吸引了
to people at the outskirts of the world.
给世界郊区的人们。
Like for me- - Like where?
喜欢我- -喜欢 哪里？
- Not geographically. - Oh, like the subcultures.
- 不是地理上的。 - 哦，就像亚文化。
- Yeah, like the weirdos,
- 是啊，就像那些怪人一样，
the darkness. - Yeah.
黑暗。 - 是 的。
Yeah, me too.
是的，我也是。
- But that might not be the best networking at 18 years old.
- 但这可能不是 18 岁时 最好的社交方式。
(Lex and Pieter laughs)
（莱克斯和彼得笑了）
- No, man, if you're smart about it,
- 不，伙计，如果你聪明的话，
you can stay safe.
你可以保持安全。
And I met so many weirdos from traveling.
我在旅行中遇到了很多奇怪的人。
That's how travel works.
这就是旅行的运作方式。
If you really let loose, you meet the craziest people.
如果你真的放松，你就会 遇到最疯狂的人。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And it's the most interesting people.
- 这是最有趣的人。
And I cannot recommend it enough.
我极力推荐它。
- Well see, the other thing is that when you're 18,
- 好吧，另一件事是 当你18岁时，
I feel like depending on your personality,
我觉得要看你的性格
you have to learn both how to be a weirdo
你必须学会​​如何成为一个怪人
and how to be a normie.
以及如何成为一个正常人。
You still have to learn how to fit into society.
你还是要学会如何 融入社会。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- For a person like me, for example,
- 例如，对于像我这样的人来说，
who's always an outcast.
谁总是一个被遗弃的人。
There's always a danger for going full outcast.
被彻底抛弃的危险 总是存在的。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- And that's a harder life if you,
- 如果你的生活会更艰难，
if you go to like, go full artists in full like darkness,
如果你去喜欢，去像 黑暗一样充满艺术家，
it's just a harder life. - You can come back,
这只是一种更艰难的生活 。 - 你可以回来了
you can come back to normie.
你可以回到常态。
- That's a skill.
- 这是一项技能。
I think you have to learn- - You think?
我认为你必须学习--你 认为呢？
- How to fit in to polite society.
- 如何融入有礼貌的社会。
- But I was very strange outcast as well.
- 但我也是一个非常奇怪的被遗弃者。
And I'm more adaptable to normie now.
我现在更能适应常态了。
- You learned it, yeah, learned it.
- 你学会了，是的，学会了。
- After 30s, you're like, yeah.
- 30岁以后，你会说，是的。
- But you need a skill, you have to learn.
- 但你需要一项技能，你必须学习。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
Man, I feel also that,
哥们，我也觉得，
you start as an outcast,
你一开始是一个被遗弃的人，
but the more you work on yourself,
但你越为自己努力，
the less like shit you have.
你拥有的东西就越少。
You kind of start becoming more normie,
你开始变得更加正常，
because you become more chill with yourself and more happy.
因为你对自己变得更加 冷静，更加快乐。
And it kind of makes you uninteresting, right?
这会让你变得无趣 ，对吧？
- Yes. - A little bit.
- 是的 。 - 一点点。
- Yes, yes.
- 是的，是的。
- The crazy people are always the most interesting.
- 疯狂的人总是 最有趣的。
If you've solved your internal struggles
如果你已经解决了内心的挣扎
and you therapy and stuff
还有你的治疗之类的
and you kind of become kind of,
你会变得有点
you know, it's not so interesting anymore maybe.
你知道，也许它 不再那么有趣了。
- You don't have to be broken to be interesting,
- 你不必被打破 才有趣，
I guess is what I'm saying.
我想这就是我所说的。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- What kind of things were left when you minimalized?
- 最小化后还 剩下什么？
- So the backpack. - Yeah.
- 所以背包。 - 是 的。
- MacBook, toothbrush,
- MacBook、牙刷、
some clothes, underwear, socks.
一些衣服，内衣，袜子。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- You don't need a lot of clothes in Asia
- 在亚洲你不需要很多衣服
'cause it's hot.
因为天气很热。
So you just wear swim pants, swim shorts.
所以你就穿泳裤、泳裤。
You walk around flip flops.
你穿着人字拖走来走去。
So very basic, T-shirt,
非常基本的T恤，
and go to the laundromat and wash my stuff.
去自助洗衣店洗 我的东西。
And I think it was like 50 things or something, yeah.
我想大概有 50 件事 之类的，是的。
- Yeah, it's nice.
- 是的，这很好。
As I mentioned to you, there's the show alone.
正如我向你提到 的，只有演出。
- Yeah. - They really test you,
- 是的。 - 他们真的在考验你，
'cause, oh, you only get 10 items,
因为，哦，你只能得到 10 件物品，
and you have to survive out in the wilderness.
你必须在荒野 中生存。
And then ax, like everybody brings an ax.
然后是斧头，就像每个人都带斧头一样。
Some people
有些人
also have a saw.
还有一把锯子。
- Wow.
- 哇。
- But usually ax does the job.
- 但通常斧头可以完成这项工作。
You basically have to,
你基本上必须，
in order to build a shelter,
为了建造一个避难所，
you have to cut down and to cut the trees and make,
你必须砍伐树木 并制作，
and like- - Learn Minecraft.
以及像- - 学习 Minecraft。
- Everything I learned about life,
- 我学到的关于生活的一切，
(Pieter laughs) I learn Minecraft, bro.
（彼得笑）我学习 《我的世界》，兄弟。
Yeah, yeah, you could.
是的，是的，你可以。
It's nice to create those constraints
很高兴创建这些约束
for yourself to understand what matters to you
让自己了解什么对你 来说是重要的
and also how to be in this world.
以及如何存在于这个世界上。
And one of the ways to do that
做到这一点的方法之一
is just to live a minimalist life.
只是为了过一种极简的生活。
But some people,
但有些人，
I've met people that really enjoy material possessions
我遇到过真正享受 物质财富的人
and that brings some happiness,
并带来一些快乐，
and that's a beautiful thing. - Yeah.
这是一件美好的事情。 - 是 的。
- For me, it doesn't,
- 对我来说，不是，
but people are different.
但人是不同的。
- It gives me happiness for like two weeks.
- 它给了我大约两 周的快乐。
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- I'm very quickly adapting to like a baseline.
- 我很快就适应 了基线。
Hedonistic adaptation very fast.
享乐主义适应非常快。
- Yeah. - But man,
- 是的。 - 但是伙计，
if you look at the studies,
如果你看看研究，
most people like get a new car six months,
大多数人喜欢六个月买一辆新车，
get a new house six months,
六个月后买新房，
you just feel the same.
你只是有同感。
She's like, wow, should I buy all this stuff?
她说，哇，我应该买 所有这些东西吗？
Studying hedonistic adaptation
研究享乐主义适应
made me think a lot about minimalism.
让我对极简主义有了很多思考。
- And so that you don't even need to go
- 这样你甚至不需要去
through the whole journey of getting it.
贯穿整个获取过程。
Just focus on the thing that's more permanent.
只专注于更持久 的事情。
- Yeah. - Like building shit.
- 是的。 - 就像建造垃圾一样。
- Yeah, like people around you, like people you love.
- 是的，就像你周围的 人，就像你爱的人。
Nice food, nice experiences. - Yeah.
美味的食物，美好的经历。 - 是 的。
- Meaningful work, those things.
- 有意义的工作，那些事情。
Exercise, those things make you happy, I think.
我想，锻炼身体会 让你快乐。
Make me happy for sure.
一定让我开心。
- You wrote a blog post,
- 你写了一篇博客文章，
"Why I'm unreachable and maybe you should be too."
“为什么我无法联系到， 也许你也应该如此。”
What's your strategy on communicating with people?
你与人沟通的 策略是什么？
- Yeah, so when I wrote that, I was getting so many DMs
- 是的，所以当我写这篇文章 时，我收到了很多私信
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
as you probably have, you have a million times more,
正如你可能拥有的那样，你 拥有的数量多了一百万倍，
and people were getting angry
人们开始生气
that I wasn't responding and I was like,
我没有回应，我当时想，
"Okay, I'll just close down these DMs completely.
“好的，我将彻底 关闭这些 DM。
And people got angry that I closed my DMs down,
人们因为我关闭私信 而生气，
that I'm not like man of the people.
我不像人民的人。
- It's like you changed man. - Yeah, you've changed.
- 就像你变了个人一样。 - 是的，你变了。
You got, you know, like this.
你知道，就像这样。
And I'm like, I'll explain why.
我想，我会解释原因。
I just don't have the time in a day
我只是一天没有时间
to answer every question.
回答每一个问题。
And also people send you like crazy shit, man.
而且人们还给你发来疯狂 的狗屎，伙计。
Stalkers and like,
跟踪狂之类的，
people write their whole life story for you
人们为你写下 他们一生的故事
and then ask you advice.
然后向你寻求建议。
Man, I have no idea.
伙计，我不知道。
I'm not a therapist.
我不是治疗师。
I don't know, I don't know this stuff.
我不知道，我不知道这些东西。
- But also beautiful stuff.
- 但也有美丽的东西。
- Absolutely, sure. - Life story.
- 绝对，当然。 - 人生 故事。
I've posted a coffee forum,
我发了一个咖啡论坛，
if you wanted to have a coffee with me.
如果你想和我喝杯咖啡。
- Nice. - And I've gotten
- 好的。 - 我已经得到了
an extremely large number of submissions
大量的提交
and when I look at them,
当我看着他们时，
there's just like beautiful people in there.
那里有很多 美丽的人。
- Yeah, stories. - Beautiful human beings.
- 是的，故事 。 - 美丽的人类。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- There's really powerful stories
- 这里有非常震撼人心的故事
and breaks my heart that I won't get
伤了我的心，但我却得不到
to meet those people. - Yeah.
去见见那些人。 - 是 的。
- And so this part of it is just like,
- 所以这部分就像，
there's only so much bandwidth to truly see other humans
只有这么多带宽才能 真正看到其他人
and help them or understand them
并帮助他们或理解他们
or hear them or yeah, see them.
或者听到他们的声音，或者是的，看到他们。
- Yeah, I have this problem that I try...
- 是的，我有这个问题，我尝试......
I wanna try help people
我想尝试帮助人们
and also like, oh- - Yeah.
而且还喜欢，哦- - 是 的。
- Let's make startups and whatever.
- 让我们创业什么的。
And I've learned over the years that generally for me,
多年来我了解到， 通常对我来说，
and it sounds maybe bad, right?
听起来可能很糟糕，对吧？
But I helped my friend Andre, for example,
但我帮助了我的朋友安德烈，例如，
he came up to me in a cowork space.
他在一个共享办公空间里向我走来。
That's how I met him.
我就是这样认识他的。
And he said, "I wanna learn to code.
他说：“我想学习编码。
I wanna do startups, how do I do it?"
我想创业，该怎么做？”
I said, "Okay, let's go install Nginx.
我说：“好吧，我们去安装 Nginx 吧。
Let's start coding."
让我们开始编码吧。”
And he has this self-energy that he actually...
他有这种自我能量， 他实际上......
He doesn't need to be pushed,
他不需要别人催促
he just goes and he just goes and he ask questions
他就走了，他就 走了，他问问题
and he doesn't ask too many questions.
他不会问太多问题。
He just goes, goes and learns it.
他只是不断地去学习。
And now he has a company and makes a lot of money,
现在他有了自己的公司 ，赚了很多钱，
has his own startups.
有自己的初创公司。
And the people that I had to kind of like,
还有那些我不得不喜欢的人，
that ask me for help, but then I gave help
向我寻求帮助，但后来我提供了帮助
and then they started debating it.
然后他们开始争论。
- Yeah. - Do you have that?
- 是的。 - 你有那个吗？
People ask you advice and they go against you say,
人们向你征求建议，但 他们却反对你说，
"No, you're wrong, because."
“不，你错了，因为。”
I'm like, "Okay, bro, I don't wanna debate.
我说：“好吧，兄弟 ，我不想争论。
You asked me for advice," right?
你向我寻求建议，”对吧？
And the people need to push generally,
人们需要普遍推动，
it doesn't happen.
它不会发生。
- Yeah. - You need to have
- 是的 。 - 你需要有
this energy for yourself.
为自己提供这种能量。
- Well, they're searching.
- 嗯，他们正在寻找。
They're searching, they're trying to figure it out.
他们正在寻找，他们正在 试图找出答案。
But oftentimes their search,
但往往他们的搜索，
if they successfully find what they're looking for,
如果他们成功地找到 了他们想要的东西
it'll be within.
它会在里面。
It sounds very like spiritual boost.
听起来很像精神上的提升。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- But it's really like figuring that shit out on your own.
- 但这真的就像你自己解决 这个问题一样。
- Yeah. - But they're reaching,
- 是的。 - 但他们正在达到，
they're trying to ask the world around them.
他们试图询问 周围的世界。
How do I live this life?
我该如何度过这一生？
How do I figure this out?
我该如何解决这个问题？
But ultimately, the answer is gonna be
但最终的答案是
from them working on themselves.
来自他们为自己努力。
And literally, it's the stupid thing,
从字面上看，这是愚蠢的事情，
but Googling and doing like searching-
但谷歌搜索并像搜索一样做-
- Yeah, surfing is procrastination.
- 是的，冲浪就是拖延。
I think sending messages to people.
我认为向人们发送信息。
- Yeah. - Is a lot of procrastination.
- 是的 。 - 有很多拖延症。
Lex, how do you become successful podcaster?
Lex，你如何成为 成功的播客？
- Yeah. - Bro, just start.
- 是的。 - 兄弟，开始吧。
Just go. - Yeah.
走吧。 - 是 的。
And just go.
就走吧。
- I would never ask you how to be successful podcaster?
- 我永远不会问你如何 成为成功的播客？
I would just start it,
我就开始吧，
and then I would copy your methods.
然后我会复制你的方法。
I would say, "Ah, this guy's a Black background.
我会说，“啊，这 家伙有黑人背景。
We probably need this as well."
我们可能也需要这个。”
- Yeah, try it. - Yeah.
- 是的，试试吧。 - 是的。
- Yeah, try.
- 是的，尝试一下。
And then you realize it's not about the Black background,
然后你意识到这与 黑色背景无关，
it's about something else.
这是关于其他事情的。
So you find your own voice,
于是你找到了自己的声音，
just keep trying stuff. - Exactly.
继续尝试。 - 确切 地。
- Meditation is a difficult thing.
- 冥想是一件困难的事情。
Like a lot of people copy and they don't move past it.
就像很多人抄袭一样， 但他们并没有超越它。
- Yeah. - You should understand
- 是的 。 - 你应该明白
their methods and then move past it.
他们的方法，然后超越它。
- Yeah. - Find yourself,
- 是的。 - 找到你自己，
find your own voice.
找到你自己的声音。
Find your own. - Yeah, you imitate
找到你自己的 。 - 是的，你模仿
and then you put your own spin to it,
然后你加入自己的想法，
and that's like creative process.
这就像创作过程。
That's literally the whole create...
这实际上就是整个创作...
Everybody always builds on the previous work.
每个人总是以以前 的工作为基础。
- Yeah. - You shouldn't get stuck.
- 是的。 - 你不应该被困住。
- [Lex] 24 hours in a day, eight hours of sleep.
- [Lex] 一天24小时 ，睡眠八小时。
You break it down into a math equation.
你把它分解成一个数学方程。
90 minutes of showering, clean up, coffee.
90 分钟的淋浴、清理、咖啡。
It just keeps whittling down to zero.
它只是不断减少到零。
- Man, it's not this specific,
- 伙计，这不是那么具体，
but I had to make like an average or something.
但我必须赚到平均 水平之类的东西。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
Firefighting (laughs) oh, I like that.
消防（笑）哦，我喜欢这个。
One hours of groceries and errands.
一小时的杂货和差事。
I've tried breaking down minute by minute,
我尝试过一分钟一分钟地崩溃
what I do in a day. - Yeah.
我一天所做的事情。 - 是的。
- Especially when my life was simpler.
- 尤其是当我的生活更简单的时候。
It's really refreshing to understand
理解起来确实让人耳目一新
where you waste a lot of time.
你浪费很多时间的地方。
- Yeah. - And what you enjoy doing.
- 是的。 - 以及你喜欢做什么。
How many minutes it takes to be happy? (laughs)
需要多少分钟才​​能 感到幸福？ （笑）
- Yeah. - Doing the thing
- 是的 。 - 做事
that makes you happy
这让你高兴
and how many minutes it takes to be productive?
需要多少分钟才​​能 发挥作用？
And you realize there's a lot of hours
你意识到还有很多时间
in the day- - Yeah.
那天—— - 是 的。
- If you spend it right.
- 如果你花钱得当的话。
- Yeah, a lot of it's wasted, yeah.
- 是的，很多都被浪费了，是的。
- For me, it's been the biggest battle
- 对我来说，这是最大的战斗
for the longest time is finding stretches of time
最长的时间是 寻找一段时间
where I can deeply focus into really, really deep work.
在那里我可以专注于非常 非常深入的工作。
Just like zoom in and completely focused,
就像放大并完全聚焦一样，
cutting away all the distractions.
排除所有干扰。
- Yeah, me too. - That's the battle.
- 是的，我也是 。 - 这就是战斗。
- Yeah. - It's unpleasant.
- 是的。 - 这很不愉快。
It's extremely unpleasant.
这是非常不愉快的。
- We need to fly to an island,
- 我们需要飞往一个岛屿，
make a man cave island where we can just,
建造一个人类洞穴岛，我们可以在那里，
everybody can just code for a week,
每个人都可以花一周的时间编码，
and just get shit done.
然后把事情做好。
Make new projects. - Yeah, yeah.
制定新项目。 - 是 啊是啊。
- But man, they called me psychopaths for this,
- 但是伙计，他们因此 称我为精神病患者，
'cause it says like one hours of sex, hugs, love.
因为它说就像一小时 的性爱、拥抱和爱。
Man, I had to write something,
伙计，我必须写点东西，
and they were like, "Oh, this guy's psychopath."
他们就像，“哦，这家伙 是个精神病患者。”
He plans his sex in specific hour-
他在特定的时间计划他的性行为-
- Like hugs. - Bro, I don't.
- 比如拥抱。 - 兄弟，我不。
- A counter for hugs. - Yeah, exactly.
- 拥抱计数器。 - 是的 ，完全正确。
Yeah, like click, click, click.
是的，就像点击，点击，点击。
- It's just a numerical representation of what life is.
- 这只是生命 的数字表示。
- Yeah. - It's like one of those,
- 是的 。 - 就像其中之一，
when you draw out how many weeks you have in a life.
当你画出你的一生有 多少个星期时。
- Oh, dude, this is like dark.
- 哦，伙计，这就像黑暗一样。
Yeah, man, don't wanna look at that too much.
是的，伙计， 不想看太多。
- Holy shit. - Yeah, man.
- 天哪。 - 是 的，伙计。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
How many times you see your parents?
你见过父母几次？
Jesus, man. - Yeah.
天哪，伙计。 - 是的。
- It's scary, man. - That's right.
- 太可怕了，伙计。 - 这是正确的。
It might be only a handful more times.
可能只会再有几次。
- [Pieter] Yeah, man.
- [彼得] 是的，伙计。
- You just look at the math of it.
- 你只要看看它的数学就可以了。
If you see him once a year or twice a year.
如果你一年见他一 次或一年两次。
- Yeah, FaceTime today. - Yeah.
- 是的，今天 FaceTime。 - 是 的。
- I mean, that's like dark when you see somebody
- 我的意思是，当你看到 某人时，就像黑暗一样
you like seeing, like a friend
你喜欢看，像朋友一样
that's on the outskirts of your friend group.
那是在你朋友圈 的郊区。
And then you realize like,
然后你意识到，
well, I haven't really seen him for like three years.
好吧，我已经三年 没见过他了。
So how many more times do we have-
那么我们还有多少次——
- Yeah. - That we see each other?
- 是的 。 - 我们见面了吗？
- Do you believe that like,
- 你相信吗，
friends just slowly disappear from your life?
朋友就慢慢从你 的生活中消失了吗？
Your friend group evolves, right?
你的朋友圈在发展，对吗？
- [Lex] So it does, it does.
- [Lex] 确实如此，确实如此。
- There's a problem with Facebook,
- Facebook 有问题，
you get all these old friends from school,
你从学校得到了所有这些老朋友，
when you were 10 years old. - Yeah.
当你10岁的时候。 - 是 的。
- Back when Facebook started.
- 回到 Facebook 刚成立的时候。
You would add friend them
你会加他们为好友
and then you're like, why are we in touch again?
然后你会想，为什么 我们又联系了？
Just keep the memories there.
只是把记忆留在那里。
It's different life now.
现在的生活不一样了。
- Yeah, that might be a guy thing or I don't know.
- 是的，这可能是男人 的事，或者我不知道。
There's certain friends I have that like,
我有一些这样的朋友，
we don't interact often, but we're still friends.
我们不经常互动，但 我们仍然是朋友。
- Yeah. - Every time I see him
- 是的 。 - 每次我看到他
I think it's because we have a foundation
我想这是因为我们有基础
of many shared experiences.
许多共同的经历。
- Yeah. - And many memories.
- 是的。 - 还有很多回忆。
I guess it's like nothing has changed.
我想就好像一切都没有改变一样。
Almost like, we've been talking every day,
几乎就像我们每天都在说话
even if we haven't talked for a year.
即使我们已经一年没有说话了。
- Yeah, yeah, that's deep.
=> - 是的，是的，这很深。
- Yeah. - Issues.
- 是的。 - 问题。
- So I don't have to be interacting with them
- 所以我不必 与他们互动
for them to be in a friend group.
让他们加入朋友小组。
And then there's some people I interact with a lot.
还有一些我经常 互动的人。
So it depends, but there's just this network
所以这要看情况 ，但只有这个网络
of good human beings that I can.
我能做的好人。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- Yeah, they have like a real love for them.
- 是的，他们对他们 有真正的爱。
And I can always count on them,
我总是可以信赖他们，
if any of them called me in the middle of the night,
如果他们中有人 半夜打电话给我
I'll get rid of a body, I'm there.
我会摆脱身体，我就在那里。
I like how that's a different definition of friendship,
我喜欢这是对友谊 的不同定义
but it's true, it's true. - True friend.
但这是真的，这是真的。 - 真正的朋友。
- You've become more and more famous recently.
- 你最近变得越来越 有名了。
How's that affect you?
这对你有什么影响？
- It's not recently because it's this gradual thing, right?
- 不是最近，因为这是 渐进的事情，对吧？
It keeps going,
一直持续下去，
and I also don't know why it's keeps going.
我也不知道为什么 它会继续下去。
- Does that put pressure on you to,
- 这会给你带来压力吗
'cause you're pretty open on Twitter
因为你在推特上很开放
and you're just like basically building shit in the open.
而你基本上就像是在公开 地建造垃圾。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- And just not really caring if it's too technical,
- 只是不太关心它是否 太技术性，
if it's any of this just being out there,
如果只是存在其中的任何一个，
does it put pressure on you?
这会给你带来压力吗？
Is it become more popular
是不是越来越流行了
to be a little bit more collected and?
更加收集一点，然后？
- Man, I think the opposite, right?
- 伙计，我认为恰恰相反，对吗？
'Cause the people I follow are interesting,
因为我关注 的人都很有趣
'cause they say whatever they think
因为他们想说什么就说什么
and they ship or whatever.
他们运送或其他什么。
It's so boring that people
人们真是太无聊了
start tweeting only about one topic.
开始只发布关于一个主题的推文。
- Yeah. - I don't know anything
- 是的 。 -我什么都不知道
about their personal life.
关于他们的个人生活。
I wanna know about their personal life.
我想了解他们的私生活。
Like you do podcasts,
就像你做播客一样，
you ask about life stuff of personality.
你问的是关于个性的生活问题。
That's the most interesting part of business or sports.
这是商业或体育中 最有趣的部分。
What's the behind the sport, the athlete, right?
这项运动的背后是什么 ，运动员，对吗？
Behind the entrepreneur. - Yeah.
企业家的背后。 - 是 的。
- That's interesting stuff. - To be human.
- 这很有趣。 - 成为 人类。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
I shared a tweet went too far,
我分享的推文太过分了，
but we were cleaning the toilet
但我们正在打扫厕所
'cause the toilet was clogged.
因为厕所堵了
But it's just real stuff,
但这只是真实的东西，
'cause Jensen Huang, the Nvidia guy,
因为 Nvidia 的黄仁勋
he says, he started cleaning toilets.
他说，他开始打扫厕所。
- That was cool.
- 太酷了。
You tweeted something about the Denny's thing, I forget.
你在推特上发了一些关于 丹尼的事，我忘了。
- Yeah, it was recent.
- 是的，这是最近的。
Nvidia was started in a Denny's diner table.
Nvidia 是在丹尼的 餐桌上创立的。
- And you made it somehow profound.
- 你让它变得有些深刻。
- [Pieter] Yeah, this one, this one.
- [彼得] 是的，这个，这个。
- Nvidia, a $3 trillion company was started
- Nvidia，一家价值 3 万亿 美元的公司成立
in a Denny's, an American diner.
在一家美国餐厅 Denny's 里。
People need a third space to work on their laptops
人们需要第三个空间来 使用笔记本电脑工作
to build the next billion or trillion dollar company.
建立下一个十亿或万亿 美元的公司。
What's the first and second space?
第一个和第二个空间是什么？
- The home office. - And then the in between.
- 家庭办公室。 - 然后是中间的部分。
The island. - Yeah, I guess, yeah.
岛屿。 - 是 的，我想，是的。
- The island. - Yeah.
- 岛屿。 - 是 的。
You need a space to like congregate.
你需要一个喜欢聚集的空间。
Man, and I found history on this.
伙计，我找到了这方面的历史。
So 400 years ago in the coffee house of Europe.
400 年前在欧洲 的咖啡馆里。
The scientific revolution, the enlightenment happened
科学革命，启蒙 运动发生
because they would go to coffee houses,
因为他们会去咖啡馆，
they would sit there,
他们会坐在那里，
they would drink coffee and they would work.
他们会喝咖啡 并工作。
They would work.
他们会工作的。
They would write and they would do debates
他们会写作并进行辩论
and they would organize marine routes, right?
他们会组织海上 航线，对吗？
They would do all the stuff in Coffeehouse in Europe,
他们会在欧洲的咖啡馆 里做所有的事情，
in France, in Austria, in UK, in Holland.
在法国、奥地利、英国、荷兰。
So we were always going to cafes to work
所以我们总是去咖啡馆上班
and to have serendipitous conversations
并进行偶然的交谈
with other people and start business and stuff.
与其他人一起开始 做生意之类的。
And like you asked me to come on here
就像你邀请我来这里一样
and we flew to America,
我们飞往美国，
and the first thing I realized was that
我意识到的第一件事是
I've been to America before,
我以前去过美国，
but we were in this cafe and there's a lot of laptops.
但我们在这家咖啡馆里，那里 有很多笔记本电脑。
Everybody's working on something.
每个人都在做某事。
And I took this photo,
我拍了这张照片，
and then when you're in Europe,
然后当你在欧洲时
like large parts of Europe now,
就像现在欧洲大部分地区一样
you cannot use a laptop anymore.
你不能再使用笔记本电脑了。
It's like no laptop.
就像没有笔记本电脑一样。
Which I understand.
我明白了。
- But that is to you, a fundamental place to create shit.
- 但那对你来说是一 个创造垃圾的基本场所。
Isn't that natural, organic coworking space of a coffee?
这难道不是一个天然、有机 的咖啡联合办公空间吗？
- Well, for a lot of people.
- 嗯，对于很多人来说。
A lot of people have very small homes-
很多人的房子都很小——
- [Lex] Yeah.
- [莱克斯] 是的。
- And coworking spaces are kind of boring.
- 联合办公空间有点无聊。
They're private.
他们是私人的。
They're not serendipitous, kinda boring.
他们不是偶然的，有点无聊。
Cafes are amazing 'cause random people can come in
咖啡馆很棒，因为 随机的人可以进来
and ask you what are you working on, or you know.
并问你在做什么 ，或者你知道。
And not just laptops,
不仅仅是笔记本电脑，
people are also having conversations
人们也在交谈
like they did 400 years ago debates or whatever.
就像 400 年前的辩论或 其他什么事情一样。
Things are happening.
事情正在发生。
And man, I understand the aesthetics of it.
伙计，我理解 它的美学。
It's like, oh, startup bro, shipping is a bullshit startup.
就像，哦，初创公司兄弟， 航运是一个废话初创公司。
But there's something more there.
但还有更多的东西。
There's people actually making stuff,
确实有人在做东西
making new companies that the society benefits from.
打造让社会受益 的新公司。
We're benefiting from Nvidia.
我们受益于英伟达。
I think it's the US GDP for sure is benefiting from Nvidia,
我认为美国的 GDP 肯定 受益于 Nvidia，
European GDB could benefit if we build more companies.
如果我们建立更多公司， 欧洲 GDB 可能会受益。
And I feel in Europe there's this vibe
我觉得欧洲有这种氛围
and you have to connect things.
你必须将事物连接起来。
But not allowing laptops in cafes
但不允许在咖啡馆使用笔记本电脑
is kind of like part of the vibe, which is like,
有点像氛围的一 部分，就像，
yeah, we're not really here to work.
是的，我们真的不是来这里工作的。
We're here to like enjoy life.
我们来这里是为了享受生活。
I agree with this Anthony Bourdain,
我同意安东尼·波登的观点，
like this tweet was quote to Anthony Bourdain photo of him
就像这条推文引用了安东尼·波登 (Anthony Bourdain) 的照片一样
with cigarettes and a coffee in France.
在法国，香烟和咖啡。
And he said, "This is what the cafes are for."
他说：“这就是 咖啡馆的用途。”
I agree.
我同意。
- But there is some element of like entrepreneurship.
- 但有一些类似于企业家 精神的元素。
You have to allow people to dream big
你必须让人们有远大的梦想
and work their ass off towards that dream.
并为这个梦想而努力奋斗。
And then feel each other's energy as they interact with.
然后在互动时感受 彼此的能量。
- [Pieter] Yes.
- [彼得] 是的。
- That's one of the things I liked in Silicon Valley
- 这是我在硅谷喜欢 的事情之一
when I was working there,
当我在那里工作时
is the cafes. - Yeah.
是咖啡馆。 - 是 的。
- There's a bunch of dreamers.
- 有一群梦想家。
You can make fun of them for like,
你可以取笑他们，比如
everybody thinks they're gonna build-
每个人都认为他们会建造-
- Sure. - A trillion dollar company,
- 当然。 - 一家价值万亿美元的公司，
but like- - Yeah, and it's off.
但就像- - 是 的，它已经关闭了。
It's not everybody wins.
并不是每个人都赢了。
99% of people- - Yeah.
99% 的人- - 是 的。
- Will be bullshit.
- 会是废话。
- But they're working their ass off.
- 但他们正在拼命工作。
- Yeah, and they're doing something,
- 是的，他们正在做某事，
and you need to pass this StartupBros.
你需要通过这个StartupBros。
Oh, it's StartupBros level.
哦，这是StartupBros级别的。
No, it's not.
不，不是。
It's people making cool shit.
这是人们在制造很酷的狗屎。
- Yeah. - And this will benefit you
- 是的 。 - 这会让你受益匪浅
'cause this will create jobs
因为这会创造就业机会
for your country and your region.
适合您的国家和地区。
And I think in Europe that's a big problem.
我认为在欧洲这 是一个大问题。
We have a very anti-entrepreneurial mindset.
我们有一种 非常反创业的心态。
- Dream big and build shit. - Yeah.
- 梦想远大，成就辉煌。 - 是 的。
- I mean this is really inspiring.
- 我的意思是这真的很鼓舞人心。
This has been tweet of yours.
这是你的推文。
All the projects that you've tried
您尝试过的所有项目
and the ones that succeeded.
以及那些成功的人。
- Has very few. - Mute life.
- 数量很少。 - 静音 生活。
- [Pieter] It was for Twitter to share the mute list.
- [Pieter] Twitter 分享 静音列表。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- Your mute words. - Fire calculator.
- 你无声的话语。 - 火灾计算器。
No more Google, make a rank.
不再谷歌，做一个排名。
How much is my site project worth?
我的网站项目值多少钱？
Climate Finder, Ideas AI.
气候查找器、创意人工智能。
- AirlineList still runs, but it doesn't make money.
- AirlineList 仍在运行 ，但不赚钱。
AirlineList like compares the safety of airlines
AirlineList 类似比较航空 公司的安全性
because I was nervous to fly.
因为我对飞行感到紧张。
So I was like, let's collect all the data on crashes
所以我想，让我们收集有关 崩溃的所有数据
for all the airplanes.
对于所有飞机。
- Bali sea cable.
- 巴厘岛海缆。
Nice, that's awesome.
不错啊，太棒了
Make village, nomad gear, 3D,
制作村庄、游牧装备、3D、
and virtual reality dev,
和虚拟现实开发人员，
play in my inbox like you mentioned.
就像你提到的那样在我的收件箱中播放。
There's a lot of stuff.
有很多东西。
- Yeah, man. - I'm trying to find some
- 是的，伙计 。 - 我正在努力寻找一些
embarrassing tweets of yours.
你的推文令人尴尬。
- You can go to the highlight tab.
- 您可以转到突出显示选项卡。
It has all like the good shit kind.
它拥有一切就像好狗屎一样。
- There you go. - This was Dubai.
- 就这样吧。 - 这是迪拜。
- POV, building an AI startup.
- POV，建立人工智能初创公司。
Wow, you're a real influencer.
哇，你真是一个有影响力的人。
- (laughs) And if people copy this photo now
-（笑）如果人们现在 复制这张照片
and they change the screenshots.
他们更改了屏幕截图。
It becomes like a meme. (Lex laughs)
它变得像一个模因。 （ 莱克斯笑）
Of course, you know. - (laughs) This is good.
当然，你知道。 -（笑）这很好。
- That's how Dubai looks, it's insane.
- 这就是迪拜的样子，太疯狂了。
- That's beautiful.
- 那好美丽。
Architectural wise.
建筑明智。
It's crazy.
太疯狂了。
The story behind these cities.
这些城市背后的故事。
- Yeah, the story behind for sure.
- 是的，当然是背后的故事。
So this is about the European economy where like.
这是关于欧洲 经济的情况。
- European economy landscape is ran by dinosaurs,
- 欧洲经济格局由 恐龙主导，
and today I studied this
今天我研究了这个
so I can produce you with my evidence.
这样我就可以向你出示我的证据。
80% of top EU companies were founded before 1950.
80% 的欧盟顶级公司 成立于 1950 年之前。
Only 36% of top US companies
只有 36% 的美国顶级公司
- Yeah, so the median founding of companies in US
- 是的，美国公司 成立的中位数
is something like 1960,
大约是1960年，
and the top companies, right?
和顶级公司，对吗？
And the median in Europe is like 1,900 or something.
欧洲的中位数约 为 1,900 左右。
- Yeah. - So it's here 1913 and 1963.
- 是的。 - 所以这是 1913 年和 1963 年。
So there's a 50th difference.
所以有 50 的差异。
- It's a good representation
- 这是一个很好的代表
of the very thing you were talking about,
你正在谈论的事情，
the difference in the cultures,
文化的差异，
entrepreneurial, spirit of the peoples.
企业家精神，人民精神。
- But Europe used to be entrepreneurial.
- 但欧洲曾经是创业型国家。
There was companies founded in 1800, 1850, 1900.
有的公司成立于 1800 年、1850 年、1900 年。
It flipped like around 1950 where America took the lead.
就像 1950 年左右那样， 美国处于领先地位。
And I guess my point is like,
我想我的观点是，
I hope that Europe gets back to,
我希望欧洲回到过去，
'cause I'm European,
因为我是欧洲人
I hope that Europe gets back to
我希望欧洲回到
being an entrepreneurial culture
成为一种创业文化
where they build big companies again.
他们再次建立大公司。
'Cause right now,
因为现在，
all the old dinosaur companies control the economies.
所有老牌恐龙公司都 控制着经济。
They're lobbying with the government.
他们正在向政府游说。
Europe is also,
欧洲也是，
they're infiltrated with the government
他们与政府渗透
where they create so much regulation,
他们创造了如此多的监管，
I think it's called regulatory capture, right?
我认为这就是所谓 的监管捕获，对吗？
Where it's very hard for a newcomer to join
新人很难加入 的地方
and to enter an industry
并进入一个行业
because there's too much regulation.
因为监管太多了。
So actually regulation is very good for big companies
所以实际上监管对大 公司来说非常有好处
'cause they can follow it.
因为他们可以遵循它。
I can't follow it, right?
我跟不上，对吧？
If I wanna start an AI startup in Europe now,
如果我现在想在欧洲创办 一家人工智能初创公司，
I cannot because there's an AI regulation
我不能，因为有人工智能法规
that makes it very complicated for me.
这对我来说非常复杂。
I probably need to get like notaries involved.
我可能需要像公证人 一样参与进来。
I need to get certificates licenses.
我需要获得证书许可证。
Whereas in America, I can just open my laptop.
而在美国，我只需打开 笔记本电脑即可。
I can start a AI startup right now, mostly.
基本上我现在就可以创办一家 人工智能初创公司。
- What do you think about e/acc,
- 您对 e/acc 有何看法？
effective accelerationist movement?
有效的加速主义运动？
- Man, you had Beff Jezos on,
- 伙计，你有贝夫·杰佐斯 (Beff Jezos) 上场，
I love Beff Jezos and he's amazing.
我喜欢 Beff Jezos，他太棒了。
And I think e/acc is very needed to
我认为 e/acc 是非常有必要的
similarly create a more positive outlook on the future.
同样，对未来产生 更积极的看法。
Because people have been very pessimistic
因为人们已经非常悲观
about society, about the future of society,
关于社会，关于 社会的未来，
climate change, all this stuff.
气候变化，所有这些东西。
E/acc is a positive outlook in the future.
E/acc对未来的展望是积极的。
It's like technology can make us,
就像科技可以让我们
we need to spend more energy.
我们需要花费更多的精力。
We should find ways to of course get like clean energy.
当然，我们应该找到 获得清洁能源的方法。
But we need to spend more energy to make cooler stuff
但我们需要花费更多的 精力来制造更酷的东西
and go into space,
并进入太空，
and build more technology that can improve society.
并开发更多可以改善 社会的技术。
And we shouldn't shy away from technology.
我们不应该回避技术。
Technology can be the answer for many things.
技术可以解决 很多问题。
- Yeah, build more.
- 是的，建造更多。
Don't spend so much time- - Yeah.
不要花那么多时间--是 的。
- On fearmongering and cautiousness
- 关于恐吓和谨慎
and all this kind of stuff.
以及所有这些东西。
Something is okay, something is good,
有事就好，有事好，
but most of the time should be spent on building
但大部分时间 应该花在构建上
and creating on- - Yeah.
并创造 - - 是 的。
- And doing so unapologetically.
- 并且毫无歉意地这样做。
It's a refreshing reminder of what made
这是一个令人耳目一新的提醒
United States great is all the builders,
美国伟大的是所有的建设者，
like you said, the entrepreneurs.
就像你说的，企业家。
- [Pieter] Yeah.
- [彼得] 是的。
- We can't forget that in all the sort of
- 我们不能忘记，在所有的事情中
discussions of how things could go wrong
讨论事情可能如何出错
with technology and all this kind of stuff.
与技术和所有 这些东西。
- Yeah, it goes Kaluga, China.
- 是的，去的是中国卡卢加。
China's now at the stage of like America, what?
中国现在已经到了像美国 这样的阶段了，什么？
Like 1900 or something.
比如1900年什么的。
They're building rapidly insane.
他们正在迅速疯狂地建设。
And obviously, China's massive problems.
显然，中国存在巨大的问题。
But that comes with the whole thing
但这是伴随着整个事情而来的
that comes with American is beginning
随美国而来的是开始
all that massive problems, right?
所有这些大问题，对吗？
But I think it's very dangerous for a country
但我认为这对一个国家 来说是非常危险的
or a region like Europe to,
或像欧洲这样的地区，
you get to this point where you're kind of complacent
你到了这个地步， 你有点自满了
and you're kind of comfortable
你感觉很舒服
and then you can either go this
然后你可以选择这个
or you can go this way, right?
或者你可以走这条路，对吗？
You're from here, you go like this,
你从这里来，你就这样走，
and then you can go this or this.
然后你可以去这个或这个。
I think you should go this way.
我想你应该走这条路。
- (laughs) And go off. - Yeah, go off.
-（笑）然后走开。 - 是 啊，走吧。
I think it's the problem is
我认为问题是
the mind culture.
心灵文化。
So eacc, I made EU Acc,
所以eacc，我做了EU Acc，
which is like the European kind of version.
这就像欧洲 版本。
(Lex laughs)
（莱克斯笑）
I made like hoodies and stuff.
我做了连帽衫之类的东西。
So a lot of people wear like,
所以很多人这样穿，
this make Europe great again hat.
这顶让欧洲再次伟大的帽子。
- Yeah.
- 是的。
- I made it red first, but it became too like Trump.
- 我先把它变成红色，但 它变得太像特朗普了。
So now it's more like European blue.
所以现在更像是欧洲蓝。
Make Europe great again.
让欧洲再次伟大。
- All right.
- 好的。
Okay, so you had incredible life.
好吧，你过着不可思议的生活。
Very successful, built a lot of cool stuff.
非常成功，构建了很多 很酷的东西。
So what advice would you give to young people
那么您会给年轻 人什么建议
about how to do the same?
关于如何做同样的事情？
- Man, I would listen to like nobody.
- 伙计，我会像没有人一样倾听。
Just do what you think is good and follow your heart, right?
做你认为好的事，跟随 你的心，对吗？
Everybody peer press you
每个人都向你施压
into doing stuff you don't wanna do.
去做你不想做的事情。
And they tell you,
他们告诉你，
parents or family or society tell you,
父母、家庭或社会告诉你，
but try your own thing,
但尝试自己的事情
'cause it might work out.
因为它可能会成功。
You can steer the ship.
你可以驾驶这艘船。
It probably doesn't work out immediately.
可能不会立即见效。
You probably go into very bad times
你可能会陷入非常糟糕的时期
like I did as well, relatively, right?
就像我一样，相对而言，对吧？
But in the end, if you're smart about it,
但最后，如果你足够聪明，
you can make things work
你可以让事情顺利进行
and you can create your own little life of things
你可以创造自己 的小生活
as you did, as I did.
正如你所做的，正如我所做的。
And I think that should be more promoted.
我认为应该进一步促进这一点。
Do your own thing.
做你自己的事。
There's space in economy
经济上还有空间
and in society for do your own thing.
并在社会上做自己的事情。
- Yeah. - It's like little villages,
- 是的 。 - 就像小村庄一样，
everybody would sell.
每个人都会卖。
I would sell bread, you would sell meat.
我卖面包，你卖肉。
Everybody can do their own little thing.
每个人都可以做自己的小事。
You don't need to be a normie as you say.
你不需要像你所说的那样成为一个普通人。
You can be what you really wanna be.
你可以成为你真正想成为的人。
- And go all out doing that thing.
- 全力以赴做那件事。
- Yeah, you gotta go all out
- 是的，你必须全力以赴
'cause if you half ass it, you cannot succeed.
因为如果你半途而废 ，你就不可能成功。
You need to go lean in to the outcast stuff.
你需要去了解那些 被遗弃的东西。
Lean in to the being different,
拥抱与众不同，
and just doing whatever it is that you wanna do, right?
做你想做的 事，对吧？
- You got a whole asset.
- 你拥有全部资产。
- Yeah, whole assets, yeah.
- 是的，全部资产，是的。
- This was an incredible conversation.
- 这是一次令人难以置信的对话。
It was an honor to finally meet you.
很荣幸终于见到你。
Finally.
最后。
- It was an honor to be here, Lex.
- 很荣幸来到这里，莱克斯。
- To talk to you and keep doing your thing.
- 与你交谈并继续 做你的事情。
Keep inspiring me and the world
不断激励我和世界
with all the cool stuff you're building.
以及您正在构建的所有很酷的东西。
- Thank you, man.
- 谢谢你，伙计。
- Thanks for listening
- 感谢您的聆听
to this conversation with Pieter Levels.
与 Pieter Levels 的对话。
To support this podcast,
为了支持这个播客，
please check out our sponsors in the description.
请在说明中查看 我们的赞助商。
And now let me leave you
现在让我离开你
with some words from Drew Houston,
德鲁·休斯顿的一些话，
Dropbox Co-founder, by the way, I love Dropbox.
Dropbox 联合创始人，顺便 说一句，我喜欢 Dropbox。
Anyway, Drew said, "Don't worry about failure.
不管怎样，德鲁说，“ 不要担心失败。
You only have to be right once."
你只需要做对一次。”
Thank you for listening,
感谢您的聆听，
and I hope to see you next time.
希望下次再见。